<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange briefly revisits the globalisation debate and suggests those who argue that as the state still exists, globalisation can be ignored are very mistaken. She then goes on to outline three dilemmas of globalisation: the economic, in that increasingly there is no political authority able to govern and control market relations; the environmental, while on one hand market actors are driven by the profit motive to use up environmental resources, countervailing power is largely absent; the political, there is a major democratic deficit in the governance structure of the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/states_and_markets_1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/states_and_markets_1994/</guid>
      <description>Although subtitled ‘An Introduction&amp;hellip;’ to IPE, this represents the only book length discussion of Strange’s theory of the four dimensions of power in IPE. It is at once an introduction to the subject and a forceful agenda setting exercise for further research. As such, though often appearing on undergraduate course reading lists, this is Strange’s defining book, one about which the rest of her work revolves. Strange discusses her ideas on theory building and methodology as well as the four structures of power in the international political economy: security, finance, production and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/states_and_markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/states_and_markets/</guid>
      <description>Although subtitled ‘An Introduction&amp;hellip;’ to IPE, this represents the only book length discussion of Strange’s theory of the four dimensions of power in IPE. It is at once an introduction to the subject and a forceful agenda setting exercise for further research. As such, though often appearing on undergraduate course reading lists, this is Strange’s defining book, one about which the rest of her work revolves. Strange discusses her ideas on theory building and methodology as well as the four structures of power in the international political economy: security, finance, production and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>Strange’s classic attack of the ‘declinist school’ in international relations. Once she has discussed the more ‘sociological’ reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE. This exposition closely parallels (though in a brief form) the arguments that appear in (1988e).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionism and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade ‘inefficiencies’ as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a ‘secondary structure’ which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures. The disruption in the international system and trade relations is in fact a symptom of disruptions within the primary structures, and especially the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_global_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_global_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration. Strange also stresses that while the four structures are not hierarchical, she believes it is disruptions in the financial structure that has caused most upheavals over the period examined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981)</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</guid>
      <description>Strange criticises Bergsten’s exaggeration of US decline in hegemonic power and absolution of the USA of bearing prime responsibility for the deteriorating economic situation. Indeed much of her work in the 1980s revolved round the dual need to recognise US responsibility for global economic crises, and the problem of such a responsibility being denied by the US (both policy makers and academics).
International Journal. Volume: 38 Issue: 2. Pages 355-356</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of International Surplus Capacity</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_politics_of_international_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_politics_of_international_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of 17 essays resulting from a conference held by the International Political Economy Group of the BISA, together with an editorial overview of theoretical approaches to IPE and a conclusion concerning the agreements and differences among the contributors. Writing with Tooze, Strange notes that it is not intended to dispense with the ‘insights’ of the realists, but it is necessary to widen their approach considerably. Any analysis should start by recognising the key historical bargains that were made within the economic structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_worlds_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_worlds_money/</guid>
      <description>After a survey of current modes of thought, both academic and practitioner, Strange concludes that while much analysis can usefully illuminate the mechanisms of the global monetary system, there is little attempt ally this to a consideration how the system links up with and effects the values of and outcomes in a globalised society. She wants work on the international monetary system to go beyond a mere mechanical explanation and to move towards a more political analysis (which would also include an assessment of the impact of technology on global finance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/what_is_economic_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/what_is_economic_power/</guid>
      <description>Here Strange commits to print an early version of the structure of power theory which she would develop over the next thirteen years. In this manifestation, there are three dimensions of power in the international political economy - security, ‘ideology’ and economic. There is more concern, though, with a location of four level or stages at which economic power is apparent - the world market structure; international co-operative relations; national/governmental control of markets; and the operational level of the economic transactions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
