<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of: J.L Allen Soviet Economic Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_jl_allen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_jl_allen/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of: J.L Allen Soviet Economic Power.&amp;rdquo; Economica 28, no. 109. (1961): 98-99.
Strange challenges the implicit assertion by the author that the interpretation of Soviet interest, or its choice of the means to an end, is static. She also doubts the ascription by the author of Finnish subservience to the Soviet Union as being solely one of economic dependence rather than strategic vulnerability. As one would expect Strange dismisses mono-causality, as she continues to do in all her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Soviet Trade Weapon</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Soviet Trade Weapon. London: Phoenix House, 1959.
This pamphlet appeared in Background Books series. Taking a rather optimistic (though at that time widespread view) of the Soviet Bloc’s economic situation vis-à-vis the West, Strange concludes that Soviet economic (and political) influence is reliant on economic ‘trouble-spots’ and the aversion by many developing states to the West’s recent history of colonialism. This leads her to suggest that money then spent on military aid might be better spent helping developing countries deal with agricultural surplus capacity in the global a market, a theme she would return to in &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rsquo; (1979).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
