<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Ernst-Otto Czempiel on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-ernst-otto-czempiel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Ernst-Otto Czempiel on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-ernst-otto-czempiel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Theory of Transnational Empire</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/towards_a_theory_of_transnational_empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/towards_a_theory_of_transnational_empire/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Towards a Theory of Transnational Empire.&amp;rdquo; In Global Changes and Theoretical Challenges: Approaches to World Politics for the 1990s, Ernst-Otto Czempiel, James N. Roseneau, editors. 161-176. Lexington: Lexington Books, 1989.
In this article Strange offers only her second explicit excursion into the epistemology of international theories, the first being a similar section in States and Markets (1988). She argues that theories must be more than description, taxonomy, importation of models from other disciplines or quantitative and that theories must explain some aspect of the international system not obvious to &amp;lsquo;commonsense&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependence in the International Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Interdependence in the International Monetary System.&amp;rdquo; In The Euro-American System: Economic and Political Relations Between North America and Western Europe, edited by Ernst-Otto Czempiel and Dankwar A. Rustow, 31-49. Frankfurt: Westview Press, 1976.&amp;quot;
Strange briefly outlines the character of the international monetary system, noting that while it has become at least partially transnational, posited solutions are still conceived at a national level. This leads her to argue that there needs to be a better attempt made to fit the response to crisis to the level at which it is manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
