<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Westview Press on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-westview-press/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Westview Press on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-westview-press/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An International Political Economy: International Political Economy: The Story so Far and the Way Ahead: </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ipe_the_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ipe_the_story/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: After noting again the essential role of economic historians in the study and understanding of the international political economy, Strange builds on an appreciation of the value of development economists, a plea for the re-inclusion of values into the study of IPE. This in the main is because they are already tacitly included, but there is little engagement with the economist’s prioritising of efficiency or the International Relations scholar’s of peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Euro-American System: Economic and Political Relations Between North America and Western Europe - Interdependence in the International Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Explicitly linking back to (1967a) Strange examines the contemporary political economy of international debt, but also seeks to put this situation into a longer historical context than merely the previous ten years. Suggesting that states can choose to grow by direction (the socialist route) or via debt, she argues that recently the combination of the welfare state and more complex credit system has allowed many states to reduce the debt risk they explicitly face and therefore expand through the extensive use of credit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
