<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Georg Schwarzenberger on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-georg-schwarzenberger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Georg Schwarzenberger on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:43 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-georg-schwarzenberger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cuba and After</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cuba_and_after/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cuba_and_after/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cuba and After.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1963, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 1-28. London: Stevens, 1963.
Resisting the prevailing &amp;lsquo;informed&amp;rsquo; analysis that the Cuban Missile Crisis was more an apparent danger than a real one, Strange sides with the &amp;lsquo;man in the street&amp;rsquo; to argue it was a very real moment of possible war and as such profoundly affected the US system of alliances. However, she also suggests that the immediate aftermath appears to have been a retreat into détente, rather than renewed confrontation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Trends in World Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/changing_trends_in_world_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/changing_trends_in_world_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Changing Trends in World Trade.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1962, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 139-158. London: Stevens, 1962.
Here Strange notes that since 1945 although manufacturing growth has accelerated expanding the trade between developed states there has been less growth in the demand for raw materials and agricultural goods. This distorted or uneven growth in trade had not only had an unsettling effect of world trade, but has also required developing states to take out loans to support their development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commonwealth and the Sterling Area</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_commonwealth_and_the_sterling_area/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_commonwealth_and_the_sterling_area/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Commonwealth and the Sterling Area.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1959, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 24-44. London: Stevens, 1959.
Strange discusses the problem of sterling&amp;rsquo;s link with the politics of the Commonwealth, the interactions between the sterling area and the rest of the world economy and policy responses to national pressures. Interestingly she considers the reciprocal arrangements for dollar holding and settlement in London by the Commonwealth nations as approaching a &amp;lsquo;socialist&amp;rsquo; ideal in attempting to provide funds, each to their need, from each as their ability warrants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strategic Trade Embargoes: Sense or Nonsense</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_strategic_trade_embargoes_sense_or_nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_strategic_trade_embargoes_sense_or_nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Strategic Trade Embargoes: Sense or Nonsense.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1958, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 55-73. London: Stevens, 1958.
Strange argues that the policy of strategic trade embargoes, a central plank of American cold war policy, should be reassessed in light of the launch of Sputnik and Britain&amp;rsquo;s decision to part from the US on an embargo on trade with China. If as she suggests that post-Suez resentment towards America prompted the British relaxation of the embargo on China than surely this policy really played no real strategic role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suez and After</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/suez_and_after/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/suez_and_after/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Suez and After.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1957, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 76-103. London: Stevens, 1957.
Noting that the underlying cause of the Suez crisis was distrust (or even fear of) Egyptian nationalism, Strange explores the idea of a Britain or France had a &amp;lsquo;vital interest&amp;rsquo; in the international (rather than national control) of the Suez Canal. While the military costs might have been open to some debate before the action, she argues that the diplomatic problems that Suez prompted were easily foreseeable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strains on NATO</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strains_on_nato/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strains_on_nato/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Strains on NATO.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1956, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 21-41. London: Stevens, 1956.
Taking as her starting point that NATO is under strain, Strange argues that policy between NATO members is barely co-ordinated, that its membership is too skewered towards colonial powers and that therefore to outsiders (especially African and Asian states) it is seen as &amp;lsquo;rich-mans-club&amp;rsquo;. However, while these problems might be alleviated by better diplomatic practice between the members, what is really required is representation for those states outside NATO in a forum with the dominant states (especially the US and UK).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/british_foreign_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/british_foreign_policy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;British Foreign Policy.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1955, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 35-53. London: Stevens, 1955.
Strange argues that a state whose power is waning is more liable to make fatal mistakes. British economic survival could only be made possible by conditions of expanding world trade, rising standards of living in export markets and a minimum of economic nationalism. Britain&amp;rsquo;s future thus largely depends on the US, as she is no longer as essential as a market and supplier of capital as she once was to the members of the Commonwealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economic Work of the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_economic_work_of_the_united_nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_economic_work_of_the_united_nations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Economic Work of the United Nations.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1956, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 118-140. London: Stevens, 1954.
Strange argues that governments have increased power over domestic economic forces, and feel that this power is necessary and desirable. The UN has generated and publicised debates surrounding economic development, and led indirectly to &amp;lsquo;point four programme&amp;rsquo; financial aid. But the US has in practice been given a paternal right to define and prioritise the economic goals of the UN, and set the agenda of acceptable economic policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Atlantic Idea</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_atlantic_idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_atlantic_idea/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Atlantic Idea.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1953, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 1-19. London: Stevens, 1953.
Strange discusses the fears of the British and French that the ideals of NATO would break down and be replaced by the domination of US arms and money. Strange suggests that in a bi-polar world, the US must be conciliatory to her allies because it is neither possible, nor does the US wish, to further its ends by force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Schumann Plan</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_schumann_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_schumann_plan/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Schumann Plan.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1951, George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, editors. 109-130. London: Stevens, 1951.
Again discussing the linkage between politics and economics, Strange points out that economic integration could not be achieved without political control from above, that it is not possible for economic integration to move forward without the political will for it to happen. However the clear aim of the Schumann Plan was to redress the balance of economic power in Western Europe in favour of France and at the expense of Germany, rather than necessarily provide for increased integration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
