<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal Article on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/categories/journal-article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal Article on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/categories/journal-article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Susan Strange saw the financial crisis coming, Your Majesty&#39;: The Case for the LSE&#39;s Great Global Political Economist</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/susan_strange_saw_the_financial_crisis_coming_your_majesty_the_case_for_the_lses_great_global_political_economist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/susan_strange_saw_the_financial_crisis_coming_your_majesty_the_case_for_the_lses_great_global_political_economist/</guid>
      <description>Dyer, Nat. &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Susan Strange saw the financial crisis coming, Your Majesty&amp;rsquo;: The Case for the LSE’s Great Global Political Economist.&amp;rdquo; Real-World Economic Review 98 (2021): 92-111.
This paper makes three arguments. First, that Susan Strange (1923-1998), who founded the field of international political economy in the UK, is one of the principal thinkers who foresaw multiple aspects of the global financial crisis of 2008 and its aftermath. She deserves credit for her prescience but has been overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Thinkers and the Canon of International Thought: Recovery, Rejection, and Reconstitution</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/women_thinkers_and_the_canon_of_international_thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/women_thinkers_and_the_canon_of_international_thought/</guid>
      <description>Hutchings, Kimberly, Patricia Owens. &amp;ldquo;Women Thinkers and the Canon of International Thought: Recovery, Rejection, and Reconstitution.&amp;rdquo; American Political Science Review 115, no. 2 (2021): 347–59.
Canons of intellectual &amp;lsquo;greats&amp;rsquo; anchor the history and scope of academic disciplines. Within international relations (IR), such a canon emerged in the mid-twentieth century and is almost entirely male. Why are women thinkers absent from IR’s canon? We show that it is not due to a lack of international thought, or that this thought fell outside established IR theories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Structural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</guid>
      <description>Babones, Salvatore, John H.S. Aberg. &amp;lsquo;Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Structural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.&amp;rsquo; International Theory 11, no. 3 (2019): 293-317.
There is a widespread feeling that globalization represents a major system change that has or should have brought world society to the forefront of international relations theory. Nonetheless, world society remains an amorphous and undertheorized concept, and its potential role in shaping the structure of the international society of states has scarcely been raised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power and Counter-Power: Knowledge Structure and the Limits of Control.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/power_and_counter-power_knowledge_structure_and_the_limits_of_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/power_and_counter-power_knowledge_structure_and_the_limits_of_control/</guid>
      <description>David, Matthew, Cynthia Meersohn Schmidt &amp;ldquo;Power and Counter-Power: Knowledge Structure and the Limits of Control.&amp;rdquo; Sociological Research Online 24, no. 1 (2019): 21-37.
In this article, we explore Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s multidimensional and non-reductive international political economy (IPE) approach to structural power. Strange&amp;rsquo;s key weakness is the failure to account for her knowledge structure&amp;rsquo;s regulative form relative to her security, production and financial structures. We seek to develop Strange&amp;rsquo;s account through the addition of Manuel Castells&#39; account of digital network structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural-Power and International Regimes.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/strucutural-power_and_international_regimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/strucutural-power_and_international_regimes/</guid>
      <description>Gwynn, Maria A. &amp;ldquo;Structural-Power and International Regimes&amp;rdquo;. Journal of Political Power 12, no. 2 (2019): 200-223.
This paper revisits the international relations approach to structural power. In particular, it stresses the influence of international regimes, institutions and international law, on current understandings of structural power. The new approach broadens conceptions that see structural power solely as constraints; structures not only reflect the capabilities of actors that created them, but also generate new capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Disaster: Power, Structural Violence, Insurance-Linked Securities, and the International Political Economy of the Disaster Politics Nexus.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/developing_disaster_power_structural_violence_insurance-linked_securities_and_the_international_political_economy_of_the_disaster_politics_nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/developing_disaster_power_structural_violence_insurance-linked_securities_and_the_international_political_economy_of_the_disaster_politics_nexus/</guid>
      <description>Pasch, Korey. &amp;ldquo;Developing Disaster: Power, Structural Violence, Insurance-Linked Securities, and the International Political Economy of the Disaster Politics Nexus.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Natural Resources 8, nos. 1 &amp;amp; 2 (2018): 131-153.
This article presents an alternative framing of disasters as a form of structural violence resulting from the unequal distribution of structural power between various groups, organizations, institutions, and states in the contemporary global political economy. The article utilizes a theoretical framework that combines Johan Galtung’s typology of violence and Susan Strange’s conceptualization of structural power to open up new space for analysis in the disaster politics nexus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 176-203.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power potentially is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This article offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Michael Jablonski. &amp;ldquo;Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?.&amp;rdquo; The Information Society 33, no. 3 (2017): 103-118.
U.S. advocacy for increased international intellectual property protection and a free and open Internet has been criticized as being inconsistent at best and hypocritical at worst. Placing U.S. copyright and Internet policy in a historical context and using Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s concepts of structural power and knowledge structures, we argue that copyright and Internet policies cannot be analyzed in isolation, but are intimately and inextricably linked forms of knowledge regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the &#39;Knowledge Structure&#39;: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the ‘Knowledge Structure’: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 164-175.
Somewhat paradoxically, the implications of knowledge governance&amp;rsquo;s changing role for the exercise of power in the Information Age remains underappreciated outside those scholars and policymakers directly engaged with these specific areas. This special issue brings together political scientists and communication scholars to consider the issue of knowledge governance through the theoretical framework of Susan Strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of Monopoly Rights as Free Trade: The TPP and Intellectual Property and Why It Still Matters</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_curious_case_of_monopoly_rights_as_free_trade_the_tpp_and_intellectual_property_and_why_it_still_matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_curious_case_of_monopoly_rights_as_free_trade_the_tpp_and_intellectual_property_and_why_it_still_matters/</guid>
      <description>Halbert, Debora J. &amp;ldquo;The Curious Case of Monopoly Rights as Free Trade: The TPP and Intellectual Property and Why It Still Matters.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 204-227.
Using the framework of a knowledge structure as conceptualized by Susan Strange, this article addresses the loss of flexibilities in international intellectual property (IP) regimes and the corresponding global criminalization of IP as serious topics of concern. The knowledge structure of IP frames a very specific type of global political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
