<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal Article on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/journal-article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal Article on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/journal-article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>In The persistent myth of lost hegemony International Organization 41,no.4(Autumn),551-574.197.
Strange’s classic attack of the ‘declinist school’ in international relations. Once she has discussed the more ‘sociological’ reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE. This exposition closely parallels (though in a brief form) the arguments that appear in States and Markets (1988).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionsim and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>In Protectionism and World Politics International Organization39, no.2(Spring).233-259.1985.
In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade ‘inefficiencies’ as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a ‘secondary structure’ which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures. The disruption in the international system and trade relations is in fact a symptom of disruptions within the primary structures, and especially the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade,&amp;rdquo; Austrailian Outlook 38, no. 2 (1984): 106-110.
Strange identifies three ‘shaky assumptions’ underlying the call to revive the GATT negotiations, that protectionism was the main cause of the 1930s depression, that the GATT was a necessary condition of post-war recovery, and free trade was ever a widely followed ‘norm’. However, though the alternatives are presented as a hegemonic system run by the US or a multilateral system managed through the GATT, Strange argues that the reality is a cob-web of bi-lateral agreements which accords with many people’s desire to have their own state manage their affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 39, no. 2 (1984): 267-283.
After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981),&amp;rdquo; International Journal 38, no. 2 (1983): 355-356.
Strange criticises Bergsten’s exaggeration of US decline in hegemonic power and absolution of the USA of bearing prime responsibility for the deteriorating economic situation. Indeed much of her work in the 1980s revolved round the dual need to recognise US responsibility for global economic crises, and the problem of such a responsibility being denied by the US (both policy makers and academics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis,&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36 no. 2, (1982): 337-354.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back - But Mostly Forward</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Looking Back - But Mostly Forward,&amp;rdquo; Millennium Journal of International Relations 11, no. 1 (1982):38-49.
In this survey article, Strange looks back across the first ten years of Millennium to examine the development of International Relations, although as she makes plain she prefers the term International Studies. Having seen the field expand from a focus on the foreign polices of various states, she maps the increasing interest in the international system itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactions to Brandt. Popular Acclaim and Academic Attack</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/reactions_to_brandt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/reactions_to_brandt/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Reactions to Brandt. Popular Acclaim and Academic Attack,&amp;rdquo; International Studies Quarterly 25, no. 2 (1981): 328-342.
Strange’s ‘review of the reviews’ draws two distinctions between reactions to the Brandt Report - American and European, popular and academic. Her discussion briefly outlines the ‘global Keynsianism’ aspects of the report before noting the criticisms that were levelled at it. After noting that in the academy many of the analyses of the problems and ‘pie in the sky’ solutions were nothing new, her final lament is that the report continues to accept the curative value of research and knowledge, set aside from the political process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money/</guid>
      <description>Strnage, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The World&amp;rsquo;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 36, no. 4 (1981): 691-712.
After a survey of current modes of thought, both academic and practitioner, Strange concludes that while much analysis can usefully illuminate the mechanisms of the global monetary system, there is little attempt ally this to a consideration how the system links up with and effects the values of and outcomes in a globalised society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_productive_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_productive_capacity/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1979): 303-335.
In this article, which is a clear precursor to (Strange and Tooze 1981), Strange discusses the management of surplus capacity in three sectors of the international economy - steel, textiles and shipbuilding, and the recourse to protectionism. She then goes on to discuss the problems this implies for mainstream theories of international economics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
