<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Taylor &amp; Francis on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-taylor-francis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Taylor &amp; Francis on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-taylor-francis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Transatlantic Divide: Why Are American And British IPE so Different?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_transatlantic_divide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_transatlantic_divide/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article:
Volume 14, Issue 2 Pages 197-219</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Global Political Economy: Authority and Markets: Susan Strange&#39;s Writings of International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/authority_and_markets_susan_stranges_writings_of_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/authority_and_markets_susan_stranges_writings_of_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter:
Pages 237-245</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ford and the Global Strategies of Multinationals: The North American Auto Indsutry</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ford_and_the_global_strategies_of_multinationals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ford_and_the_global_strategies_of_multinationals/</guid>
      <description>Book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Today-Finance, Firms, Mafias and the State: A Review of Susan Strange’s Work from a Developing Country Perspective</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/dependency_today-finance_firms_mafias/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/dependency_today-finance_firms_mafias/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article:
Volume 22, Issue 1 Pages 115-128</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange, Academic Interntaional Relations and the Study of International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_academic_interntaional_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_academic_interntaional_relations/</guid>
      <description>Journal: Overview of Strange&amp;rsquo;s Work
Volume 5, Issue 2 Pages: 280-289</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globaloney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globaloney/</guid>
      <description>In this review of the influential Paul Hirst and Grahame Thompson Globalisation in Question (Oxford: Polity Press, 1996) alongside two other books arguing a similar position, Strange makes a major intervention in the debate over the ‘myth’ of globalisation. Arguing that the authors (like others) miss the deterritorialisation of commercial power in the global system, Strange allows that there needs to be a corrective to the extreme globalisation thesis of complete transformation, but that a failure to examine what is really happening in the global political economy, while relying on aggregated and out-of-date statistics has led too many political economists to fail to recognise the very real changes in the balance of power between multinational corporations and states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_reply_to_chris_may/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_reply_to_chris_may/</guid>
      <description>In Strange’s reply to May’s article (Strange Fruit: Susan Strange’s theory of Structural Power in the International Political Economy Global Society 10, 2 (May 1996): 167 -189), she engages with two criticisms made of her theory of structural power. Firstly she suggests that the knowledge structure itself is not necessarily prior as is suggested it might be considered to be if her process of agenda setting power is regarded as central.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/wake_up_krasner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/wake_up_krasner/</guid>
      <description>Strange offers a criticism of Krasner’s realist position, drawing on her recent work and an understanding of structural power. She also offers brief critiques of political and economic liberalism as being essentially internally inconsistent, before suggesting that it is they rather than the ‘societal’ approaches that are having theoretical problems with recent developments in the international political economy. Realism and liberalism lack the heuristic power of her own (and others) structuralist approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
