<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politcal Economy on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/politcal-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politcal Economy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/politcal-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economic_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economic_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach.&amp;rdquo; In The Study of International Affairs: Essays in Honour of Kenneth Younger, edited by Roger Morgan, 63-84. London: RIIA/Oxford University Press, 1972.
Strange’s second major attack on the discipline of international economics as it then stood, see also &amp;lsquo;International economics and international relations: a case of mutual neglect&amp;rsquo; (1970). She derides the academic ‘apartheid’ that separates off political considerations from the economic and argues that what is required is a single international studies discipline that encompasses both the politics and economics of international relations (what would eventually become International Political Economy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations and International Economic Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_united_nations_and_international_economic_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_united_nations_and_international_economic_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The United Nations and International Economic Relations.&amp;rdquo; In The Evolving United Nations, edited by Kenneth J. Twitchet, 100-119. London: Europa Publications for the David Davies Memorial Institute of International Studies, 1971.
In The Evolving United Nations, edited by Kenneth J. Twitchet, 100-119. London: Europa Publications for the David Davies Memorial Institute of International Studies, 1971.&amp;quot; excerpt2: &amp;ldquo;Contrasting a Unitarian (‘one-world’) or egalitarian vision of the United Nations mission with a reformist position, Strange argues that despite some early hopes that the UN might remake the global economy, its subsequent history has revealed it to be largely powerless over much of international economic relations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
