<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal: PeaceFinder Series on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/journal-peacefinder-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal: PeaceFinder Series on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/journal-peacefinder-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Dissident View</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a_dissident_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a_dissident_view/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article: Strange comments on the UN deliberations concerning the future of Palestine and highlights the central factor that gave the Zionists an in-built advantage at the assembly. While the Arabs were negotiating in a state that was essentially antipathetic to their struggle, their opposite numbers were surrounded by sympathisers and supporters both within and outside the organisation. She also discusses some of the limitations and problems with such negotiations within the forum of the UN, and alludes to structural impediments to the ‘fair’ settlement of differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Four. Helping Develop Half a World </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/point_four/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/point_four/</guid>
      <description>Strange comments on the UN deliberations concerning the future of Palestine and highlights the central factor that gave the Zionists an in-built advantage at the assembly. While the Arabs were negotiating in a state that was essentially antipathetic to their struggle, their opposite numbers were surrounded by sympathisers and supporters both within and outside the organisation. She also discusses some of the limitations and problems with such negotiations within the forum of the UN, and alludes to structural impediments to the ‘fair’ settlement of differences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
