<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structural Power, Power on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/structural-power-power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structural Power, Power on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/structural-power-power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Structural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</guid>
      <description>Babones, Salvatore, John H.S. Aberg. &amp;lsquo;Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Structural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.&amp;rsquo; International Theory 11, no. 3 (2019): 293-317.
There is a widespread feeling that globalization represents a major system change that has or should have brought world society to the forefront of international relations theory. Nonetheless, world society remains an amorphous and undertheorized concept, and its potential role in shaping the structure of the international society of states has scarcely been raised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/information_technology_and_control_in_a_changing_world_understanding_power_structures_in_the_21st_century/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/information_technology_and_control_in_a_changing_world_understanding_power_structures_in_the_21st_century/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Kate Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Draws on Susan Strange’s conception of the knowledge structure to offer guiding theoretical insights for analyzing how the control of knowledge in its many forms is affecting global politics, society and economics.
Keywords: Theory; Knowledge; Structural Power, Power ; Security
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Infrastructure and the Persistent Myth of U.S. Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/internet_infrastructure_and_the_persistent_myth_of_us_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/internet_infrastructure_and_the_persistent_myth_of_us_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>Winseck Dwayne. &amp;ldquo;Internet Infrastructure and the Persistent Myth of U.S. Hegemony.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 93-120. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
According to many observers, economic globalisation and the liberalisation of telecoms/internet policy have remade the world in the image of the United States. The dominant role of Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google has also led to charges of U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural-Power and International Regimes.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strucutural-power_and_international_regimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strucutural-power_and_international_regimes/</guid>
      <description>Gwynn, Maria A. &amp;ldquo;Structural-Power and International Regimes&amp;rdquo;. Journal of Political Power 12, no. 2 (2019): 200-223.
This paper revisits the international relations approach to structural power. In particular, it stresses the influence of international regimes, institutions and international law, on current understandings of structural power. The new approach broadens conceptions that see structural power solely as constraints; structures not only reflect the capabilities of actors that created them, but also generate new capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Disaster: Power, Structural Violence, Insurance-Linked Securities, and the International Political Economy of the Disaster Politics Nexus.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/developing_disaster_power_structural_violence_insurance-linked_securities_and_the_international_political_economy_of_the_disaster_politics_nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/developing_disaster_power_structural_violence_insurance-linked_securities_and_the_international_political_economy_of_the_disaster_politics_nexus/</guid>
      <description>Pasch, Korey. &amp;ldquo;Developing Disaster: Power, Structural Violence, Insurance-Linked Securities, and the International Political Economy of the Disaster Politics Nexus.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Natural Resources 8 nos. 1&amp;amp;2 (2018): 131-153.
This article presents an alternative framing of disasters as a form of structural violence resulting from the unequal distribution of structural power between various groups, organizations, institutions, and states in the contemporary global political economy. The article utilizes a theoretical framework that combines Johan Galtung’s typology of violence and Susan Strange’s conceptualization of structural power to open up new space for analysis in the disaster politics nexus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 176-203.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power potentially is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This article offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Michael Jablonski. &amp;ldquo;Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?.&amp;rdquo; *The Information Society * 33, no. 3 (2017): 103-118.
U.S. advocacy for increased international intellectual property protection and a free and open Internet has been criticized as being inconsistent at best and hypocritical at worst. Placing U.S. copyright and Internet policy in a historical context and using Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s concepts of structural power and knowledge structures, we argue that copyright and Internet policies cannot be analyzed in isolation, but are intimately and inextricably linked forms of knowledge regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the &#39;Knowledge Structure&#39;: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the ‘Knowledge Structure’: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 164-175.
Somewhat paradoxically, the implications of knowledge governance&amp;rsquo;s changing role for the exercise of power in the Information Age remains underappreciated outside those scholars and policymakers directly engaged with these specific areas. This special issue brings together political scientists and communication scholars to consider the issue of knowledge governance through the theoretical framework of Susan Strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</guid>
      <description>Sell, Susan K. &amp;ldquo;Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. Randall Germain, editor. 39-50. London: Routledge 2016.
This chapter argues that Strange&amp;rsquo;s work is of enduring significance because it helps us forge a practical understanding of critical global problems. Global environmental problems, global financial crises, and global inequalities are three of the small set of global problems regularly pointed to by promoters of the new global public policy degree programs established over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Power in a Global Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/corporate_power_in_a_global_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/corporate_power_in_a_global_economy/</guid>
      <description>Palan, Ronen. &amp;ldquo;Corporate Power in a Global Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. Randall Germain, editor. 170-182. London: Routledge, 2016.
What is the nature of the powers of corporations in a globalized economy? Has there been a shift of power from states to corporations? From states to markets? And if yes, how and why? These are the sort of questions that were at heart of Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
