<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Chatham House on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-chatham-house/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Chatham House on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-chatham-house/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>States, Firms and Diplomacy </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/states_firms_and_diplomacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/states_firms_and_diplomacy/</guid>
      <description>This article in a brief summation of (Strange and Stopford 1991) outlining the central argument of the book concerning the diplomacy between firms and states, and discusses some areas for further research. This represents a useful entry to the book picking out the salient points from the longer work, without the empirical elements.
International Affairs. Volume: 68 Issue: 1. Pages 1-15</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Using the ‘Dollar Crisis’ as a way of examining the problems which beset academic approaches to international relations Strange suggests that: foreign policy analysis seems unable to recognise the centrality of economic problems for states; (Neo)functionalism is far too optimistic concerning the possibility of international integration; much ‘abstract theorising’, such as game theory, seems to have no connection with what is happening in the international system; and international economics has diverted attention away from international political problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dollar Crisis 1971</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</guid>
      <description>Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.
International Affairs. Volume: 48 Issue: 2. Pages 191-216</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>In the first article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane ‘transnational politics’ approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sterling and British Policy: A Political View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy_a_political_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy_a_political_view/</guid>
      <description>Strange sets the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar in the context of international politics. She stresses the need to integrate economic studies with those of international relations. Both state behaviour and the behaviour of international society, hitherto interpreted in terms of power and politics should now be extended to take in the monetary factor especially in the light of economic interdependence - the monetary factor is bound to become increasingly important in understanding state behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</guid>
      <description>Strange’s first call for the development of International Political Economy as a separate discipline. She identifies a major void between the academic study of international relations and the study of international economics. The failure to fill this void will result in a loss of relevance for the subjects and an inability to deal with the major problems that beset the international economy. This will also lead to the inability to analyse the two main tendencies in the international economic system; growing international co-operation and organisation, and increased domestic defensiveness over national welfare issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Money Matters</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_money_matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_money_matters/</guid>
      <description>Strange uses a survey of a number of recent textbooks (and other writing) on international economics to criticise the economics profession as a whole for taking too little account of politics. Most economists are satisfied with international growth and rising ‘efficiency’ she argues without ever asking questions regarding the evident inequalities in the intentional economy or the political dimensions of the uneven growth between countries. These criticisms were instrumental in her call in other writing around this time for the establishment of a discipline of International Political Economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</guid>
      <description>In this small pamphlet Strange analyses the twin roles of sterling in the international economy - that of reserve currency and of vehicle currency (in which transactions are carried out), in a precursor to her typology of currencies in (1971c). She argues that while the City has benefited from the expansion of the ‘Euro-currency’ markets, in its ‘middleman’ role, this has led to a number of problems for sterling both in the wider context of the international economy and, more specifically, the context of the emerging European Community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers. While encouraging industry in developing states, instead of commodity exports, this would reduce the ‘loading of the dice’ identified by G77.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debts, Defaulters, and Development</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</guid>
      <description>Strange suggests that problems of national debt default have not been solved, merely suppressed by the expansion of credit provision. Developing states dependence on ‘supplier credit’, and frequent rescheduling of other debts will lead to eventual wide-spread default unless action is taken. She suggests that: principles governing international loans should be established; these ‘rules’ should be applied through aid-agencies and other international bodies; technical assistance to finance ministries should be available from multilateral institutions (the World Bank, possibly) to ensure states understand their fiscal position and their options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
