<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Fall&#39; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;Fall&amp;rdquo; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy.&amp;rdquo; In The Fall of Great Powers: Peace, Stability and Legitimacy, edited by Geir Lundestad, 197-211. Oslo and Oxford: Scandinavian University Press and Oxford University Press, 1994.
Once again Strange argues at length that the notion of American decline in the global system is mistaken if examined through her structural perspective. She presents a brief history of the previous fifty years to explore how America&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;fall&amp;rsquo; can be proposed and why this misunderstands power in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending Benign Mercantilism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Defending Benign Mercantilism.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Peace Research 25, no. 3 (1988): 273-277.
In this review of Robert Gilpin&amp;rsquo;s Political Economy of International Relations, Strange again argues against &amp;lsquo;Hegemonic Stability Theory&amp;rsquo;, see &amp;lsquo;The persistent myth of lost hegemony&amp;rsquo; (1987), but has started to develop a theory of transnational empire to explain the structural power of the United States. Part of this argument is the increasing non-territoriality of structural power, which is developed in a number of works below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 39, no. 2 (1984): 267-283.
After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structures, Values and Risk in the Study of the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/structures_values_and_risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/structures_values_and_risk/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Structures, Values and Risk in the Study of the International Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Perspectives on Political Economy, edited by R.J. Barry Jones, 209-230. London: Francis Printer Journals, 1983.
In this article Strange argues for the centrality of questions surrounding the nature of risk and how it is mitigated, managed and transferred in the international economy. In addition she suggests five structures of power in IPE, noting that she is adding to the Marxist concept of a production structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis.&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1982): 479-496.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Economics: A Sectoral Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_economics_a_sectoral_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_economics_a_sectoral_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Politics of Economics: A Sectoral Analysis.&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues and the Atlantic Community, edited by Wolfram F. Hanrieder, 15-26. New York: Praeger, 1982.
Strange here proposes a structural approach that is implied by her argument that an analysis of the global political economy must be concerned with its ‘environment’. However, while suggesting three of her four later structures - here, security, monetary and production structures - she also includes a number of other structures - transport, trade, communication - that would later become in her schema, secondary structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity.&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues of the Eighties, edited by Nake M. Kamrany and Richard H. Day, 226-246. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1979.
This chapter is a lightly edited version of &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rsquo; (1979).
Keywords: Production; Structural Power, Power; Theory; Trade
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Study of Transnational Relations.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 333-345.
Published alongside &amp;lsquo;Who Runs World Shipping?&amp;rsquo; (1976). In this article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane &amp;lsquo;transnational politics&amp;rsquo; approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
