<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 39, no. 2 (1984): 267-283.
After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structures, Values and Risk in the Study of the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/structures_values_and_risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/structures_values_and_risk/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Structures, Values and Risk in the Study of the International Political Economy,&amp;rdquo; In Perspectives on Political Economy, edited by R.J. Barry Jones, 209-230. London: Francis Printer Journals, 1983.
In this article Strange argues for the centrality of questions surrounding the nature of risk and how it is mitigated, managed and transferred in the international economy. In addition she suggests five structures of power in IPE, noting that she is adding to the Marxist concept of a production structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis,&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36 no. 2, (1982): 337-354.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe and the United States: The Transatlantic Aspects of Inflation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_and_the_us_the_transatlantic_aspects_of_inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_and_the_us_the_transatlantic_aspects_of_inflation/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Europe and the United States: The Transatlantic Aspects of Inflation,&amp;rdquo; In The Politics of Inflation: Acomparative Analysis, edited by Richard Medley, 65-76. New York: Pergamon Press, 1982.
This short article discusses the international financial sector and the interaction between American monetary policy and European exchange rates, monetary policy and the then new European Monetary System. While containing little explication of structural power, being more of an historical overview, the article is of interest for Strange’s concluding discussion of the reasons for American domination of the international financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still and Extraordinary Power: America&#39;s Role in the Global Monetary System (Paper 3) (with discussants section)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_and_extraordinary_power_americas_role_in_the_global_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_and_extraordinary_power_americas_role_in_the_global_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Still and Extraordinary Power: America&amp;rsquo;s Role in the Global Monetary System (Paper 3) (with discussants section),&amp;rdquo; In The Political Economy of Interdependence and Domestic Monetary Relations, edited by Raymond E. Lomra and Willard E. Witte, 73-93. Ames: Iowa State University Press, 1982.
excerpt2: &amp;ldquo;A paper delivered to a conference on international monetary relations. As well as considering power in the financial markets, Strange also makes a provisional (in light of her later work) analysis of structural power in the international political economy more generally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Economics: A Sectoral Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_economics_a_sectoral_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_economics_a_sectoral_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Politics of Economics: A Sectoral Analysis,&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues and the Atlantic Community, edited by Wolfram F. Hanrieder, 15-26. New York: Praeger, 1982.
Strange here proposes a structural approach that is implied by her argument that an analysis of the global political economy must be concerned with its ‘environment’. However, while suggesting three of her four later structures - here, security, monetary and production structures - she also includes a number of other structures - transport, trade, communication - that would later become in her schema, secondary structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Politics of Surplus Capacity: Competition for Market Shares in the World</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_international_politics_of_surplus_capacity_competition_for_market_shares_in_the_world_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_international_politics_of_surplus_capacity_competition_for_market_shares_in_the_world_/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, and Roger Tooze, eds., The International Politics of Surplus Capacity: Competition for Market Shares in the World. London: Allen and Unwin, 1981.
This is a collection of 17 essays resulting from a conference held by the International Political Economy Group of the BISA, together with an editorial overview of theoretical approaches to IPE and a conclusion concerning the agreements and differences among the contributors. Writing with Tooze, Strange notes that it is not intended to dispense with the ‘insights’ of the realists, but it is necessary to widen their approach considerably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity,&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues of the Eighties edited by Nake M. Kamrany and Richard H. Day, 226-246. Baltimore, Johns Hopkins University Press, 1979.
This chapter is a lightly edited version of &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity: Or how does theory stand up to protectionism 1970s style?&amp;rsquo; (1979).
Keywords: Production, Structural Power, Power, Theory, Trade
Text Access (External Link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Study of Transnational Relations.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 333-345.
Using the ‘Dollar Crisis’ as a way of examining the problems which beset academic approaches to international relations Strange suggests that: foreign policy analysis seems unable to recognise the centrality of economic problems for states; (Neo)functionalism is far too optimistic concerning the possibility of international integration; much ‘abstract theorising’, such as game theory, seems to have no connection with what is happening in the international system; and international economics has diverted attention away from international political problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, and Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
