<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to the Susan Strange Web Archive on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to the Susan Strange Web Archive on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2022-2023 Jordon Dumenil</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About The Archive</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/about-the-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/about-the-archive/</guid>
      <description>In February 2020, just before the pandemic closed everything down, Nat Dyer and I were having lunch at the British Museum cafeteria in London. Dyer, a researcher and author, had met online and had bonded over our shared admiration of Susan Strange. Naturally, our conversation turned to Strange, as we marvelled over her life and accomplishments: a White House correspondent at 23 years of age, time with The Economist and The Observer, co-founder of the academic discipline of International Political Economy (despite not having a PhD!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Archive</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description>This page contains the searchable bibliography of Susan Strange’s academic work, academic and journalistic work that draws on Susan Strange’s theories and ideas. This bibliography remains a work in progress: if you have completed work, or know of works, that we should feature here, please let us know.
For copyright reasons, this site does not host any of Strange’s work, or of Strange-influenced work. Where available, we have provided links to external sites that host these works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Strange</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/about-strange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/about-strange/</guid>
      <description>Sketch credit: Erin Kavanagh @geomythkavanagh
Susan Strange (1923-1998) was one of the most innovative and interesting thinkers about global politics and economics in the late twentieth-century. After studying economics at the LSE during World War II, she began her working life as a journalist in the US and UK, before going on to co-found a new academic field, International Political Economy (IPE), despite never having received a doctorate. Her writing in the 1970s, 80s, and 90s about systemic risks in financial markets, America&amp;rsquo;s global influence and more was ahead of its time and engaged deeply with power and history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference and Podcast</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/conference-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/conference-podcast/</guid>
      <description>This is a page for conference and podcast details!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/contact-us/</guid>
      <description>This site is maintained by Blayne Haggart, Associate Professor, Political Science, Brock University.
One of the goals of this website is to identify a community of scholars who draw upon the work and ideas of Susan Strange. If you would like to be informed of updates to this website such as listings of new Strange-influenced work, including a potential Susan Strange listserv (forthcoming), [please contact us](STRANGE MAILING LIST EMAIL TBD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay 1</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/essay1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/essay1/</guid>
      <description>This is a page for an essay!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essays</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/essays/</guid>
      <description>This where links to the essays go
This page is updated from content&amp;gt;en&amp;gt;essays&amp;gt;index.html</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
