<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authority on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/authority/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authority on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/authority/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 176-203.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power potentially is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This article offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the &#39;Knowledge Structure&#39;: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the ‘Knowledge Structure’: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 164-175.
Somewhat paradoxically, the implications of knowledge governance&amp;rsquo;s changing role for the exercise of power in the Information Age remains underappreciated outside those scholars and policymakers directly engaged with these specific areas. This special issue brings together political scientists and communication scholars to consider the issue of knowledge governance through the theoretical framework of Susan Strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ford and the Global Strategies of Multinationals: The North American Auto Industry</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ford_and_the_global_strategies_of_multinationals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ford_and_the_global_strategies_of_multinationals/</guid>
      <description>Studer-Noguez, Maria Isabel. Ford and the Global Strategies of Multinationals: The North American Auto Industry. London: Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, 2002.
Keywords: Corporations; States; Globalization; Authority; Markets
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Competitiveness and Enlargement: Is There Anyone in Charge?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_competitiveness_and_enlargement_is_there_anyone_in_charge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_competitiveness_and_enlargement_is_there_anyone_in_charge/</guid>
      <description>Pellegrin, Julie. &amp;ldquo;European Competitiveness and Enlargement: Is There Anyone in Charge?.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy. Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, editors. 297-316. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Economics; Authority; Markets; Political Economy; International Relations; Authority vs Markets
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Money and the Decline of State Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/global_money_and_the_decline_of_state_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/global_money_and_the_decline_of_state_power/</guid>
      <description>Underhill, Geoffrey R.D. &amp;ldquo;Global Money and the Decline of State Power.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy. Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, editors. 115-135. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Global governance; Globalization; Money and finance; Authority; Markets; States
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Beyond States and Markets to Civil Societies?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/going_beyond_states_and_markets_to_civil_societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/going_beyond_states_and_markets_to_civil_societies/</guid>
      <description>Shaw, Timothy M., Sandra J. MacLean. &amp;ldquo;Going Beyond States and Markets to Civil Societies?.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy. Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, editors. 391-406. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Theory; Authority; Markets; States; Civil Society
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money (CSGR Working Paper No. 18/98)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_theory_the_theory_in_mad_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_theory_the_theory_in_mad_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money (CSGR Working Paper No. 18/98). Coventry: University of Warwick/Centre for the Study of Globalisation and Regionalisation, 1998.
In this, her final piece of writing, Strange reprise arguments from &amp;lsquo;Rival States, Rival Firms&amp;rsquo; (with John M. Stopford, 1991) and The Retreat of the State (1996) to argue that the disciplines of International Relations and International Economics fail to understand contemporary globalisation. Where IR scholars have missed the structural shifts in the global system away from state-centric power with the emergence of new non-state authority, economists have missed the role of the state in promoting these changes, and misunderstand the working of global markets, discounting, or not even recognising the political relations between firms, what Strange refers to as the new diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Territory, State, Authority and Economy: A New Realist Ontology of Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/territory_state_authority_and_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/territory_state_authority_and_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Territory, State, Authority and Economy: A New Realist Ontology of Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; In The New Realism: Perspectives on Multilateralism and World Order, Robert W. Cox, editor. 3-19. Basingstoke: Macmillan Press/ United Nations University Press, 1997.
Strange argues that the global economy is in the midst of a transition; the close incidence of political authority, economic activity and geographical territory no longer holds. This has been caused by two main groups of factors: firstly changes derived from science and technology; and secondly structural changes within the global finance structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Erosion of the State</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;The Erosion of the State.&amp;rdquo; Current History 96, no. 613 (1997): 365-369.
Strange briefly revisits the globalisation debate and suggests those who argue that as the state still exists, globalisation can be ignored are very mistaken. She then goes on to outline three dilemmas of globalisation: the economic, in that increasingly there is no political authority able to govern and control market relations; the environmental, while on one hand market actors are driven by the profit motive to use up environmental resources, countervailing power is largely absent; the political, there is a major democratic deficit in the governance structure of the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;The Limits of Politics.&amp;rdquo; Government and Opposition 30, no. 3 (1995): 291-311.
Originally delivered as a lecture at the LSE this article finds Strange explicitly engaging with the notion of globalisation. For Strange globalisation is: the development of products for explicitly global and transnational markets; the decline of barriers and distinctions between national economies; the emergence of at least partial labour mobility in addition to the more recognised capital mobility; and the speeding up of transport and communications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
