<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National Debt on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/national-debt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in National Debt on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/national-debt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Default in the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Acting as a rapporteur for the SSRC Advisory Group on International Organisation (chaired by Goodwin), Strange maps out current and future research as well as examining its organisation and administration. Though published two year prior to Strange’s first call for the establishment of International Political Economy (1970a), this report on the discussion of research into international organisation and international relations reveals many themes (from the impact of structure and technology to the importance of international economics) she would develop in her own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debts, Defaulters, and Development</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</guid>
      <description>Strange suggests that problems of national debt default have not been solved, merely suppressed by the expansion of credit provision. Developing states dependence on ‘supplier credit’, and frequent rescheduling of other debts will lead to eventual wide-spread default unless action is taken. She suggests that: principles governing international loans should be established; these ‘rules’ should be applied through aid-agencies and other international bodies; technical assistance to finance ministries should be available from multilateral institutions (the World Bank, possibly) to ensure states understand their fiscal position and their options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
