<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Allen and Unwin on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-allen-and-unwin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Allen and Unwin on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-allen-and-unwin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paths to International Political Economy </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_ipe/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of nine essays looking at various sectoral aspects to the study of IPE, together with a brief preface by Strange. In her preface Strange again singles out development economists, applied economists and economic historians and praises their openness to insights and evidence from other disciplines and sub-disciplines. Implicitly there is an epistemological argument here, against theoretical closure, though as in the majority of her writings this remains implicit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of International Surplus Capacity</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_international_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_international_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of 17 essays resulting from a conference held by the International Political Economy Group of the BISA, together with an editorial overview of theoretical approaches to IPE and a conclusion concerning the agreements and differences among the contributors. Writing with Tooze, Strange notes that it is not intended to dispense with the ‘insights’ of the realists, but it is necessary to widen their approach considerably. Any analysis should start by recognising the key historical bargains that were made within the economic structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
