<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Cambridge University Press on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-cambridge-university-press/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Cambridge University Press on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-cambridge-university-press/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Strcutural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article:
Volume 11, Issue 3 Pages 293-317</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Currency Internationalisation: The Case of the RMB</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article
Volume 43, Issue 3 Pages 765-787</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Business and Government Relations in the 21st Century: Revisting Rival States: Beyond the Triangle?</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/revisting_rival_states_beyond_the_triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/revisting_rival_states_beyond_the_triangle/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter:
Pages 103-116</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system’s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure Sytem</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_westfailure_sytem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_westfailure_sytem/</guid>
      <description>Journal: In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system’s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Retreat of the State. State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>In what might effectively be regarded as the third part of a trilogy, together with (1988e) and (Strange and Stopford 1991), Strange examines states’ transition towards the sidelines of global political economic relations. Though in the past authority might have been state based, now she argues it is more often based on non-state abilities to bring about (or structure) outcomes. This has to some extent been obscured by the increasing intervention by states in the lives of their citizens, giving an impression of the retention of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Retreat of the State: State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state_diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state_diffusion/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: In what might effectively be regarded as the third part of a trilogy, together with (1988e) and (Strange and Stopford 1991), Strange examines states’ transition towards the sidelines of global political economic relations. Though in the past authority might have been state based, now she argues it is more often based on non-state abilities to bring about (or structure) outcomes. This has to some extent been obscured by the increasing intervention by states in the lives of their citizens, giving an impression of the retention of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>In this short review of P.J. Cain and A.G. Hopkins British Imperialism (2 vols) (London: Longman 1993), Strange again emphasises the structural characteristics of US power in the global system and suggest that Britain’s structural power was more long lasting than is sometimes presumed, with clear implications for the continuing power of the US in the global economy.
Review of International Studies. Volume: 20 Issue: 4. Pages 407-410</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</guid>
      <description>A self-avowedly part international relations - part international business management work which in keeping with Strange’s views discusses the interdependence between politics and economics without fore-grounding one at the expense of the other. The book builds on Strange’s theory of power and links it through three national studies (Brazil, Malaysia, Kenya) to a consideration of the effect of structural change in the international political economy on the role of TNCs in international economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_information_and_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_information_and_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange discusses the difference between American structural power and Japanese relational power in the financial structure. In addition she discusses the impact of communications technology changes on the operation of international financial markets, which represents an illuminating case study of how two structures interact with each other to bring about changes in the international political economy, in this case the financial and knowledge structures. In addition Strange notes that at least part of American structural power is derived from the privileged position of the ‘American-English’ language in the knowledge structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
