<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dwayne Winseck on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/contributors/dwayne-winseck/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dwayne Winseck on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/contributors/dwayne-winseck/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internet Infrastructure and the Persistent Myth of U.S. Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/internet_infrastructure_and_the_persistent_myth_of_us_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/internet_infrastructure_and_the_persistent_myth_of_us_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>Winseck Dwayne. &amp;ldquo;Internet Infrastructure and the Persistent Myth of U.S. Hegemony.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century, edited by Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, 93-120. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
According to many observers, economic globalisation and the liberalisation of telecoms/internet policy have remade the world in the image of the United States. The dominant role of Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google has also led to charges of U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geopolitical Economy of the Global Internet Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_geopolitical_economy_of_the_global_internet_infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_geopolitical_economy_of_the_global_internet_infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Winseck, Dwayne. &amp;ldquo;The Geopolitical Economy of the Global Internet Infrastructure.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 228-267.
According to many observers, economic globalization and the liberalization of telecoms/internet policy have remade the world in the image of the United States. The dominant roles of Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google have also led to charges of US internet imperialism. This article, however, argues that while these internet giants dominate some of the most popular internet services, the ownership and control of core elements of the internet infrastructure—submarine cables, internet exchange points, autonomous system numbers, datacenters, and so on—are tilting increasingly toward the EU and BRICS (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
