<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1970&#39;s on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/1970s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1970&#39;s on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/1970s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Default in the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Debt and Default in the International Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Debt and the Less Developed Countries, edited by Jonathan David Aronson, 1-26. Boulder: Westview Press, 1979.
Explicitly linking back to &amp;lsquo;Debts, Defaulters and Development&amp;rsquo; (1967) Strange examines the contemporary political economy of international debt, but also seeks to put this situation into a longer historical context than merely the previous ten years. Suggesting that states can choose to grow by direction (the socialist route) or via debt, she argues that recently the combination of the welfare state and more complex credit system has allowed many states to reduce the debt risk they explicitly face and therefore expand through the extensive use of credit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity_or_how_does_theory_stand_up_to_protectionism_1970s_style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity_or_how_does_theory_stand_up_to_protectionism_1970s_style/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1979): 303-335.
In this article, which is a clear precursor to The Politics of International Surplus Capacity (with Roger Tooze, 1981), Strange discusses the management of surplus capacity in three sectors of the international economy - steel, textiles and shipbuilding, and the recourse to protectionism. She then goes on to discuss the problems this implies for mainstream theories of international economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity.&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues of the Eighties, edited by Nake M. Kamrany and Richard H. Day, 226-246. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1979.
This chapter is a lightly edited version of &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rsquo; (1979).
Keywords: Production; Structural Power, Power; Theory; Trade
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependence in the International Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Interdependence in the International Monetary System.&amp;rdquo; In The Euro-American System: Economic and Political Relations Between North America and Western Europe, edited by Ernst-Otto Czempiel and Dankwar A. Rustow, 31-49. Frankfurt: Westview Press, 1976.&amp;quot;
Strange briefly outlines the character of the international monetary system, noting that while it has become at least partially transnational, posited solutions are still conceived at a national level. This leads her to argue that there needs to be a better attempt made to fit the response to crisis to the level at which it is manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Monetary Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Monetary Relations.&amp;rdquo; In International Economic Relations in the Western World 1959-71, edited by Andrew Shonfield, 18-25. London: Oxford University Press, 1976.
While much more than an expanded and internationalised version of Sterling and British Policy (1971), this work covers much of the same period and material. Strange spends little time here developing further her theories and refers the reader to &amp;lsquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach&amp;rsquo; (1972) for her thoughts regarding the discipline of international studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Shipping and the Developing Countries</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_shipping_and_the_developing_countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_shipping_and_the_developing_countries/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, Richard Holland. &amp;ldquo;International Shipping and the Developing Countries.&amp;rdquo; World Development 4, no. 4 (1976): 241-251.
Focusing on the importance of sea transport for developing countries that need to gain access to other markets (both for imports and their own exports) Strange and Holland examine the political economy of liner conferences by which international shipping capacity is managed. This private management system does not serve the developing states well leading UNCTAD to press for fairer international rules of conduct for international shipping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Robert O. Keohane and Joseph S. Nye (1977) Power and Interdependence: World Politics in Transition and Edward L. Morse (1976) Modernization and Transformation of International Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_keohane_and_nye_power_and_interdependence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_keohane_and_nye_power_and_interdependence/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of Robert O. Keohane and Joeseph S. Nye (1977) Power and Interdependence: World Politics in Transition and Edward L. Morse (1976) Modernization and Transformation of International Relations.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 53, no. 2 (1977): 270-273.
In this short review of two important books in the development of International Political Economy, Strange briefly suggests the position which she would adopt more forthrightly later in her career: that IPE was not a sub-discipline of International Relations, but rather sought to completely redefine what it is to study the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Study of Transnational Relations.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 333-345.
Published alongside &amp;lsquo;Who Runs World Shipping?&amp;rsquo; (1976). In this article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane &amp;lsquo;transnational politics&amp;rsquo; approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Who Runs World Shipping?.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 346-367.
Published alongside &amp;lsquo;The Study of Transnational Relations?&amp;rsquo; (1976). Based on the theory developed in that article, Strange&amp;rsquo;s sectoral analysis (of world shipping), which carries some material forward from &amp;lsquo;International shipping and the developing countries&amp;rsquo; (with Richard Holland, 1976).
Keywords: Theory; Trade; International Institutions; Transportation; International Development
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
