<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edited Volume on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/edited-volume/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edited Volume on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/edited-volume/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/information_technology_and_control_in_a_changing_world_understanding_power_structures_in_the_21st_century/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/information_technology_and_control_in_a_changing_world_understanding_power_structures_in_the_21st_century/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Kate Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Draws on Susan Strange’s conception of the knowledge structure to offer guiding theoretical insights for analyzing how the control of knowledge in its many forms is affecting global politics, society and economics.
Keywords: Theory; Knowledge; Structural Power, Power; Security
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall, editor. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. London: Routledge, 2016.
This edited volume addresses the 2007/2009 financial crisis as the occasion to engage critically with the corpus of Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s work, in order to consider what changes (if any) this crisis portends for the structural organization of the global political economy. The contributors use Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on the broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority and Markets: Susan Strange&#39;s Writings of International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/authority_and_markets_susan_stranges_writings_on_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/authority_and_markets_susan_stranges_writings_on_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Authority and Markets: Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s Writings of International Political Economy, edited by Roger Tooze, Christopher May. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2002.
Collection of 16 works by Susan Strange, with an introduction and commentaries by Roger Tooze and Christopher May.
Keywords: Political Economy; Structural Power, Power; Theory; Other
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_power_shaping_the_parameters_of_international_relations_and_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_power_shaping_the_parameters_of_international_relations_and_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Lawton, Thomas, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, editors. Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy. London: Routledge, 2000.
Focusing on the contribution of Susan Strange to the study of international political economy, this collection forms a unique perspective on the global economy whilst providing tools for the reader to better understand that economic system. The book examines Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s structural power theories, whilst adding the perspective of the contributor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Experiences on the Asian Mainland</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, editor. Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Experiences on the Asian Mainland. Florence: European University Institute/Robert Schulman Centre, 1997.
This volume collects together papers presented at a conference organised by Strange at the EUI on 2-4th May 1996. Strange herself only contributed an introduction outlining the papers in the volume and discussing the organisational background to the conference. Strange argues that comparative politics scholars and international business academics need to &amp;lsquo;build bridges&amp;rsquo; between the two disciplines to better understand the interaction between states and firms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths to International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, editor. Paths to International Political Economy. London: Allan and Unwin, 1984.
This is a collection of nine essays looking at various sectoral aspects to the study of IPE, together with a brief preface by Strange. In her preface Strange again singles out development economists, applied economists and economic historians and praises their openness to insights and evidence from other disciplines and sub-disciplines. Implicitly there is an epistemological argument here, against theoretical closure, though as in the majority of her writings this remains implicit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Politics of Surplus Capacity: Competition for Market Shares in the World</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_international_politics_of_surplus_capacity_competition_for_market_shares_in_the_world_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_international_politics_of_surplus_capacity_competition_for_market_shares_in_the_world_/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, Roger Tooze, editors. The International Politics of Surplus Capacity: Competition for Market Shares in the World. London: Allen and Unwin, 1981.
This is a collection of 17 essays resulting from a conference held by the International Political Economy Group of the BISA, together with an editorial overview of theoretical approaches to IPE and a conclusion concerning the agreements and differences among the contributors. Writing with Tooze, Strange notes that it is not intended to dispense with the ‘insights’ of the realists, but it is necessary to widen their approach considerably.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
