<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Chapter on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/book-chapter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Chapter on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/book-chapter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Political Economy and the Changing Global Order: World Order, Non-State Actors, and the Global Casino: The Retreat of the State?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/world_order/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/world_order/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: This is the an edited version of the text published as (1998g) with the addition of a new introduction which briefly lays out many of the arguments which Strange made her own over her long and distinguished career.
Pages 82-90</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The poverty of multilateral economic diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_poverty_of_multilateral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_poverty_of_multilateral/</guid>
      <description>In Diplomacy at the United Nations, edited by Geoff Berridge and Anthony Jennings, 109-129. London: Macmillan Press, 1985.
After reviewing the four values authority might pursue - wealth, security, justice and freedom (an argument developed at more length in States and Markets (1988), she uses these value choices to interrogate the three main paradigms used to think about the international political economy, liberalism, structuralism and nationalism. She then examines UN economic multilateralism utilising an eclectic combination of all three perspectives and concludes that as each approach continues to look to international organisation to sustain the values it emphasises, despite its failings economic multilateralism is likely to continue to be regarded as a worthwhile enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependence in the International Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Interdependence in the International Monetary System.&amp;rdquo; In The Euro-American System: Economic and Political Relations Between North America and Western Europe, edited by Ernst-Otto Czempiel and Dankwar A. Rustow, 31-49. Frankfurt: Westview Press, 1976.&amp;quot;
Strange briefly outlines the character of the international monetary system, noting that while it has become at least partially transnational, posited solutions are still conceived at a national level. This leads her to argue that there needs to be a better attempt made to fit the response to crisis to the level at which it is manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Monetary Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Monetary Relations.&amp;rdquo; In International Economic Relations in the Western World 1959-71, edited by Andrew Shonfield, 18-25. London: Oxford University Press, 1976.
While much more than an expanded and internationalised version of Sterling and British Policy (1971), this work covers much of the same period and material. Strange spends little time here developing further her theories and refers the reader to &amp;lsquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach&amp;rsquo; (1972) for her thoughts regarding the discipline of international studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Poicy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, and Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMF: Monetary Managers</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;IMF: Monetary Managers.&amp;rdquo; In The Anatomy of Influence: Decision Making in International Organisation, edited by Robert W. Cox and Harold K. Jacobson, 263-297. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1974.
This is a detailed case study of the IMF, which Strange uses to back up her warning that there can be no justification for an analytical division between the economic and the political. She argues that the IMF can only be understood within its international political context, and suggests that any institutional changes will reflect the continuing development of the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Business and the EEC</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</guid>
      <description>Stange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Business and the EEC.&amp;rdquo; In The Eruopean Economic Community, edited by James Barber, 82-95. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1974.
Strange discusses the relationship between international business and the EEC by briefly examining three partly overlapping assertions: that the main achievements of the EEC have resulted not from the community’s own work but from the impact of international business; that international business is a ‘Trojan horse’ for American influence and interest in Europe; and that the EEC is a necessary response to the problems brought by international business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economic_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economic_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach.&amp;rdquo; In The Study of International Affairs: Essays in Honour of Kenneth Younger, edited by Roger Morgan, 63-84. London: RIIA/Oxford University Press, 1972.
Strange’s second major attack on the discipline of international economics as it then stood, see also &amp;lsquo;International economics and international relations: a case of mutual neglect&amp;rsquo; (1970). She derides the academic ‘apartheid’ that separates off political considerations from the economic and argues that what is required is a single international studies discipline that encompasses both the politics and economics of international relations (what would eventually become International Political Economy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest.&amp;rdquo; In Decision Making in Britain, edited by James Barber, 165-178. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1972.
In one of her earliest pieces to deal directly with multinational companies or corporations Strange argues that an analysis of the companies not only leads to both domestic and foreign policy making but also into the realm of international (regulatory) policy making. Much of the text is taken up with a discussion of the likely conflicts in interest between governments and corporations with multinational operations (as she prefers to term them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations and International Economic Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_united_nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_united_nations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The United Nations and International Economic Relations.&amp;rdquo; In The Evolving United Nations, edited by Kenneth J. Twitchet, 100-119. London: Europa Publications for the David Davies Memorial Institute of International Studies, 1971.
In The Evolving United Nations, edited by Kenneth J. Twitchet, 100-119. London: Europa Publications for the David Davies Memorial Institute of International Studies, 1971.&amp;quot; excerpt2: &amp;ldquo;Contrasting a Unitarian (‘one-world’) or egalitarian vision of the United Nations mission with a reformist position, Strange argues that despite some early hopes that the UN might remake the global economy, its subsequent history has revealed it to be largely powerless over much of international economic relations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
