<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blayne Haggart on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/contributors/blayne-haggart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blayne Haggart on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/contributors/blayne-haggart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion: Looking Back, Looking Forward</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/conclusion_looking_back_looking_forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/conclusion_looking_back_looking_forward/</guid>
      <description>Tusikov, Natasha, Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne. &amp;ldquo;Conclusion: Looking Back, Looking Forward.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Centuryedited by Blayne Haggart, Natasha Tusikov and Kathryn Henne, 285-306. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Our goal in this book was to spur an inter- and multi-disciplinary dialogue on the rising importance of knowledge in the global political economy and the role of knowledge in contemporary governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov. &amp;ldquo;Introduction.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century, edited by Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 1-20. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
While the control of knowledge is becoming the dominant means by which economic, political, and social control is exerted globally, the mechanisms through which this is happening—including intellectual property rights, state and commercial surveillance, digitisation and datafication, and a nearly ubiquitous internet mediating human interactions—are often examined separately instead of as part of a larger phenomenon of knowledge governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection III</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/reflection_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/reflection_iii/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Reflection III.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century, edited by Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, 213-218. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Blayne Haggart reflects on the chapters by Debora Halbert, and Jenna Harb and Kathryn Henne.
Keywords: Knowledge; Security
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Knowledge Seriously: Towards an International Political Economy Theory of Knowledge Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/taking_knowledge_seriously_towards_an_international_political_economy_theory_of_knowledge_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/taking_knowledge_seriously_towards_an_international_political_economy_theory_of_knowledge_governance/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Taking Knowledge Seriously: Towards an International Political Economy Theory of Knowledge Governance.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 25-52. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This chapter offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 176-203.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power potentially is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This article offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Michael Jablonski. &amp;ldquo;Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?.&amp;rdquo; The Information Society 33, no. 3 (2017): 103-118.
U.S. advocacy for increased international intellectual property protection and a free and open Internet has been criticized as being inconsistent at best and hypocritical at worst. Placing U.S. copyright and Internet policy in a historical context and using Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s concepts of structural power and knowledge structures, we argue that copyright and Internet policies cannot be analyzed in isolation, but are intimately and inextricably linked forms of knowledge regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the &#39;Knowledge Structure&#39;: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the ‘Knowledge Structure’: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 164-175.
Somewhat paradoxically, the implications of knowledge governance&amp;rsquo;s changing role for the exercise of power in the Information Age remains underappreciated outside those scholars and policymakers directly engaged with these specific areas. This special issue brings together political scientists and communication scholars to consider the issue of knowledge governance through the theoretical framework of Susan Strange.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
