<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Oxford University Press on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-oxford-university-press/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Oxford University Press on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-oxford-university-press/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Political Economy and the Changing Global Order: World Order, Non-State Actors, and the Global Casino: The Retreat of the State?</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/world_order/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/world_order/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: This is the an edited version of the text published as (1998g) with the addition of a new introduction which briefly lays out many of the arguments which Strange made her own over her long and distinguished career.
Pages 82-90</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governments, Globalization, and International Business: An International Political Economy Perspective </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/an_international_political_economy_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/an_international_political_economy_perspective/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: In this chapter Strange lays out her idea of what International Political Economy is, including a wide-ranging view of politics (not just the activities of politicians and governments) and a focus on structural power. This then leads her to discuss the problems that globalisation presents for governments, business and people. She concludes that these problems require a re-examination of authority and justice both by states and by international business and adopting an IPE perspective facilitates such analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactions to Brandt. Popular Acclaim and Academic Attack</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/reactions_to_brandt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/reactions_to_brandt/</guid>
      <description>Strange’s ‘review of the reviews’ draws two distinctions between reactions to the Brandt Report - American and European, popular and academic. Her discussion briefly outlines the ‘global Keynsianism’ aspects of the report before noting the criticisms that were levelled at it. After noting that in the academy many of the analyses of the problems and ‘pie in the sky’ solutions were nothing new, her final lament is that the report continues to accept the curative value of research and knowledge, set aside from the political process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</guid>
      <description>Strange proposes a four element theoretical framework for international currencies in the international political economy: Neutral currencies; Top currencies; Master Currencies; and Negotiated currencies, where each category exhibits certain economic and political characteristics. A currency may display more than one set of characteristics but will belong predominantly to one category. She then goes on to discuss the development of the international political economy in light of the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Trends in World Trade</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/changing_trends_in_world_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/changing_trends_in_world_trade/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article: In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers. While encouraging industry in developing states, instead of commodity exports, this would reduce the ‘loading of the dice’ identified by G77.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
