<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working Paper on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/working-paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Working Paper on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/working-paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money (CSGR Working Paper No. 18/98)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_theory_the_theory_in_mad_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_theory_the_theory_in_mad_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money (CSGR Working Paper No. 18/98). Coventry: University of Warwick/Centre for the Study of Globalisation and Regionalisation, 1998.
In this, her final piece of writing, Strange reprise arguments from &amp;lsquo;Rival States, Rival Firms&amp;rsquo; (with John M. Stopford, 1991) and The Retreat of the State (1996) to argue that the disciplines of International Relations and International Economics fail to understand contemporary globalisation. Where IR scholars have missed the structural shifts in the global system away from state-centric power with the emergence of new non-state authority, economists have missed the role of the state in promoting these changes, and misunderstand the working of global markets, discounting, or not even recognising the political relations between firms, what Strange refers to as the new diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traitors, Double Agents or Rescuing Knights</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/traitors_double_agents_or_rescuing_knights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/traitors_double_agents_or_rescuing_knights/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Europe 1992 - Some Personal Observations (SAIIA occasional paper). [Working Paper for] Table Ronde No. 4 ‘Les Individus dans la Politique Internatioanle’ Association Française de Science Politique, Quatrième Congrès, 1992.
In this working paper Strange links her approach laid out in States and Markets (1988) and links it to the research she had recently published on the role of firms in the global system Rival States, Rival Firms (with John M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 1992 - Some Personal Observations (SAIIA occasional paper)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_1992-some_personal_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_1992-some_personal_observations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Johannesburg: South African Institute of International Affairs, 1990.
In this record of a personal address, Strange suggests the 1992 project served both the European collective interest (in the face of Asian and American competition) and the national interests of the major European states (France and Germany), though as notes Britain&amp;rsquo;s position is less clear cut. Post 1992 Strange suggests the democratic deficit (in European institutions), finance (the European Central Bank, co-ordination of banking regulations and the single currency), defence (and public procurement), reciprocity in international trade, and R&amp;amp;D are areas which are likely to be the most important for governments to attend to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
