<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structural Power Theory on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/structural-power-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structural Power Theory on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/structural-power-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange briefly revisits the globalisation debate and suggests those who argue that as the state still exists, globalisation can be ignored are very mistaken. She then goes on to outline three dilemmas of globalisation: the economic, in that increasingly there is no political authority able to govern and control market relations; the environmental, while on one hand market actors are driven by the profit motive to use up environmental resources, countervailing power is largely absent; the political, there is a major democratic deficit in the governance structure of the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a_reply_to_chris_may/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a_reply_to_chris_may/</guid>
      <description>In Strange’s reply to May’s article (Strange Fruit: Susan Strange’s theory of Structural Power in the International Political Economy Global Society 10, 2 (May 1996): 167 -189), she engages with two criticisms made of her theory of structural power. Firstly she suggests that the knowledge structure itself is not necessarily prior as is suggested it might be considered to be if her process of agenda setting power is regarded as central.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Retreat of the State. State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>In what might effectively be regarded as the third part of a trilogy, together with (1988e) and (Strange and Stopford 1991), Strange examines states’ transition towards the sidelines of global political economic relations. Though in the past authority might have been state based, now she argues it is more often based on non-state abilities to bring about (or structure) outcomes. This has to some extent been obscured by the increasing intervention by states in the lives of their citizens, giving an impression of the retention of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred. As in (1975a) the underlying history of bargains, which condition regimes are emphasised as being crucial to any understanding of the IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
