<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Protectionism on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/protectionism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Protectionism on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/protectionism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Protectionism - Why Not?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism/</guid>
      <description>In this short polemic piece Strange argues that states should adopt a pragmatic approach to protectionism (mimicking the practices, if not the ideology of America). With the growth of international production and bi-lateralism it is little wonder that, despite the GATT’s claims to the contrary, the actual figures on international trade suggest the overall protectionism has little effect on growth. This suggests that the state (and politically driven preferential procurement) can still play a role in the national links to international trade without fear of disaster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionism and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade ‘inefficiencies’ as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a ‘secondary structure’ which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures. The disruption in the international system and trade relations is in fact a symptom of disruptions within the primary structures, and especially the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
