<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Helleiner on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/contributors/eric-helleiner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric Helleiner on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/contributors/eric-helleiner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</guid>
      <description>Helleiner, Eric. &amp;ldquo;Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 111-126. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explores Strange&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the centrality of dominant knowledge and financial structures in the constitution of the contours of the global political economy and of financial capitalism. It draws upon critical political economy, focusing on the how of power and its mobilization through dominant knowledge and financial structures to establish central bank independence and financial liberalization as grundnorms of the global financial system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still an Extraordinary Power, but for How Much Longer? The United States in World Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_but_for_how_much_longer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_but_for_how_much_longer/</guid>
      <description>Helleiner, Eric. &amp;ldquo;Still an Extraordinary Power, but for How Much Longer? The United States In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 251-270. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Structural Power, Power; Money and Finance; United States
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
