<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Susan Strange Archive on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Susan Strange Archive on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a-reply-to-chris-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a-reply-to-chris-may/</guid>
      <description>In Strange’s reply to May’s article (Strange Fruit: Susan Strange’s theory of Structural Power in the International Political Economy Global Society 10, 2 (May 1996): 167 -189), she engages with two criticisms made of her theory of structural power. Firstly she suggests that the knowledge structure itself is not necessarily prior as is suggested it might be considered to be if her process of agenda setting power is regarded as central.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a-new-look-at-trade-and-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a-new-look-at-trade-and-aid/</guid>
      <description>In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers. While encouraging industry in developing states, instead of commodity exports, this would reduce the ‘loading of the dice’ identified by G77.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dissident View</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a-dissident-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a-dissident-view/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article: Strange comments on the UN deliberations concerning the future of Palestine and highlights the central factor that gave the Zionists an in-built advantage at the assembly. While the Arabs were negotiating in a state that was essentially antipathetic to their struggle, their opposite numbers were surrounded by sympathisers and supporters both within and outside the organisation. She also discusses some of the limitations and problems with such negotiations within the forum of the UN, and alludes to structural impediments to the ‘fair’ settlement of differences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
