<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Casino Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/casino_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/casino_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange argues that uncertainty and risk in the financial sector/structure have provoked major economic disturbances in the last twenty or so years. This work represents a detailed sectoral history and analysis which argues against many of the proposed solutions to the international economic crisis she identifies. Strange argues that the United States must once again take up the leadership role (which it enjoys by virtue of economic preponderance) and more radically suggests that in the future financial regulation of credit creating agencies should not be a territorially based jurisdiction, but based on the currencies themselves wherever the credit transactions take place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths to International Political Economy </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_ipe/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of nine essays looking at various sectoral aspects to the study of IPE, together with a brief preface by Strange. In her preface Strange again singles out development economists, applied economists and economic historians and praises their openness to insights and evidence from other disciplines and sub-disciplines. Implicitly there is an epistemological argument here, against theoretical closure, though as in the majority of her writings this remains implicit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
