<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Susan Strange&#39;s Work on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/contributors/susan-strange/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Susan Strange&#39;s Work on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/contributors/susan-strange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Authority and Markets: Susan Strange&#39;s Writings of International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/authority_and_markets_susan_stranges_writings_on_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/authority_and_markets_susan_stranges_writings_on_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Authority and Markets: Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s Writings of International Political Economy, edited by Roger Tooze, Christopher May. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2002.
Collection of 16 works by Susan Strange, with an introduction and commentaries by Roger Tooze and Christopher May.
Keywords: Political Economy; Structural Power, Power; Theory; Other
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Order, Non-State Actors, and the Global Casino: The Retreat of the State?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/world_order_non-state_actors_and_the_global_casino_the_retreat_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/world_order_non-state_actors_and_the_global_casino_the_retreat_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;World Order, Non-State Actors, and the Global Casino: The Retreat of the State?&amp;rdquo; In *Political Economy and the Changing Global Order, edited by Richard Stubbs, Geoffrey R.D. Underhill, 82-90. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2000.
This is an edited version of the text published as &amp;lsquo;What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money&amp;rsquo; (1998) with the addition of a new introduction which briefly lays out many of the arguments which Strange made her own over her long and distinguished career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange. &amp;ldquo;The Westfailure System.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Studies 25, no. 3 (1999): 345-354.
In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globaloney? (Review Essay)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/globaloney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/globaloney/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Globaloney? (Review Essay).&amp;rdquo; Review of International Political Economy 5, no. 4 (1998): 704-711.
In this review of the influential Paul Hirst and Grahame Thompson Globalisation in Question (Oxford: Polity Press, 1996) alongside two other books arguing a similar position, Strange makes a major intervention in the debate over the &amp;lsquo;myth&amp;rsquo; of globalisation. Arguing that the authors (like others) miss the deterritorialisation of commercial power in the global system, Strange allows that there needs to be a corrective to the extreme globalisation thesis of complete transformation, but that a failure to examine what is really happening in the global political economy, while relying on aggregated and out-of-date statistics has led too many political economists to fail to recognise the very real changes in the balance of power between multinational corporations and states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: Beyond Economies and International Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_political_economy_beyond_economies_and_international_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_political_economy_beyond_economies_and_international_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Political Economy: Beyond Economies and International Relations.&amp;rdquo; Economies et Sociétés 34, no. 4 (1998): 3-24.
This is slightly revised version of &amp;lsquo;Political Economy and International Relations&amp;rsquo; (1995).
Keywords: Political Economy; Structural Power, Power; Theory; International Relations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mad Money</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/mad_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/mad_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Mad Money. Manchester: Manchester University Press, 1998.
In this sequel to Casino Capitalism (1986) Strange returns to a concentration on the financial structure. Her final book finds Strange once again emphasising the need to recognise the problems of instability in the global financial sector. Arguing that the system itself needed to be reformed, she once again refused to accept that the current upheavals were inevitable or unavoidable.
Keywords: Money and Finance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New World of Debt</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_new_world_of_debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_new_world_of_debt/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The New World of Debt.&amp;rdquo; New Left Review 230, July/August (1998): 91-114.
An extract from Mad Money (1998) in which Strange focuses on the problems of international indebtedness in the 1990s including the Mexican, Brazilian and Asian debt crises and a discussion of central and Eastern European issues. She suggests that the key problem has not been the indebtedness of poor states itself, but the sorts of credit historically extended and the timidity of the solutions to the problems that have arisen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money (CSGR Working Paper No. 18/98)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/what_theory_the_theory_in_mad_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/what_theory_the_theory_in_mad_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. What Theory? The Theory in Mad Money (CSGR Working Paper No. 18/98). Coventry: University of Warwick/Centre for the Study of Globalisation and Regionalisation, 1998.
In this, her final piece of writing, Strange reprise arguments from &amp;lsquo;Rival States, Rival Firms&amp;rsquo; (with John M. Stopford, 1991) and The Retreat of the State (1996) to argue that the disciplines of International Relations and International Economics fail to understand contemporary globalisation. Where IR scholars have missed the structural shifts in the global system away from state-centric power with the emergence of new non-state authority, economists have missed the role of the state in promoting these changes, and misunderstand the working of global markets, discounting, or not even recognising the political relations between firms, what Strange refers to as the new diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Common Market Studies 36, no. 1 (1998): 101-114.
Building on the argument of Robert Reich that the location of economic activity (in a state) was more important for its competitiveness than the ownership of companies (whose production was carried out abroad), Strange suggests that unless European policy recognises the importance of society based competitiveness rather than firm-based competitiveness, Europe&amp;rsquo;s economic problems cannot be overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do International Organisations Never Die?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/why_do_international_organisations_never_die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/why_do_international_organisations_never_die/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Why do International Organisations Never Die?.&amp;rdquo; In Autonomous Policy Making by International Organisations, edited by Bob Reinalda, Bertjan Verbeek, 213-220. London: Routledge, 1998.
In this concluding chapter of a collection of articles drawn from a series of workshops organised under the auspices of the ECPR, Strange reflects on the legacy of The Anatomy of Influence (see &amp;lsquo;‘IMF: Monetary Managers’ [1974]) and suggests that a focus on international organisation remains a largely European enterprise due to the continuing dominance of liberal institutionalism and (neo)Realism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
