<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Production on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/production/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Production on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/production/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Strange Approach to Information, Network, Sharing, and Platform Societies</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_strange_approach_to_information_network_sharing_and_platform_societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_strange_approach_to_information_network_sharing_and_platform_societies/</guid>
      <description>Bannerman Sara, Angela Orasch. &amp;ldquo;A Strange Approach to Information, Network, Sharing, and Platform Societies.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 53-80. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Susan Strange’s framework for international political economic analysis emphasises the importance of the interrelationships between what she saw as four interlinked structures and sources of power in the global economy: security, production, finance, and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power and Counter-Power: Knowledge Structure and the Limits of Control.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/power_and_counter-power_knowledge_structure_and_the_limits_of_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/power_and_counter-power_knowledge_structure_and_the_limits_of_control/</guid>
      <description>David, Matthew, Cynthia Meersohn Schmidt &amp;ldquo;Power and Counter-Power: Knowledge Structure and the Limits of Control.&amp;rdquo; Sociological Research Online 24, no. 1 (2019): 21-37.
In this article, we explore Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s multidimensional and non-reductive international political economy (IPE) approach to structural power. Strange&amp;rsquo;s key weakness is the failure to account for her knowledge structure&amp;rsquo;s regulative form relative to her security, production and financial structures. We seek to develop Strange&amp;rsquo;s account through the addition of Manuel Castells&#39; account of digital network structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precarious Ownership of the Internet of Things in the Age of Data</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/precarious_ownership_of_the_internet_of_things_in_the_age_of_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/precarious_ownership_of_the_internet_of_things_in_the_age_of_data/</guid>
      <description>Tusikov, Natasha. &amp;ldquo;Precarious Ownership of the Internet of Things in the Age of Data.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 121-148. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
The growth of the Internet of Things (IoT)—internet-connected software embedded within physical products—has the potential to shift fundamentally traditional conceptions of ownership and the ways people can access, use, and control information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Common Market Studies 36, no. 1 (1998): 101-114.
Building on the argument of Robert Reich that the location of economic activity (in a state) was more important for its competitiveness than the ownership of companies (whose production was carried out abroad), Strange suggests that unless European policy recognises the importance of society based competitiveness rather than firm-based competitiveness, Europe&amp;rsquo;s economic problems cannot be overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of the Solution? Capitalism and the State System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_problem_of_the_solution_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_problem_of_the_solution_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Problem of the Solution? Capitalism and the State System.&amp;rdquo; In Innovation and Transformation in International Studies, Stephen Gill, James H. Mittelman, editors. 236-247. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1997.
Again Strange criticises International Relations for not focusing on the systemic problems, not least of all environmental and financial issues which a concern for inter-state relations misses. Thus International Political Economy is open to approaches from political geography, historical sociology and elsewhere that have not been fixated on the relations between states as the key causal factor in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe&#39;s Future in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europes_future_in_the_global_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europes_future_in_the_global_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Europe&amp;rsquo;s Future in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Reflections on the Identity of Europe: Global Transatlantic Perspectives, Thomas Row, editor. Bologna: The John Hopkins University Bologna Center, 1996.
Strange argues in this reflection on the future of Europe that too little analytical attention has been paid to the corporate sector and its role in three important structural shifts in the global political economy: new and faster technological changes that have speeded up the competitive cycle (and reduced the time for investors to recover their outlay on innovation); moves in finance towards a much more globalised financial sector with a reduction in the role of national (or in this case European Union) policy interventions; and a shift in the location of production, facilitated by the other two changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Economics: A Sectoral Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_economics_a_sectoral_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_economics_a_sectoral_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Politics of Economics: A Sectoral Analysis.&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues and the Atlantic Community, Wolfram F. Hanrieder, editor. 15-26. New York: Praeger, 1982.
Strange here proposes a structural approach that is implied by her argument that an analysis of the global political economy must be concerned with its ‘environment’. However, while suggesting three of her four later structures - here, security, monetary and production structures - she also includes a number of other structures - transport, trade, communication - that would later become in her schema, secondary structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity_or_how_does_theory_stand_up_to_protectionism_1970s_style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity_or_how_does_theory_stand_up_to_protectionism_1970s_style/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1979): 303-335.
In this article, which is a clear precursor to The Politics of International Surplus Capacity (with Roger Tooze, 1981), Strange discusses the management of surplus capacity in three sectors of the international economy - steel, textiles and shipbuilding, and the recourse to protectionism. She then goes on to discuss the problems this implies for mainstream theories of international economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity,&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues of the Eighties, Nake M. Kamrany and Richard H. Day, editors. 226-246. Baltimore, Johns Hopkins University Press, 1979.
This chapter is a lightly edited version of &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rsquo; (1979).
Keywords: Production, Structural Power, Power, Theory, Trade
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, &amp;ldquo;A New Look at Trade and Aid,&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 42 no. 1 (1966): 61 - 73.
In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
