<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hegemony on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/hegemony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hegemony on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/hegemony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_erosion_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange briefly revisits the globalisation debate and suggests those who argue that as the state still exists, globalisation can be ignored are very mistaken. She then goes on to outline three dilemmas of globalisation: the economic, in that increasingly there is no political authority able to govern and control market relations; the environmental, while on one hand market actors are driven by the profit motive to use up environmental resources, countervailing power is largely absent; the political, there is a major democratic deficit in the governance structure of the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/who_governs_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/who_governs_networks/</guid>
      <description>Starting from Strange’s response to Waltz’s (in)famous London School of Economic lecture (see Millennium 22/2 - Summer 1993) in this article she first argues for a wider reading of politics – not just what states do. She then briefly summarises her arguments regarding structural power before discussing the roles states have historically played as producers of security, credit, market relations and environment. The power over finance and environment has moved to centre stage, but states have been losing relative power over these areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending Benign Mercantilism </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>In this review of Robert Gilpin’s Political Economy of International Relations, Strange again argues against ‘Hegemonic Stability Theory’, see (1987), but has started to develop a theory of transnational empire to explain the structural power of the United States. Part of this argument is the increasing non-territoriality of structural power, which is developed in a number of works below.
Journal of Peace Research. Volume: 25 Issue: 3. Pages 273-277</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange identifies three ‘shaky assumptions’ underlying the call to revive the GATT negotiations, that protectionism was the main cause of the 1930s depression, that the GATT was a necessary condition of post-war recovery, and free trade was ever a widely followed ‘norm’. However, though the alternatives are presented as a hegemonic system run by the US or a multilateral system managed through the GATT, Strange argues that the reality is a cob-web of bi-lateral agreements which accords with many people’s desire to have their own state manage their affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
