<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hegemony on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/hegemony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hegemony on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/hegemony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm.&amp;rdquo; International Studies Quality 39, no. 3 (1995): 289-295.
After briefly discussing the history of the ISA, Strange points out that it is the International Studies Association, despite the current domination of International Relations. Once again Strange argues for the constructive engagement with other discipline interested in the international system, from political geographers to business economists. Strange points to the relative decline of state-state violence relative to civil and local violence, the increasing interest in the environment, and the dangers stemming from the financial markets, as reasons for widening the ISA&amp;rsquo;s implicit agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance and Capitalism: The City&#39;s Imperial Role Yesterday and Today</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Finance and Capitalism: The City&amp;rsquo;s Imperial Role Yesterday and Today.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Studies 20, no. 4 (1994): 407-410.
In this short review of P.J. Cain and A.G. Hopkins British Imperialism (2 vols) (London: Longman 1993), Strange again emphasises the structural characteristics of US power in the global system and suggest that Britain&amp;rsquo;s structural power was more long lasting than is sometimes presumed, with clear implications for the continuing power of the US in the global economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Fall&#39; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;Fall&amp;rdquo; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy.&amp;rdquo; In The Fall of Great Powers: Peace, Stability and Legitimacy, Geir Lundestad, editor. 197-211. Oslo and Oxford: Scandinavian University Press and Oxford University Press, 1994.
Once again Strange argues at length that the notion of American decline in the global system is mistaken if examined through her structural perspective. She presents a brief history of the previous fifty years to explore how America&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;fall&amp;rsquo; can be proposed and why this misunderstands power in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of  Finance in the World System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_structure_of__finance_in_the_world_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_structure_of__finance_in_the_world_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Structure of Finance in the World System.&amp;rdquo; In Global Transformation: Challenges to the State System, Yoshikazu Sakamoto, editor. 228-249. Tokyo: United Nations University Press, 1994.
Strange again stresses, as she has done before, that the crucial element of the financial structure is the ability to create credit. This is only one side of the financial structure, however - the other side is the institutional regulation of exchange rates between currencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_governs_networks_of_power_in_world_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_governs_networks_of_power_in_world_society/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society.&amp;rdquo; Hitotsubashi Journal of Law and Politics Special Issue (1994): 5-17.
Starting from Strange&amp;rsquo;s response to Waltz&amp;rsquo;s (in)famous London School of Economic lecture (see Millennium 22/2 - Summer 1993) in this article she first argues for a wider reading of politics – not just what states do. She then briefly summarises her arguments regarding structural power before discussing the roles states have historically played as producers of security, credit, market relations and environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transformation of the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_transformation_of_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_transformation_of_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Transformation of the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Mapping the Unknown: Towards a New World Order (Yearbook of the Swedish Institute for International Affairs 1992-1993), Lidija Babic, Bo Huldt, editors. 43-49. London: Hurst and Co., 1993.
In this short article Strange reviews many of the same arguments that have been featured above. However, here she argues that the transformation of the world economy is not so much the product of state/firm interactions, rather it is firms that are playing (and will continue to play) the more important role in structural change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?.&amp;rdquo; In The External Relations of the European Community, in Particular EC-US Relations, Jürgen Schwarze, editor. 109-118. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1989.
Strange suggests that the two primary activities of any political organisation are the furtherance of security and the control of money, and it is these issues that remain at the centre of the problem of US-Europe relations. Here Strange again challenges the assumption of a loss of American hegemony (and therefore power) in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Theory of Transnational Empire</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/towards_a_theory_of_transnational_empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/towards_a_theory_of_transnational_empire/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Towards a Theory of Transnational Empire.&amp;rdquo; In Global Changes and Theoretical Challenges: Approaches to World Politics for the 1990s, Ernst-Otto Czempiel, James N. Roseneau, editors. 161-176. Lexington: Lexington Books, 1989.
In this article Strange offers only her second explicit excursion into the epistemology of international theories, the first being a similar section in States and Markets (1988). She argues that theories must be more than description, taxonomy, importation of models from other disciplines or quantitative and that theories must explain some aspect of the international system not obvious to &amp;lsquo;commonsense&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending Benign Mercantilism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Defending Benign Mercantilism.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Peace Research 25, no. 3 (1988): 273-277.
In this review of Robert Gilpin&amp;rsquo;s Political Economy of International Relations, Strange again argues against &amp;lsquo;Hegemonic Stability Theory&amp;rsquo;, see &amp;lsquo;The persistent myth of lost hegemony&amp;rsquo; (1987), but has started to develop a theory of transnational empire to explain the structural power of the United States. Part of this argument is the increasing non-territoriality of structural power, which is developed in a number of works below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of the American Empire</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_future_of_the_american_empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_future_of_the_american_empire/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;The Future of the American Empire.&amp;rdquo; Journal of International Affairs 42, no. 1 (1988): 1-17.
Strange argues that increasingly power in the international political economy is not territorially defined, and what has emerged is an empire that is not territorially based, and secondly is controlled by information-rich US corporations. However while she call this the &amp;lsquo;American Empire&amp;rsquo; her argument is (self-avowedly) close to an international Gramscian &amp;lsquo;historical bloc&amp;rsquo; analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
