<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hegemony on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/hegemony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hegemony on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/hegemony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>In The persistent myth of lost hegemony International Organization 41,no.4(Autumn),551-574.197.
Strange’s classic attack of the ‘declinist school’ in international relations. Once she has discussed the more ‘sociological’ reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE. This exposition closely parallels (though in a brief form) the arguments that appear in States and Markets (1988).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981),&amp;rdquo; International Journal 38, no. 2 (1983): 355-356.
Strange criticises Bergsten’s exaggeration of US decline in hegemonic power and absolution of the USA of bearing prime responsibility for the deteriorating economic situation. Indeed much of her work in the 1980s revolved round the dual need to recognise US responsibility for global economic crises, and the problem of such a responsibility being denied by the US (both policy makers and academics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Credit Crisis: A European View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_credit_crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_credit_crisis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Credit Crisis: A European View,&amp;rdquo; SAIS Review 3, no. 2 (1983): 171-181.
Strange here uses the term crisis, but notes that the implication that some sort of solution is imminent is less than certain. She suggests that the world economic crisis has three interrelated aspects: unemployment, ‘flagging trade’, and unstable money. As in ‘The Management of Surplus Capacity: Or how does theory stand up to protectionism 1970s style?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe and the United States: The Transatlantic Aspects of Inflation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_and_the_us_the_transatlantic_aspects_of_inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_and_the_us_the_transatlantic_aspects_of_inflation/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Europe and the United States: The Transatlantic Aspects of Inflation,&amp;rdquo; In The Politics of Inflation: Acomparative Analysis, edited by Richard Medley, 65-76. New York: Pergamon Press, 1982.
This short article discusses the international financial sector and the interaction between American monetary policy and European exchange rates, monetary policy and the then new European Monetary System. While containing little explication of structural power, being more of an historical overview, the article is of interest for Strange’s concluding discussion of the reasons for American domination of the international financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still and Extraordinary Power: America&#39;s Role in the Global Monetary System (Paper 3) (with discussants section)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_and_extraordinary_power_americas_role_in_the_global_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_and_extraordinary_power_americas_role_in_the_global_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Still and Extraordinary Power: America&amp;rsquo;s Role in the Global Monetary System (Paper 3) (with discussants section),&amp;rdquo; In The Political Economy of Interdependence and Domestic Monetary Relations, edited by Raymond E. Lomra and Willard E. Witte, 73-93. Ames: Iowa State University Press, 1982.
excerpt2: &amp;ldquo;A paper delivered to a conference on international monetary relations. As well as considering power in the financial markets, Strange also makes a provisional (in light of her later work) analysis of structural power in the international political economy more generally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependence in the International Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Interdependence in the International Monetary System.&amp;rdquo; In The Euro-American System: Economic and Political Relations Between North America and Western Europe, edited by Ernst-Otto Czempiel and Dankwar A. Rustow, 31-49. Frankfurt: Westview Press, 1976.&amp;quot;
Strange briefly outlines the character of the international monetary system, noting that while it has become at least partially transnational, posited solutions are still conceived at a national level. This leads her to argue that there needs to be a better attempt made to fit the response to crisis to the level at which it is manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Monetary Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Monetary Relations.&amp;rdquo; In International Economic Relations in the Western World 1959-71, edited by Andrew Shonfield, 18-25. London: Oxford University Press, 1976.
While much more than an expanded and internationalised version of Sterling and British Policy (1971), this work covers much of the same period and material. Strange spends little time here developing further her theories and refers the reader to &amp;lsquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach&amp;rsquo; (1972) for her thoughts regarding the discipline of international studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arab Oil and International Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Arab Oil and International Finance.&amp;rdquo; The Ditchley Journal, 1974.
Essentially a conference report, Strange discusses the meeting held at Ditchley in December 1973 to discuss the financial prospects and problems for industry and government in the world economy, and the inescapable problem of the oil crisis. Discussing the various aspects of monetary order, from balance of payments problems and trade barriers, to financial flows, she argues that at this point too little work had been done to understand the effects and causes of shifts in monetary flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of : R.J Barber The American Corporation: Its Power, Its Money, Its Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_rj_barber/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_rj_barber/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of : R.J Barber The American Corporation: Its Power, Its Money, Its Politics.&amp;rdquo; International Journal 27, no. 2 (1972): 308-309.
Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dollar Crisis 1971</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Dollar Crisis 1971.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 48, no. 2 (1972): 191-216.
Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
