<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hegemony on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/hegemony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hegemony on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/hegemony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</guid>
      <description>Helleiner, Eric. &amp;ldquo;Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 111-126. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explores Strange&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the centrality of dominant knowledge and financial structures in the constitution of the contours of the global political economy and of financial capitalism. It draws upon critical political economy, focusing on the how of power and its mobilization through dominant knowledge and financial structures to establish central bank independence and financial liberalization as grundnorms of the global financial system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Power Over Credit; or the Enduring Strength of US Structural-Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/strange_power_over_credit_or_the_enduring_strength_of_us_structural-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/strange_power_over_credit_or_the_enduring_strength_of_us_structural-power/</guid>
      <description>Schwartz, Herman Mark. &amp;ldquo;Strange Power Over Credit; or the Enduring Strength of US Structural-Power.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 87-110. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter provides some retrospective comments on what Strange says on the nexus of money and power; and second, in the light of what she had to say, to assess her vision of where the monetary system is heading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Global Transformation: Susan Strange, E.H. Carr and the Dynamics of Structural Change</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_political_economy_of_global_transformation_susan_strange_eh_carr_and_the_dynamics_of_structural_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_political_economy_of_global_transformation_susan_strange_eh_carr_and_the_dynamics_of_structural_change/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;The Political Economy of Global Transformation: Susan Strange, E.H. Carr and the Dynamics of Structural Change.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 183-200. London: Routledge, 2016.
Do international relations precede or follow (logically) fundamental social relations? There can be no doubt that they follow. Any organic innovation in the social structure, through its technical–military expressions, modifies organically absolute and relative relations in the international field too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm.&amp;rdquo; International Studies Quality 39, no. 3 (1995): 289-295.
After briefly discussing the history of the ISA, Strange points out that it is the International Studies Association, despite the current domination of International Relations. Once again Strange argues for the constructive engagement with other discipline interested in the international system, from political geographers to business economists. Strange points to the relative decline of state-state violence relative to civil and local violence, the increasing interest in the environment, and the dangers stemming from the financial markets, as reasons for widening the ISA&amp;rsquo;s implicit agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance and Capitalism: The City&#39;s Imperial Role Yesterday and Today</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Finance and Capitalism: The City&amp;rsquo;s Imperial Role Yesterday and Today.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Studies 20, no. 4 (1994): 407-410.
In this short review of P.J. Cain and A.G. Hopkins British Imperialism (2 vols) (London: Longman 1993), Strange again emphasises the structural characteristics of US power in the global system and suggest that Britain&amp;rsquo;s structural power was more long lasting than is sometimes presumed, with clear implications for the continuing power of the US in the global economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Fall&#39; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;Fall&amp;rdquo; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy.&amp;rdquo; In The Fall of Great Powers: Peace, Stability and Legitimacy, edited by Geir Lundestad, 197-211. Oslo and Oxford: Scandinavian University Press and Oxford University Press, 1994.
Once again Strange argues at length that the notion of American decline in the global system is mistaken if examined through her structural perspective. She presents a brief history of the previous fifty years to explore how America&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;fall&amp;rsquo; can be proposed and why this misunderstands power in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of  Finance in the World System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_structure_of__finance_in_the_world_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_structure_of__finance_in_the_world_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Structure of Finance in the World System.&amp;rdquo; In Global Transformation: Challenges to the State System, edited by Yoshikazu Sakamoto, 228-249. Tokyo: United Nations University Press, 1994.
Strange again stresses, as she has done before, that the crucial element of the financial structure is the ability to create credit. This is only one side of the financial structure, however - the other side is the institutional regulation of exchange rates between currencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_governs_networks_of_power_in_world_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_governs_networks_of_power_in_world_society/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society.&amp;rdquo; Hitotsubashi Journal of Law and Politics Special Issue (1994): 5-17.
Starting from Strange&amp;rsquo;s response to Waltz&amp;rsquo;s (in)famous London School of Economic lecture (see Millennium: 22/2 - Summer 1993) in this article she first argues for a wider reading of politics – not just what states do. She then briefly summarises her arguments regarding structural power before discussing the roles states have historically played as producers of security, credit, market relations and environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transformation of the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_transformation_of_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_transformation_of_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Transformation of the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Mapping the Unknown: Towards a New World Order (Yearbook of the Swedish Institute for International Affairs 1992-1993), edited by Lidija Babic, Bo Huldt, 43-49. London: Hurst and Co., 1993.
In this short article Strange reviews many of the same arguments that have been featured above. However, here she argues that the transformation of the world economy is not so much the product of state/firm interactions, rather it is firms that are playing (and will continue to play) the more important role in structural change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?&amp;rdquo; In The External Relations of the European Community, in Particular EC-US Relations, edited by Jürgen Schwarze, 109-118. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1989.
Strange suggests that the two primary activities of any political organisation are the furtherance of security and the control of money, and it is these issues that remain at the centre of the problem of US-Europe relations. Here Strange again challenges the assumption of a loss of American hegemony (and therefore power) in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
