<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: SAGE Journals on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-sage-journals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: SAGE Journals on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-sage-journals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Business and the State</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/big_business_and_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/big_business_and_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange argues in this short piece that TNCs should be placed at the centre of IPE analysis along with the state and should not be left on the periphery. She also argues for an outside-in understanding of TNCs, putting them into the context in which they operate to understand them. This context is being transformed by changes in the production and financial structures, while she implicitly also argues for the centrality of changes in the ‘knowledge’ structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending Benign Mercantilism </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>In this review of Robert Gilpin’s Political Economy of International Relations, Strange again argues against ‘Hegemonic Stability Theory’, see (1987), but has started to develop a theory of transnational empire to explain the structural power of the United States. Part of this argument is the increasing non-territoriality of structural power, which is developed in a number of works below.
Journal of Peace Research. Volume: 25 Issue: 3. Pages 273-277</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_global_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_global_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration. Strange also stresses that while the four structures are not hierarchical, she believes it is disruptions in the financial structure that has caused most upheavals over the period examined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981)</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</guid>
      <description>Strange criticises Bergsten’s exaggeration of US decline in hegemonic power and absolution of the USA of bearing prime responsibility for the deteriorating economic situation. Indeed much of her work in the 1980s revolved round the dual need to recognise US responsibility for global economic crises, and the problem of such a responsibility being denied by the US (both policy makers and academics).
International Journal. Volume: 38 Issue: 2. Pages 355-356</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back - But Mostly Forward</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</guid>
      <description>In this survey article, Strange looks back across the first ten years of Millennium to examine the development of International Relations, although as she makes plain she prefers the term International Studies. Having seen the field expand from a focus on the foreign polices of various states, she maps the increasing interest in the international system itself. However, she then argues that what is now needed is a further development of research into the structures of this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_worlds_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_worlds_money/</guid>
      <description>After a survey of current modes of thought, both academic and practitioner, Strange concludes that while much analysis can usefully illuminate the mechanisms of the global monetary system, there is little attempt ally this to a consideration how the system links up with and effects the values of and outcomes in a globalised society. She wants work on the international monetary system to go beyond a mere mechanical explanation and to move towards a more political analysis (which would also include an assessment of the impact of technology on global finance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/what_is_economic_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/what_is_economic_power/</guid>
      <description>Here Strange commits to print an early version of the structure of power theory which she would develop over the next thirteen years. In this manifestation, there are three dimensions of power in the international political economy - security, ‘ideology’ and economic. There is more concern, though, with a location of four level or stages at which economic power is apparent - the world market structure; international co-operative relations; national/governmental control of markets; and the operational level of the economic transactions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
