<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Money and Finance on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/money-and-finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Money and Finance on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/money-and-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Susan Strange saw the financial crisis coming, Your Majesty&#39;: The Case for the LSE&#39;s Great Global Political Economist</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_saw_the_financial_crisis_coming_your_majesty_the_case_for_the_lses_great_global_political_economist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_saw_the_financial_crisis_coming_your_majesty_the_case_for_the_lses_great_global_political_economist/</guid>
      <description>Dyer, Nat. &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Susan Strange saw the financial crisis coming, Your Majesty&amp;rsquo;: The Case for the LSE’s Great Global Political Economist.&amp;rdquo; Real-World Economic Review 98 (2021).
This paper makes three arguments. First, that Susan Strange (1923-1998), who founded the field of international political economy in the UK, is one of the principal thinkers who foresaw multiple aspects of the global financial crisis of 2008 and its aftermath. She deserves credit for her prescience but has been overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Structural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalization_and_the_rise_of_integrated_world_society_deterritorialization/</guid>
      <description>Babones, Salvatore, John H.S. Aberg. &amp;lsquo;Globalization and the Rise of Integrated World Society: Deterritorialization, Structural-Power, and the Endogenization of International Society.&amp;rsquo; International Theory 11, no. 3 (2019): 293-317.
There is a widespread feeling that globalization represents a major system change that has or should have brought world society to the forefront of international relations theory. Nonetheless, world society remains an amorphous and undertheorized concept, and its potential role in shaping the structure of the international society of states has scarcely been raised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power and Counter-Power: Knowledge Structure and the Limits of Control.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/power_and_counter-power_knowledge_structure_and_the_limits_of_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/power_and_counter-power_knowledge_structure_and_the_limits_of_control/</guid>
      <description>David, Matthew, Cynthia Meersohn Schmidt &amp;ldquo;Power and Counter-Power: Knowledge Structure and the Limits of Control.&amp;rdquo; Sociological Research Online 24, no. 1 (2019): 21-37.
In this article, we explore Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s multidimensional and non-reductive international political economy (IPE) approach to structural power. Strange&amp;rsquo;s key weakness is the failure to account for her knowledge structure&amp;rsquo;s regulative form relative to her security, production and financial structures. We seek to develop Strange&amp;rsquo;s account through the addition of Manuel Castells&#39; account of digital network structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Financial Crime Wave Is No Accident.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_global_financial_crime_wave_is_no_accident/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_global_financial_crime_wave_is_no_accident/</guid>
      <description>Dyer, Nat. &amp;ldquo;The Global Financial Crime Wave Is No Accident.&amp;rdquo; Open Democracy (2018).
Financial crime is a feature of our global financial system not a bug, pioneering economist Susan Strange recognised. Her message is more urgent than ever.
Keywords: Money and Finance; Security
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Currency Internationalisation: The Case of the RMB</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency_internationalisation_the_case_of_the_rmb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency_internationalisation_the_case_of_the_rmb/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall, Herman Mark Schwartz. &amp;ldquo;The Political Economy of Currency Internationalisation: The Case of the RMB.&amp;rdquo; *Review of International Studies * 43, no. 3 (2017): 765-787.
The rise of China has sparked a debate about the economic and political consequences for the global economy of the internationalisation of the renminbi. We argue that the dominant focus of this literature – primarily the external conditions and requirements for a national currency to become an international currency – misspecifies the connections between the international and domestic requirements for currency internationalisation, as well as the potential to become the dominant international reserve currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money, Power, Authority</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/money_power_authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/money_power_authority/</guid>
      <description>Cohen, BenjamIn J. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 129-143. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter discusses the political economy of the global transformation. The share of American gross domestic product (GDP) in relation to global GDP had declined; the control of American corporations over key international markets remained high and was even growing. Strange argued that the global articulation of power was constituted by a complicated amalgam of public and the private authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</guid>
      <description>Helleiner, Eric. &amp;ldquo;Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 111-126. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explores Strange&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the centrality of dominant knowledge and financial structures in the constitution of the contours of the global political economy and of financial capitalism. It draws upon critical political economy, focusing on the how of power and its mobilization through dominant knowledge and financial structures to establish central bank independence and financial liberalization as grundnorms of the global financial system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Bedfellows? Bankers, Business(men) and Bureaucrats in Global Financial Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_bedfellows_bankers_businessmen_and_bureaucrats_in_global_financial_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_bedfellows_bankers_businessmen_and_bureaucrats_in_global_financial_governance/</guid>
      <description>Cutler, A. Claire. &amp;ldquo;Strange Bedfellows? Bankers, Business(men) and Bureaucrats In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 144-169. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explains how to diagnose the human condition in a dynamic global system. Strange was the one who insisted that the things to be explained were not always what they seemed, and that theory, especially the grand theory, could obscure the fundamental realities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Power Over Credit; or the Enduring Strength of US Structural-Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_power_over_credit_or_the_enduring_strength_of_us_structural-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_power_over_credit_or_the_enduring_strength_of_us_structural-power/</guid>
      <description>Schwartz, Herman Mark. &amp;ldquo;Strange Power Over Credit; or the Enduring Strength of US Structural-Power.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 87-110. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter provides some retrospective comments on what Strange says on the nexus of money and power; and second, in the light of what she had to say, to assess her vision of where the monetary system is heading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall, editor. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. London: Routledge, 2016.
This edited volume addresses the 2007/2009 financial crisis as the occasion to engage critically with the corpus of Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s work, in order to consider what changes (if any) this crisis portends for the structural organization of the global political economy. The contributors use Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on the broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
