<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Money and Finance on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/money-and-finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Money and Finance on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/money-and-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 39, no. 2 (1984): 267-283.
After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe and the United States: The Transatlantic Aspects of Inflation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_and_the_us_the_transatlantic_aspects_of_inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_and_the_us_the_transatlantic_aspects_of_inflation/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Europe and the United States: The Transatlantic Aspects of Inflation,&amp;rdquo; In The Politics of Inflation: Acomparative Analysis, edited by Richard Medley, 65-76. New York: Pergamon Press, 1982.
This short article discusses the international financial sector and the interaction between American monetary policy and European exchange rates, monetary policy and the then new European Monetary System. While containing little explication of structural power, being more of an historical overview, the article is of interest for Strange’s concluding discussion of the reasons for American domination of the international financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still and Extraordinary Power: America&#39;s Role in the Global Monetary System (Paper 3) (with discussants section)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_and_extraordinary_power_americas_role_in_the_global_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_and_extraordinary_power_americas_role_in_the_global_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Still and Extraordinary Power: America&amp;rsquo;s Role in the Global Monetary System (Paper 3) (with discussants section),&amp;rdquo; In The Political Economy of Interdependence and Domestic Monetary Relations, edited by Raymond E. Lomra and Willard E. Witte, 73-93. Ames: Iowa State University Press, 1982.
excerpt2: &amp;ldquo;A paper delivered to a conference on international monetary relations. As well as considering power in the financial markets, Strange also makes a provisional (in light of her later work) analysis of structural power in the international political economy more generally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money_expanding_the_agenda_for_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money_expanding_the_agenda_for_research/</guid>
      <description>Strnage, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The World&amp;rsquo;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 36, no. 4 (1981): 691-712.
After a survey of current modes of thought, both academic and practitioner, Strange concludes that while much analysis can usefully illuminate the mechanisms of the global monetary system, there is little attempt ally this to a consideration how the system links up with and effects the values of and outcomes in a globalised society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Germany and the World Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/germany_and_the_world_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/germany_and_the_world_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Germany and the World Monetary System,&amp;rdquo; In West Germany: A European and Global Power, edited by Wilfrid L. Kohl and Georgio Basevi, 45-62. Lexington: Lexington Books, 1980.
Strange suggests that for any major state in the global system, such as Germany there are five roles that could be adopted by its government: ‘leader of the system’, ‘obedient ally’, ‘bigemonist partner’, ‘lone ranger’ or ‘leader of the opposition’. After discussing recent developments in the political economy of German and Europe, Strange suggests that it is time for Germany to consider a role more like that adopted briefly by De Gaulle’s France in the early 1960s, that of ‘leader of the opposition’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Default in the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Debt and Default in the International Political Economy,&amp;rdquo; In Debt and the Less Developed Countries, edited by Johnathan David, 7-26. Boulder, Westview Press, 1979.
Explicitly linking back to &amp;lsquo;Debts, Defaulters and Development&amp;rsquo; (1967) Strange examines the contemporary political economy of international debt, but also seeks to put this situation into a longer historical context than merely the previous ten years. Suggesting that states can choose to grow by direction (the socialist route) or via debt, she argues that recently the combination of the welfare state and more complex credit system has allowed many states to reduce the debt risk they explicitly face and therefore expand through the extensive use of credit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependence in the International Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/interdependence_in_the_international_monetary_system/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Interdependence in the International Monetary System.&amp;rdquo; In The Euro-American System: Economic and Political Relations Between North America and Western Europe, edited by Ernst-Otto Czempiel and Dankwar A. Rustow, 31-49. Frankfurt: Westview Press, 1976.&amp;quot;
Strange briefly outlines the character of the international monetary system, noting that while it has become at least partially transnational, posited solutions are still conceived at a national level. This leads her to argue that there needs to be a better attempt made to fit the response to crisis to the level at which it is manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Monetary Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_monetary_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Monetary Relations.&amp;rdquo; In International Economic Relations in the Western World 1959-71, edited by Andrew Shonfield, 18-25. London: Oxford University Press, 1976.
While much more than an expanded and internationalised version of Sterling and British Policy (1971), this work covers much of the same period and material. Strange spends little time here developing further her theories and refers the reader to &amp;lsquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach&amp;rsquo; (1972) for her thoughts regarding the discipline of international studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, and Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arab Oil and International Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Arab Oil and International Finance.&amp;rdquo; The Ditchley Journal, 1974.
Essentially a conference report, Strange discusses the meeting held at Ditchley in December 1973 to discuss the financial prospects and problems for industry and government in the world economy, and the inescapable problem of the oil crisis. Discussing the various aspects of monetary order, from balance of payments problems and trade barriers, to financial flows, she argues that at this point too little work had been done to understand the effects and causes of shifts in monetary flows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
