<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Europe on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Europe on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge and Structural-Power in the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/knowledge_and_structural-power_in_the_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/knowledge_and_structural-power_in_the_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Mytelka, Lynn K. &amp;ldquo;Knowledge and Structural-Power In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 61-78. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Knowledge; Structural Power, Power; Europe; Political Economy; International Relations
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Common Market Studies 36, no. 1 (1998): 101-114.
Building on the argument of Robert Reich that the location of economic activity (in a state) was more important for its competitiveness than the ownership of companies (whose production was carried out abroad), Strange suggests that unless European policy recognises the importance of society based competitiveness rather than firm-based competitiveness, Europe&amp;rsquo;s economic problems cannot be overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do International Organisations Never Die?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/why_do_international_organisations_never_die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/why_do_international_organisations_never_die/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Why do International Organisations Never Die?.&amp;rdquo; In Autonomous Policy Making by International Organisations, edited by Bob Reinalda, Bertjan Verbeek, 213-220. London: Routledge, 1998.
In this concluding chapter of a collection of articles drawn from a series of workshops organised under the auspices of the ECPR, Strange reflects on the legacy of The Anatomy of Influence (see &amp;lsquo;‘IMF: Monetary Managers’ [1974]) and suggests that a focus on international organisation remains a largely European enterprise due to the continuing dominance of liberal institutionalism and (neo)Realism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe&#39;s Future in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europes_future_in_the_global_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europes_future_in_the_global_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Europe&amp;rsquo;s Future in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Reflections on the Identity of Europe: Global Transatlantic Perspectives, edited by Thomas Row. Bologna: The John Hopkins University Bologna Center, 1996.
Strange argues in this reflection on the future of Europe that too little analytical attention has been paid to the corporate sector and its role in three important structural shifts in the global political economy: new and faster technological changes that have speeded up the competitive cycle (and reduced the time for investors to recover their outlay on innovation); moves in finance towards a much more globalised financial sector with a reduction in the role of national (or in this case European Union) policy interventions; and a shift in the location of production, facilitated by the other two changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Business in Japan. A Policy Cross-roads?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_business_in_japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_business_in_japan/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;European Business in Japan. A Policy Cross-roads?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Common Market Studies 33, no. 1 (1995): 1-25.
Contrasting European and American proposals for the perceived difficulty of setting up foreign owned subsidiaries in Japan, Strange argues that this is a central issue for any nascent European foreign policy initiative. She argues that it may now be beyond any nationally elected government (even in the US.) to re-impose its hegemonic intent on other states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power Gap: Member States and the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_power_gap_member_states_and_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_power_gap_member_states_and_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Power Gap: Member States and the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Economic Policy Making and the European Union, edited by Frank Brouwer, Valerio Linter, Mike Newman, 19-26. London: Federal Trust, 1994.
Strange criticises arguments that suggest the European Union is a sui generis political institution. She criticises such claims, self avowedly, not from a lengthy engagement with European political analysis, but from a more global concern with political economy. She suggests that except for the Commission there is little to distinguish the EU from some other intergovernmental organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe 1992 - Some Personal Observations (SAIIA occasional paper)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_1992-some_personal_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/europe_1992-some_personal_observations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Johannesburg: South African Institute of International Affairs, 1990.
In this record of a personal address, Strange suggests the 1992 project served both the European collective interest (in the face of Asian and American competition) and the national interests of the major European states (France and Germany), though as notes Britain&amp;rsquo;s position is less clear cut. Post 1992 Strange suggests the democratic deficit (in European institutions), finance (the European Central Bank, co-ordination of banking regulations and the single currency), defence (and public procurement), reciprocity in international trade, and R&amp;amp;D are areas which are likely to be the most important for governments to attend to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?&amp;rdquo; In The External Relations of the European Community, in Particular EC-US Relations, edited by Jürgen Schwarze, 109-118. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1989.
Strange suggests that the two primary activities of any political organisation are the furtherance of security and the control of money, and it is these issues that remain at the centre of the problem of US-Europe relations. Here Strange again challenges the assumption of a loss of American hegemony (and therefore power) in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dissident View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_dissident_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_dissident_view/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;A Dissident View.&amp;rdquo; In One European Market? A Critical Analysis of the Commission&amp;rsquo;s Internal Market Strategy, edited byRoland Bieber, John Pinder, Joseph H.H. Weiler, 73-76. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1988.
A brief article in which Strange argues that in the national competition for market shares within the global economy, there are two important strategies, neither of which at that time could the European Community realistically follow. Firstly, state procurement can be used as a stimulus to research and development and secondly the control of market access can be used as a bargaining lever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics, Trade and Money</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/politics_trade_and_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/politics_trade_and_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Politics, Trade and Money.&amp;rdquo; In Europe, America and the World Economy, edited by Loukas Tsoukalis, 243-255. Oxford: Basil Blackwell for the College of Europe, 1986.
Strange identifies two main obstructions to a constructive dialogue between the United States and Europe over international trade: America&amp;rsquo;s lack of interest in maintaining a steady provision of credit to the interdependent international system; and Europe&amp;rsquo;s inability to take responsibility for its own defence and security, and therefore reducing its dependence on America.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
