<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Europe on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Europe on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Credit Crisis: A European View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_credit_crisis_a_european_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_credit_crisis_a_european_view/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Credit Crisis: A European View,&amp;rdquo; SAIS Review 3, no. 2 (1983): 171-181.
Strange here uses the term crisis, but notes that the implication that some sort of solution is imminent is less than certain. She suggests that the world economic crisis has three interrelated aspects: unemployment, ‘flagging trade’, and unstable money. As in ‘The Management of Surplus Capacity: Or how does theory stand up to protectionism 1970s style?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Business and the EEC</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</guid>
      <description>Stange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Business and the EEC.&amp;rdquo; In The Eruopean Economic Community, edited by James Barber, 82-95. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1974.
Strange discusses the relationship between international business and the EEC by briefly examining three partly overlapping assertions: that the main achievements of the EEC have resulted not from the community’s own work but from the impact of international business; that international business is a ‘Trojan horse’ for American influence and interest in Europe; and that the EEC is a necessary response to the problems brought by international business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Sterling Problem and the Six. London:Chatham House/PEP, 1967.
In this small pamphlet Strange analyses the twin roles of sterling in the international economy - that of reserve currency and of vehicle currency (in which transactions are carried out), in a precursor to her typology of currencies in Sterling and British Policy (1971). She argues that while the City has benefited from the expansion of the ‘Euro-currency’ markets, in its ‘middleman’ role, this has led to a number of problems for sterling both in the wider context of the international economy and, more specifically, the context of the emerging European Community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Question</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_question/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_question/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Sterling Question.&amp;rdquo; In Britain and the Common Market edited by Anthony Moncrieff, 43-50. London, BBC, 1967.
In this text of a radio talk first broadcast on 19th February 1967, Strange summarises the arguments she made in The Sterling Problem and the Six (1967). Discussing the links between Britain and the European Community, she examines the international position of sterling in a time of monetary crisis. Noting both the lack of reserves held by the British government and Britain’s extra-European financial commitments, Strange argues that de Gaulle may be correct in thinking it is impossible for Britain to act ‘like good Europeans’.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
