<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Europe on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Europe on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New World of Debt</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_new_world_of_debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_new_world_of_debt/</guid>
      <description>An extract from (1998f) in which Strange focuses on the problems of international indebtedness in the 1990s including the Mexican, Brazilian and Asian debt crises and a discussion of central and Eastern European issues. She suggests that the key problem has not been the indebtedness of poor states itself, but the sorts of credit historically extended and the timidity of the solutions to the problems that have arisen. Noting the missed opportunity of a new Marshall Plan for Eastern Europe, she notes not only is there little agreement on the causes of problems but also little consensus about ‘what is to be done’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</guid>
      <description>Building on the argument of Robert Reich that the location of economic activity (in a state) was more important for its competitiveness than the ownership of companies (whose production was carried out abroad), Strange suggests that unless European policy recognises the importance of society based competitiveness rather than firm-based competitiveness, Europe’s economic problems cannot be overcome. Strange then discusses European trade policy (which needs to be more predictable), investment policy (which should be more open), European Monetary Union (which while stabilising may have little effect on inward investment from non-European investors), and welfare issues (which need to continue to cushion technological-unemployment).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Expieriences on the Asian Mainland</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</guid>
      <description>This volume collects together papers presented at a conference organised by Strange at the EUI on 2-4th May 1996. Strange herself only contributed an introduction outlining the papers in the volume and discussing the organisational background to the conference. Strange argues that comparative politics scholars and international business academics need to ‘build bridges’ between the two disciplines to better understand the interaction between states and firms. Additionally Strange wanted the conference to bring together European and Japanese academics to discuss the relationship between firms and states in Asia’s economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Business in Japan. A Policy Cross-roads?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_business_in_japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_business_in_japan/</guid>
      <description>Contrasting European and American proposals for the perceived difficulty of setting up foreign owned subsidiaries in Japan, Strange argues that this is a central issue for any nascent European foreign policy initiative. She argues that it may now be beyond any nationally elected government (even in the US.) to re-impose its hegemonic intent on other states. But some co-ordinated pressure from Japanese and European policy bodies may support the reintroduction into global politics of a more interdependent (and less free-market) approach to commercial and financial diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</guid>
      <description>Strange proposes a four element theoretical framework for international currencies in the international political economy: Neutral currencies; Top currencies; Master Currencies; and Negotiated currencies, where each category exhibits certain economic and political characteristics. A currency may display more than one set of characteristics but will belong predominantly to one category. She then goes on to discuss the development of the international political economy in light of the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</guid>
      <description>In this small pamphlet Strange analyses the twin roles of sterling in the international economy - that of reserve currency and of vehicle currency (in which transactions are carried out), in a precursor to her typology of currencies in (1971c). She argues that while the City has benefited from the expansion of the ‘Euro-currency’ markets, in its ‘middleman’ role, this has led to a number of problems for sterling both in the wider context of the international economy and, more specifically, the context of the emerging European Community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
