<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Political Economy on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/international-political-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Political Economy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/international-political-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system’s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: Beyond Economies and International Relations</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ipe_beyond_economies_and_international_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ipe_beyond_economies_and_international_relations/</guid>
      <description>This is slightly revised version of (1995e).
Economies et Sociétés. Volume: 34 Issue: 4. Pages 3-24</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New World of Debt</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_new_world_of_debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_new_world_of_debt/</guid>
      <description>An extract from (1998f) in which Strange focuses on the problems of international indebtedness in the 1990s including the Mexican, Brazilian and Asian debt crises and a discussion of central and Eastern European issues. She suggests that the key problem has not been the indebtedness of poor states itself, but the sorts of credit historically extended and the timidity of the solutions to the problems that have arisen. Noting the missed opportunity of a new Marshall Plan for Eastern Europe, she notes not only is there little agreement on the causes of problems but also little consensus about ‘what is to be done’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/globaloney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/globaloney/</guid>
      <description>In this review of the influential Paul Hirst and Grahame Thompson Globalisation in Question (Oxford: Polity Press, 1996) alongside two other books arguing a similar position, Strange makes a major intervention in the debate over the ‘myth’ of globalisation. Arguing that the authors (like others) miss the deterritorialisation of commercial power in the global system, Strange allows that there needs to be a corrective to the extreme globalisation thesis of complete transformation, but that a failure to examine what is really happening in the global political economy, while relying on aggregated and out-of-date statistics has led too many political economists to fail to recognise the very real changes in the balance of power between multinational corporations and states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Expieriences on the Asian Mainland</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</guid>
      <description>This volume collects together papers presented at a conference organised by Strange at the EUI on 2-4th May 1996. Strange herself only contributed an introduction outlining the papers in the volume and discussing the organisational background to the conference. Strange argues that comparative politics scholars and international business academics need to ‘build bridges’ between the two disciplines to better understand the interaction between states and firms. Additionally Strange wanted the conference to bring together European and Japanese academics to discuss the relationship between firms and states in Asia’s economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to Chris May </title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a_reply_to_chris_may/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/a_reply_to_chris_may/</guid>
      <description>In Strange’s reply to May’s article (Strange Fruit: Susan Strange’s theory of Structural Power in the International Political Economy Global Society 10, 2 (May 1996): 167 -189), she engages with two criticisms made of her theory of structural power. Firstly she suggests that the knowledge structure itself is not necessarily prior as is suggested it might be considered to be if her process of agenda setting power is regarded as central.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Defective State</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_defective_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_defective_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange argues that while states remain superficially important as major actors within the global system, the underlying power relations have hollowed out their authority. This authority has in some cases flowed ‘upwards’ to international institutions, and in other cases flowed down to markets (and also more localised organisations). These movements have led to an asymmetry of structural authority in the global system. Strange also makes some comments regarding the state-centric nature of the discipline of International Relations and suggests a new research agenda based around her conception of structural power and the importance of non-state actors in the functioning of authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of Politics</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</guid>
      <description>Originally delivered as a lecture at the LSE this article finds Strange explicitly engaging with the notion of globalisation. For Strange globalisation is: the development of products for explicitly global and transnational markets; the decline of barriers and distinctions between national economies; the emergence of at least partial labour mobility in addition to the more recognised capital mobility; and the speeding up of transport and communications. While these trends have changed the balance between authority and markets over outcomes in the international political economy, they have also led to an increasingly globalised but asymmetrical array of structural power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/states_and_markets_1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/states_and_markets_1994/</guid>
      <description>Although subtitled ‘An Introduction&amp;hellip;’ to IPE, this represents the only book length discussion of Strange’s theory of the four dimensions of power in IPE. It is at once an introduction to the subject and a forceful agenda setting exercise for further research. As such, though often appearing on undergraduate course reading lists, this is Strange’s defining book, one about which the rest of her work revolves. Strange discusses her ideas on theory building and methodology as well as the four structures of power in the international political economy: security, finance, production and knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/wake_up_krasner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/wake_up_krasner/</guid>
      <description>Strange offers a criticism of Krasner’s realist position, drawing on her recent work and an understanding of structural power. She also offers brief critiques of political and economic liberalism as being essentially internally inconsistent, before suggesting that it is they rather than the ‘societal’ approaches that are having theoretical problems with recent developments in the international political economy. Realism and liberalism lack the heuristic power of her own (and others) structuralist approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
