<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Report on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Report on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research on International Organisation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, Geoffrey Goodwin. Research on International Organisation (Social Science Research Council Review of Current Research: 2). London: Heinemann Educational, for the Social Sciences Research Council, 1968.
Acting as a rapporteur for the SSRC Advisory Group on International Organisation (chaired by Goodwin), Strange maps out current and future research as well as examining its organisation and administration. Though published two year prior to Strange’s first call for the establishment of International Political Economy, in &amp;lsquo;International economics and international relations: a case of mutual neglect&amp;rsquo; (1970), this report on the discussion of research into international organisation and international relations reveals many themes (from the impact of structure and technology to the importance of international economics) she would develop in her own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Four. Helping Develop Half a World</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/point_four_helping_develop_half_a_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/point_four_helping_develop_half_a_world/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, Point Four. Helping Develop Half a World, Peacefinder Series: 7. London: United Nations, 1950.
Strange comments on the UN deliberations concerning the future of Palestine and highlights the central factor that gave the Zionists an in-built advantage at the assembly. While the Arabs were negotiating in a state that was essentially antipathetic to their struggle, their opposite numbers were surrounded by sympathisers and supporters both within and outside the organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
