<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Institutions on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/international-institutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Institutions on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/international-institutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Shipping and the Developing Countries</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_shipping_and_the_developing_countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_shipping_and_the_developing_countries/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Shipping and the Developing Countries.&amp;rdquo; World Development 4, no. 4 (1976): 241-251.
Focusing on the importance of sea transport for developing countries that need to gain access to other markets (both for imports and their own exports) Strange and Holland examine the political economy of liner conferences by which international shipping capacity is managed. This private management system does not serve the developing states well leading UNCTAD to press for fairer international rules of conduct for international shipping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan.&amp;ldquo;Who Runs World Shipping?&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 346-367.
In the first article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane ‘transnational politics’ approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arab Oil and International Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Arab Oil and International Finance.&amp;rdquo; The Ditchley Journal, 1974.
Essentially a conference report, Strange discusses the meeting held at Ditchley in December 1973 to discuss the financial prospects and problems for industry and government in the world economy, and the inescapable problem of the oil crisis. Discussing the various aspects of monetary order, from balance of payments problems and trade barriers, to financial flows, she argues that at this point too little work had been done to understand the effects and causes of shifts in monetary flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dollar Crisis 1971</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Dollar Crisis 1971.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 48, no. 2 (1972): 191-216.
Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Multilateral Surveilance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveilance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveilance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Meaning of Multilateral Surveilance.&amp;rdquo; In International Organisation: World Politics, Studies in Economic and Social Agencies, edited by Robert W. Cox, 231-247. London: Macmillan, 1969.
In International Organisation: World Politics, Studies in Economic and Social Agencies, edited by Robert W. Cox, 231-247. London: Macmillan, 1969.&amp;quot; excerpt2: &amp;ldquo;Taking the relationship between debtor and creditor countries as her starting point Strange argues that multilateral surveillance is not as draconian as it is presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debts, Defaulters, and Development</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Debts, Defaulters, and Development.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 43, no. 3 (1967): 516-529.
Strange suggests that problems of national debt default have not been solved, merely suppressed by the expansion of credit provision. Developing states dependence on ‘supplier credit’, and frequent rescheduling of other debts will lead to eventual wide-spread default unless action is taken. She suggests that: principles governing international loans should be established; these ‘rules’ should be applied through aid-agencies and other international bodies; technical assistance to finance ministries should be available from multilateral institutions (the World Bank, possibly) to ensure states understand their fiscal position and their options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
