<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Institutions on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/international-institutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Institutions on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/international-institutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Doubtful Handshake: From International to Comparative Political Economy?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_doubtful_handshake_from_international_to_comparative_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_doubtful_handshake_from_international_to_comparative_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Walzenback, G.P.E. &amp;ldquo;The Doubtful Handshake: From International to Comparative Political Economy?&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 391-412. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: International Institutions; Theory; Structural Power, Power
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do International Organisations Never Die?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/why_do_international_organisations_never_die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/why_do_international_organisations_never_die/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Why do International Organisations Never Die?.&amp;rdquo; In Autonomous Policy Making by International Organisations, edited by Bob Reinalda, Bertjan Verbeek, 213-220. London: Routledge, 1998.
In this concluding chapter of a collection of articles drawn from a series of workshops organised under the auspices of the ECPR, Strange reflects on the legacy of The Anatomy of Influence (see &amp;lsquo;‘IMF: Monetary Managers’ [1974]) and suggests that a focus on international organisation remains a largely European enterprise due to the continuing dominance of liberal institutionalism and (neo)Realism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Defective State</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_defective_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_defective_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Defective State.&amp;rdquo; Daedelus 124, no. 2 (1995): 55-74.
Strange argues that while states remain superficially important as major actors within the global system, the underlying power relations have hollowed out their authority. This authority has in some cases flowed &amp;lsquo;upwards&amp;rsquo; to international institutions, and in other cases flowed down to markets (and also more localised organisations). These movements have led to an asymmetry of structural authority in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade.&amp;rdquo; Austrailian Outlook 38, no. 2 (1984): 106-110.
Strange identifies three ‘shaky assumptions’ underlying the call to revive the GATT negotiations, that protectionism was the main cause of the 1930s depression, that the GATT was a necessary condition of post-war recovery, and free trade was ever a widely followed ‘norm’. However, though the alternatives are presented as a hegemonic system run by the US or a multilateral system managed through the GATT, Strange argues that the reality is a cob-web of bi-lateral agreements which accords with many people’s desire to have their own state manage their affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Shipping and the Developing Countries</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_shipping_and_the_developing_countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_shipping_and_the_developing_countries/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, Richard Holland. &amp;ldquo;International Shipping and the Developing Countries.&amp;rdquo; World Development 4, no. 3 (1976): 241-251.
Focusing on the importance of sea transport for developing countries that need to gain access to other markets (both for imports and their own exports) Strange and Holland examine the political economy of liner conferences by which international shipping capacity is managed. This private management system does not serve the developing states well leading UNCTAD to press for fairer international rules of conduct for international shipping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Who Runs World Shipping?.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 346-367.
Published alongside &amp;lsquo;The Study of Transnational Relations?&amp;rsquo; (1976). Based on the theory developed in that article, Strange&amp;rsquo;s sectoral analysis (of world shipping), which carries some material forward from &amp;lsquo;International shipping and the developing countries&amp;rsquo; (with Richard Holland, 1976).
Keywords: Theory; Trade; International Institutions; Transportation; International Development
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arab Oil and International Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Arab Oil and International Finance.&amp;rdquo; The Ditchley Journal 1 (1974).
Essentially a conference report, Strange discusses the meeting held at Ditchley in December 1973 to discuss the financial prospects and problems for industry and government in the world economy, and the inescapable problem of the oil crisis. Discussing the various aspects of monetary order, from balance of payments problems and trade barriers, to financial flows, she argues that at this point too little work had been done to understand the effects and causes of shifts in monetary flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dollar Crisis 1971</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Dollar Crisis 1971.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 48, no. 2 (1972): 191-216.
Using the &amp;lsquo;Dollar Crisis&amp;rsquo; as a way of examining the problems which beset academic approaches to international relations Strange suggests that: foreign policy analysis seems unable to recognise the centrality of economic problems for states; (Neo)functionalism is far too optimistic concerning the possibility of international integration; much &amp;lsquo;abstract theorising&amp;rsquo;, such as game theory, seems to have no connection with what is happening in the international system; and international economics has diverted attention away from international political problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Multilateral Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Meaning of Multilateral Surveillance.&amp;rdquo; In International Organisation: World Politics: Studies in Economic and Social Agencies, edited by Robert W. Cox, 231-247. London: Macmillan, 1969.
Taking the relationship between debtor and creditor countries as her starting point Strange argues that multilateral surveillance is not as draconian as it is presented. She notes that military expenditure is seldom included in the requests for debtor country adjustments. Despite the international economic organisations’ role, states were still able to manipulate their creditors through political pressures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debts, Defaulters, and Development</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Debts, Defaulters, and Development.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 43, no. 3 (1967): 516-529.
Strange suggests that problems of national debt default have not been solved, merely suppressed by the expansion of credit provision. Developing states dependence on &amp;lsquo;supplier credit&amp;rsquo;, and frequent rescheduling of other debts will lead to eventual wide-spread default unless action is taken. She suggests that: principles governing international loans should be established; these &amp;lsquo;rules&amp;rsquo; should be applied through aid-agencies and other international bodies; technical assistance to finance ministries should be available from multilateral institutions (the World Bank, possibly) to ensure states understand their fiscal position and their options.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
