<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: James Barber on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-james-barber/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: James Barber on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-james-barber/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Business and the EEC</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</guid>
      <description>Stange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Business and the EEC.&amp;rdquo; In The Eruopean Economic Community, edited by James Barber, 82-95. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1974.
Strange discusses the relationship between international business and the EEC by briefly examining three partly overlapping assertions: that the main achievements of the EEC have resulted not from the community’s own work but from the impact of international business; that international business is a ‘Trojan horse’ for American influence and interest in Europe; and that the EEC is a necessary response to the problems brought by international business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation_and_the_national_interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation_and_the_national_interest/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest.&amp;rdquo; In Decision Making in Britain, edited by James Barber, 165-178. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1972.
In one of her earliest pieces to deal directly with multinational companies or corporations Strange argues that an analysis of the companies not only leads to both domestic and foreign policy making but also into the realm of international (regulatory) policy making. Much of the text is taken up with a discussion of the likely conflicts in interest between governments and corporations with multinational operations (as she prefers to term them).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
