<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Andy Knight on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-andy-knight/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Andy Knight on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-andy-knight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</guid>
      <description>Strange criticises Bergsten’s exaggeration of US decline in hegemonic power and absolution of the USA of bearing prime responsibility for the deteriorating economic situation. Indeed much of her work in the 1980s revolved round the dual need to recognise US responsibility for global economic crises, and the problem of such a responsibility being denied by the US (both policy makers and academics).
International Journal. Volume: 38 Issue: 2. Pages 355-356</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money/</guid>
      <description>After a survey of current modes of thought, both academic and practitioner, Strange concludes that while much analysis can usefully illuminate the mechanisms of the global monetary system, there is little attempt ally this to a consideration how the system links up with and effects the values of and outcomes in a globalised society. She wants work on the international monetary system to go beyond a mere mechanical explanation and to move towards a more political analysis (which would also include an assessment of the impact of technology on global finance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</guid>
      <description>Here Strange commits to print an early version of the structure of power theory which she would develop over the next thirteen years. In this manifestation, there are three dimensions of power in the international political economy - security, ‘ideology’ and economic. There is more concern, though, with a location of four level or stages at which economic power is apparent - the world market structure; international co-operative relations; national/governmental control of markets; and the operational level of the economic transactions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
