<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Nicholas X. Rizopoulo on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-nicholas-x.-rizopoulo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Nicholas X. Rizopoulo on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-nicholas-x.-rizopoulo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Europe 1992 - Some Personal Observations</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/europe_1992-some_personal_observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/europe_1992-some_personal_observations/</guid>
      <description>Working Paper:In this record of a personal address, Strange suggests the 1992 project served both the European collective interest (in the face of Asian and American competition) and the national interests of the major European states (France and Germany), though as notes Britain’s position is less clear cut. Post 1992 Strange suggests the democratic deficit (in European institutions), finance (the European Central Bank, co-ordination of banking regulations and the single currency), defence (and public procurement), reciprocity in international trade, and R&amp;amp;D are areas which are likely to be the most important for governments to attend to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Changes: American Foreign Policy in a World Transformed: The Name of the Game</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_name_of_the_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_name_of_the_game/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Strange develops an argument that the competition for territory in international relations has been superseded by the competition for world market shares. This decline in the importance in territory has engendered among other things an international business civilisation that is based on firms and enterprises rather than nationality. However this seems to be different from the transnational empire she suggests in (1989b). This central change in the international political economy, has led to a diffusion of state power, but still leaves the US the most powerful actor in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
