<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Open University on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-open-university/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Open University on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/publisher-open-university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implimentation: The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account. This short piece illustrates her argument about the applicability of her IPE approach, but does not include her more usual extended criticism of previous analyses from International Relations or International Economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest: The Study of International Affairs: Essays in Honour of Kenneth Younger: International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: In one of her earliest pieces to deal directly with multinational companies or corporations Strange argues that an analysis of the companies not only leads to both domestic and foreign policy making but also into the realm of international (regulatory) policy making. Much of the text is taken up with a discussion of the likely conflicts in interest between governments and corporations with multinational operations (as she prefers to term them).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
