<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Robert W. Cox on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-robert-w.-cox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Robert W. Cox on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-robert-w.-cox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New Realism: Perspectives on Multilateralism and World Order: Territory, State, Authority and Economy: A New Realist Ontology of Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/territory_state_authority_and_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/territory_state_authority_and_economy/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Strange argues that the global economy is in the midst of a transition; the close incidence of political authority, economic activity and geographical territory no longer holds. This has been caused by two main groups of factors: firstly changes derived from science and technology; and secondly structural changes within the global finance structure. Authority has shifted, or is shifting, from states to other actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of Influence: Decision Making in International Organisation - IMF: Monetary Managers</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: This is a detailed case study of the IMF, which Strange uses to back up her warning that there can be no justification for an analytical division between the economic and the political. She argues that the IMF can only be understood within its international political context, and suggests that any institutional changes will reflect the continuing development of the international economy. It is important to recognise that the US is its chief initiator of policy and influence, both directly through its constitutionally predominant position in the organisation and through its wider impact on the international environment in which the IMF operates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Organisation: World Politics, Studies in Economic: The Meaning of Multilateral Surveilance</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveilance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveilance/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Taking the relationship between debtor and creditor countries as her starting point Strange argues that multilateral surveillance is not as draconian as it is presented. She notes that military expenditure is seldom included in the requests for debtor country adjustments. Despite the international economic organisations’ role, states were still able to manipulate their creditors through political pressures. Interestingly, Strange notes with great prescience that while at the time states could still play this role, with the continuing internationalisation of money markets (and the emergent technologies that made such developments possible), this would in the future present a strategic problem for states’ governments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
