<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Robert W. Cox on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-robert-w.-cox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Robert W. Cox on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-robert-w.-cox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Territory, State, Authority and Economy: A New Realist Ontology of Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/territory_state_authority_and_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/territory_state_authority_and_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Territory, State, Authority and Economy: A New Realist Ontology of Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; In The New Realism: Perspectives on Multilateralism and World Order, edited by Robert W. Cox, 3-19. Basingstoke: Macmillan Press/United Nations University Press, 1997.
Strange argues that the global economy is in the midst of a transition; the close incidence of political authority, economic activity and geographical territory no longer holds. This has been caused by two main groups of factors: firstly changes derived from science and technology; and secondly structural changes within the global finance structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Take six eggs&#39;: theory, finance, and the real economy in the work of Susan Strange</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/take_six_eggs_theory_finance_and_the_real_economy_in_the_work_of_susan_strange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/take_six_eggs_theory_finance_and_the_real_economy_in_the_work_of_susan_strange/</guid>
      <description>Robert W. Cox. In Approaches to World Order. Robert W. Cox, Timothy J. Sinclair, editors. 174-187. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1992. Keywords: Theory; Finance Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMF: Monetary Managers</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;IMF: Monetary Managers.&amp;rdquo; In The Anatomy of Influence: Decision Making in International Organisation, edited by Robert W. Cox and Harold K. Jacobson, 263-297. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1974.
This is a detailed case study of the IMF, which Strange uses to back up her warning that there can be no justification for an analytical division between the economic and the political. She argues that the IMF can only be understood within its international political context, and suggests that any institutional changes will reflect the continuing development of the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Multilateral Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Meaning of Multilateral Surveillance.&amp;rdquo; In International Organisation: World Politics: Studies in Economic and Social Agencies, edited by Robert W. Cox, 231-247. London: Macmillan, 1969.
Taking the relationship between debtor and creditor countries as her starting point Strange argues that multilateral surveillance is not as draconian as it is presented. She notes that military expenditure is seldom included in the requests for debtor country adjustments. Despite the international economic organisations’ role, states were still able to manipulate their creditors through political pressures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
