<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structural Power on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/structural-power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structural Power on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/tags/structural-power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of Politics</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</guid>
      <description>Originally delivered as a lecture at the LSE this article finds Strange explicitly engaging with the notion of globalisation. For Strange globalisation is: the development of products for explicitly global and transnational markets; the decline of barriers and distinctions between national economies; the emergence of at least partial labour mobility in addition to the more recognised capital mobility; and the speeding up of transport and communications. While these trends have changed the balance between authority and markets over outcomes in the international political economy, they have also led to an increasingly globalised but asymmetrical array of structural power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>In this short review of P.J. Cain and A.G. Hopkins British Imperialism (2 vols) (London: Longman 1993), Strange again emphasises the structural characteristics of US power in the global system and suggest that Britain’s structural power was more long lasting than is sometimes presumed, with clear implications for the continuing power of the US in the global economy.
Review of International Studies. Volume: 20 Issue: 4. Pages 407-410</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_information_and_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/finance_information_and_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange discusses the difference between American structural power and Japanese relational power in the financial structure. In addition she discusses the impact of communications technology changes on the operation of international financial markets, which represents an illuminating case study of how two structures interact with each other to bring about changes in the international political economy, in this case the financial and knowledge structures. In addition Strange notes that at least part of American structural power is derived from the privileged position of the ‘American-English’ language in the knowledge structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: Reuiniting Three Fields of Intellectual Endeavour</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ipe_reuiniting_three_fields_of_intellectual_endeavour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ipe_reuiniting_three_fields_of_intellectual_endeavour/</guid>
      <description>Strange uses the work she was co-ordinating with John Stopford, later published as (Strange and Stopford 1991) to launch a critique of the separation of International Relations, International Economics and the research carried out in business schools. She argues that her approach, foregrounding structural power, requires analysis from all three directions and therefore there needs to be much better contact and co-operation between the three fields. Here Strange is again expressing her frustration, which first surfaced in (1970a) and continued to produce recommendations for the breaking down of disciplinary boundaries throughout her subsequent career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on International Organisation</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</guid>
      <description>Acting as a rapporteur for the SSRC Advisory Group on International Organisation (chaired by Goodwin), Strange maps out current and future research as well as examining its organisation and administration. Though published two year prior to Strange’s first call for the establishment of International Political Economy (1970a), this report on the discussion of research into international organisation and international relations reveals many themes (from the impact of structure and technology to the importance of international economics) she would develop in her own work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
