<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Loukas Tsoukalis on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-loukas-tsoukalis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Loukas Tsoukalis on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-loukas-tsoukalis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Europe, America and the World Economy: Politics, Trade and Money</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/politics_trade_and_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/politics_trade_and_money/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Strange identifies two main obstructions to a constructive dialogue between the United States and Europe over international trade: America’s lack of interest in maintaining a steady provision of credit to the interdependent international system; and Europe’s inability to take responsibility for its own defence and security, and therefore reducing its dependence on America. This leads Strange to conclude that the U.S. has abused rather than lost its power in the international economy, refusing to allow the separation the international risks from domestic bank activities in developing countries, taking no notice of the Brandt’s commissions call for a independent multilateral financial institution, and not taking the role of international lender of last resort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of International Money: In Search of a New Order: Interpretations of a Decade</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/interpretations_of_a_decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/interpretations_of_a_decade/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: After reiterating her criticism of over-specialisation in the study of international economic relations, Strange goes on to discuss the shortcomings of a large spectrum of perspectives on economic development. The bulk of this article subsequently appeared as chapter three (1986f).
Pages: 1-43</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
