<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal: Review of International Studies on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/journal-review-of-international-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal: Review of International Studies on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/journal-review-of-international-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Currency Internationalisation: The Case of the RMB</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article
Volume 43, Issue 3 Pages 765-787</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange, Academic Interntaional Relations and the Study of International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_academic_interntaional_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_academic_interntaional_relations/</guid>
      <description>Journal: Overview of Strange&amp;rsquo;s Work
Volume 5, Issue 2 Pages: 280-289</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system’s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure Sytem</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_sytem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_sytem/</guid>
      <description>Journal: In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system’s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_and_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>In this short review of P.J. Cain and A.G. Hopkins British Imperialism (2 vols) (London: Longman 1993), Strange again emphasises the structural characteristics of US power in the global system and suggest that Britain’s structural power was more long lasting than is sometimes presumed, with clear implications for the continuing power of the US in the global economy.
Review of International Studies. Volume: 20 Issue: 4. Pages 407-410</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_information_and_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_information_and_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange discusses the difference between American structural power and Japanese relational power in the financial structure. In addition she discusses the impact of communications technology changes on the operation of international financial markets, which represents an illuminating case study of how two structures interact with each other to bring about changes in the international political economy, in this case the financial and knowledge structures. In addition Strange notes that at least part of American structural power is derived from the privileged position of the ‘American-English’ language in the knowledge structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
