<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publisher: Lynne Rienner Publishers on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-lynne-rienner-publishers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publisher: Lynne Rienner Publishers on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:23 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/publisher-lynne-rienner-publishers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Caught up in the Madness? State Power and Transnational Organized Crime in the Work of Susan Strange</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/caught_up_in_the_madness_state_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/caught_up_in_the_madness_state_power/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article:
Volume 28, Issue 4 Pages 473-490</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcending the State-Global Divide: A Neostructuralist Agenda in International Relations: Foreword</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/foreword/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/foreword/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: This is merely a brief supportive introduction to a collection of papers which were developed from a seminar organised by Strange at the European University Institute, Florence in May 1990.
Pages: vii - viii</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New International Political Economy (International Political Economy Year Book No.6: An Eclectic Approach</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/an_eclectic_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/an_eclectic_approach/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter: Strange reiterates the structural dimensions of power from (1988e) and then goes on to develop this further by adding three conditioning factors that influence the structural elements of power - these are states, markets and technology. Essentially the new element here is the dynamic of technology. Strange makes the contribution of the technological dynamic to the four structures more explicit in this article than previously. She then concludes by again stressing the need for interdisciplinary understanding of IPE and how this should influence the teaching of the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
