<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asia on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/asia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asia on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/asia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Expieriences on the Asian Mainland</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</guid>
      <description>This volume collects together papers presented at a conference organised by Strange at the EUI on 2-4th May 1996. Strange herself only contributed an introduction outlining the papers in the volume and discussing the organisational background to the conference. Strange argues that comparative politics scholars and international business academics need to ‘build bridges’ between the two disciplines to better understand the interaction between states and firms. Additionally Strange wanted the conference to bring together European and Japanese academics to discuss the relationship between firms and states in Asia’s economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</guid>
      <description>A self-avowedly part international relations - part international business management work which in keeping with Strange’s views discusses the interdependence between politics and economics without fore-grounding one at the expense of the other. The book builds on Strange’s theory of power and links it through three national studies (Brazil, Malaysia, Kenya) to a consideration of the effect of structural change in the international political economy on the role of TNCs in international economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
