<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Brian Barry on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-brian-barry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Brian Barry on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/contributors/editor-brian-barry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Free Movement. Ethical Issues in Transnational Migration of People and Money: Ethics and the Movement of Money: Realist Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ethics_and_the_movement_of_money_realist_approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/ethics_and_the_movement_of_money_realist_approaches/</guid>
      <description>Book Chapter:Identifying herself as a Realist, Strange notes that there is not one easily defined Realist perspective on the ethics of international monetary flows. Focusing on the continued existence and relative power of states she explores the problems these flows cause for states and stability in the international system overall. Here she examines international debt, free trade and protectionism, the transfer of profits, and but-outs or take-overs. Strange still seems to have some confidence that the state may play a useful regulatory and political role in economic affairs, a position she would move away from by the end of her career in (1995a) and (1996c) and elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traitors, Double Agents or Rescuing Knights</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/traitors_double_agents_or_rescuing_knights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/traitors_double_agents_or_rescuing_knights/</guid>
      <description>Working Paper: In this, her final piece of writing, Strange reprise arguments from (Strange and Stopford 1991) and (1996c) to argue that the disciplines of International Relations and International Economics fail to understand contemporary globalisation. Where IR scholars have missed the structural shifts in the global system away from state-centric power with the emergence of new non-state authority, economists have missed the role of the state in promoting these changes, and misunderstand the working of global markets, discounting, or not even recognising the political relations between firms, what Strange refers to as the new diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
