<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Randall Germain on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/contributors/randall-germain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Randall Germain on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/contributors/randall-germain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflection I</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/reflection_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/reflection_i/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;Reflection I.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century, edited by Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, 81-89. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Randall Germain reflects on the chapters by Blayne Haggart, and Sara Bannerman and Angela Orasch.
Keywords: Knowledge
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Currency Internationalisation: The Case of the RMB</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency_internationalisation_the_case_of_the_rmb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_political_economy_of_currency_internationalisation_the_case_of_the_rmb/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall, Herman Mark Schwartz. &amp;ldquo;The Political Economy of Currency Internationalisation: The Case of the RMB.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Studies 43, no. 3 (2017): 765-787.
The rise of China has sparked a debate about the economic and political consequences for the global economy of the internationalisation of the renminbi. We argue that the dominant focus of this literature – primarily the external conditions and requirements for a national currency to become an international currency – misspecifies the connections between the international and domestic requirements for currency internationalisation, as well as the potential to become the dominant international reserve currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of IPE</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;Susan Strange and the Future of IPE.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 19-36. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explains how contributors use Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of international political economy (IPE). Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s life and times spanned the most tumultuous decades of the twentieth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Global Transformation: Susan Strange, E.H. Carr and the Dynamics of Structural Change</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_political_economy_of_global_transformation_susan_strange_eh_carr_and_the_dynamics_of_structural_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_political_economy_of_global_transformation_susan_strange_eh_carr_and_the_dynamics_of_structural_change/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;The Political Economy of Global Transformation: Susan Strange, E.H. Carr and the Dynamics of Structural Change.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 183-200. London: Routledge, 2016.
Do international relations precede or follow (logically) fundamental social relations? There can be no doubt that they follow. Any organic innovation in the social structure, through its technical–military expressions, modifies organically absolute and relative relations in the international field too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
