<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal: International SAIS Review on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/journal-international-sais-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal: International SAIS Review on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/journal-international-sais-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bondage of Liberal Economics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_bondage_of_liberal_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_bondage_of_liberal_economics/</guid>
      <description>Here Strange returns again to the inadequacy of economics in its analysis of international trade, made in (1955b) and (1970b), and elsewhere. Noting the contradictions between economic models of international trade and what was actually happening in the international economy, Strange argues economists have failed to appreciate that trade is only a secondary international structure. This leads her to briefly lay out the argument that would be developed at more length in (1988e).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Credit Crisis: A European View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_credit_crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_credit_crisis/</guid>
      <description>Strange here uses the term crisis, but notes that the implication that some sort of solution is imminent is less than certain. She suggests that the world economic crisis has three interrelated aspects: unemployment, ‘flagging trade’, and unstable money. As in (1979a) she shows some scepticism to the arguments that demonise protectionism, and suggests this is an essentially ideological position that would not repay global implementation. After briefly rehearsing the global financial history of the previous decade, Strange suggests that financial regulation which in the last analysis is dependent on certain sovereign states, can never be disinterested.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
