<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Governance on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/global-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Global Governance on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/global-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</guid>
      <description>Sell, Susan K. &amp;ldquo;Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 39-50. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter argues that Strange&amp;rsquo;s work is of enduring significance because it helps us forge a practical understanding of critical global problems. Global environmental problems, global financial crises, and global inequalities are three of the small set of global problems regularly pointed to by promoters of the new global public policy degree programs established over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return of the State? The G20, the Financial Crisis and Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/return_of_the_state_the_g20_the_financial_crisis_and_power_in_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/return_of_the_state_the_g20_the_financial_crisis_and_power_in_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Nordberg, Donald. &amp;ldquo;Return of the State? The G20, the Financial Crisis and Power in the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; Review of Political Economy 24, no. 2 (2012): 289-302.
The Group of Twenty and the new world order it is meant to signify have prompted a wave of triumphalism around the world from those who, like French President Nicolas Sarkozy, bemoan the influences of ‘Anglo-Saxon capitalism’ and from neo-Marxists, who view the economic crisis as a harbinger of the resurgence of states over markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Money and the Decline of State Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/global_money_and_the_decline_of_state_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/global_money_and_the_decline_of_state_power/</guid>
      <description>Underhill, Geoffrey R.D. &amp;ldquo;Global Money and the Decline of State Power.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 115-135. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Global governance; Globalization; Money and finance; Authority; Markets; States
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money and Power in World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/money_and_power_in_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/money_and_power_in_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>Cohen, Benjam. In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 91-114. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Global governance; Money and Finance
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional Blocks and International Relations: Economic Groupings or Political Hegemons?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/regional_blocks_and_international_relations_economic_groupings_or_political_hegemons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/regional_blocks_and_international_relations_economic_groupings_or_political_hegemons/</guid>
      <description>Tovias, Alfred. &amp;ldquo;Regional Blocks and International Relations: Economic Groupings or Political Hegemons?.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 321-342. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Global governance; Regionalism; International Relations
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dynamics of Paralysis: Japan in the Global Era</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_dynamics_of_paralysis_japan_in_the_global_era/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_dynamics_of_paralysis_japan_in_the_global_era/</guid>
      <description>Lehmann, Jean-Pierre. &amp;ldquo;The Dynamics of Paralysis: Japan In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 295-320. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Global governance; Japan
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange. &amp;ldquo;The Westfailure System.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Studies 25, no. 3 (1999): 345-354.
In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Global Capitalism: or Will Divergence Persist Forever</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_future_of_global_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_future_of_global_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Future of Global Capitalism: or Will Divergence Persist Forever.&amp;rdquo; In The Political Economy of Modern Capitalism: Capping Convergence and Diversity, edited by Colin Crouch, Wolfgang Streeck, 182-191. London: Sage, 1997.
In this response to the contents of the volume in which it appears, Strange distances herself from comparative political economists studying different forms of national capitalism, and argues for a global perception of a more systemic view of capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem or the Solution? Capitalism and the State System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_problem_or_the_solution_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_problem_or_the_solution_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Problem or the Solution? Capitalism and the State System.&amp;rdquo; In Innovation and Transformation in International Studies, edited by Stephen Gill, James H. Mittelman, 236-247. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1997.
Again Strange criticises International Relations for not focusing on the systemic problems, not least of all environmental and financial issues which a concern for inter-state relations misses. Thus International Political Economy is open to approaches from political geography, historical sociology and elsewhere that have not been fixated on the relations between states as the key causal factor in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm.&amp;rdquo; International Studies Quality 39, no. 3 (1995): 289-295.
After briefly discussing the history of the ISA, Strange points out that it is the International Studies Association, despite the current domination of International Relations. Once again Strange argues for the constructive engagement with other discipline interested in the international system, from political geographers to business economists. Strange points to the relative decline of state-state violence relative to civil and local violence, the increasing interest in the environment, and the dangers stemming from the financial markets, as reasons for widening the ISA&amp;rsquo;s implicit agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
