<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Governance on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/global-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Global Governance on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/global-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</guid>
      <description>Sell, Susan K. &amp;ldquo;Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. Randall Germain, editor. 39-50. London: Routledge 2016.
This chapter argues that Strange&amp;rsquo;s work is of enduring significance because it helps us forge a practical understanding of critical global problems. Global environmental problems, global financial crises, and global inequalities are three of the small set of global problems regularly pointed to by promoters of the new global public policy degree programs established over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Money and the Decline of State Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/global_money_and_the_decline_of_state_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/global_money_and_the_decline_of_state_power/</guid>
      <description>Underhill, Geoffrey R.D. &amp;ldquo;Global Money and the Decline of State Power.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy. Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, editors. 115-135. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Global governance; Globalization; Money and finance; Authority; Markets; States
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange. &amp;ldquo;The Westfailure System.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Studies 25, no. 3 (1999): 345-354.
In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system&amp;rsquo;s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Global Capitalism: or Will Divergence Persist Forever</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_future_of_global_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_future_of_global_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Future of Global Capitalism: or Will Divergence Persist Forever.&amp;rdquo; In The Political Economy of Modern Capitalism. Capping Convergence and Diversity, Colin Crouch, Wolfgang Streeck, editors. 182-191. London: Sage, 1997.
In this response to the contents of the volume in which it appears, Strange distances herself from comparative political economists studying different forms of national capitalism, and argues for a global perception of a more systemic view of capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of the Solution? Capitalism and the State System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_problem_of_the_solution_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_problem_of_the_solution_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Problem of the Solution? Capitalism and the State System.&amp;rdquo; In Innovation and Transformation in International Studies, Stephen Gill, James H. Mittelman, editors. 236-247. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1997.
Again Strange criticises International Relations for not focusing on the systemic problems, not least of all environmental and financial issues which a concern for inter-state relations misses. Thus International Political Economy is open to approaches from political geography, historical sociology and elsewhere that have not been fixated on the relations between states as the key causal factor in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/1995_presidential_address_isa_as_a_microcosm/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;1995 Presidential Address: ISA as a Microcosm.&amp;rdquo; International Studies Quality 39, no. 3 (1995): 289-295.
After briefly discussing the history of the ISA, Strange points out that it is the International Studies Association, despite the current domination of International Relations. Once again Strange argues for the constructive engagement with other discipline interested in the international system, from political geographers to business economists. Strange points to the relative decline of state-state violence relative to civil and local violence, the increasing interest in the environment, and the dangers stemming from the financial markets, as reasons for widening the ISA&amp;rsquo;s implicit agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power Gap: Member States and the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_power_gap_member_states_and_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_power_gap_member_states_and_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Power Gap: Member States and the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Economic Policy Making and the European Union, Frank Brouwer, Valerio Linter, Mike Newman, editors. 19-26. London: Federal Trust, 1994.
Strange criticises arguments that suggest the European Union is a sui generis political institution. She criticises such claims, self avowedly, not from a lengthy engagement with European political analysis, but from a more global concern with political economy. She suggests that except for the Commission there is little to distinguish the EU from some other intergovernmental organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/wake_up_krasner_the_world_has_changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/wake_up_krasner_the_world_has_changed/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed.&amp;rdquo; Review of International Political Economy 1, no. 2 (1994): 209-219.
Strange offers a criticism of Krasner&amp;rsquo;s realist position, drawing on her recent work and an understanding of structural power. She also offers brief critiques of political and economic liberalism as being essentially internally inconsistent, before suggesting that it is they rather than the &amp;lsquo;societal&amp;rsquo; approaches that are having theoretical problems with recent developments in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transformation of the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_transformation_of_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_transformation_of_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Transformation of the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Mapping the Unknown: Towards a New World Order (Yearbook of the Swedish Institute for International Affairs 1992-1993), Lidija Babic, Bo Huldt, editors. 43-49. London: Hurst and Co., 1993.
In this short article Strange reviews many of the same arguments that have been featured above. However, here she argues that the transformation of the world economy is not so much the product of state/firm interactions, rather it is firms that are playing (and will continue to play) the more important role in structural change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traitors, Double Agents or Rescuing Knights</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/traitors_double_agents_or_rescuing_knights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/traitors_double_agents_or_rescuing_knights/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Europe 1992 - Some Personal Observations (SAIIA occasional paper). [Working Paper for] Table Ronde No. 4 ‘Les Individus dans la Politique Internatioanle’ Association Française de Science Politique, Quatrième Congrès, 1992.
In this working paper Strange links her approach laid out in States and Markets (1988) and links it to the research she had recently published on the role of firms in the global system Rival States, Rival Firms (with John M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
