<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foundational Work on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/foundational-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foundational Work on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/foundational-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Retreat of the State: State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state_state_diffusion_of_power_in_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state_state_diffusion_of_power_in_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Retreat of the State: State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1996.
In what might effectively be regarded as the third part of a trilogy, together with States and Markets (1988) and Rival States, Rival Firms (with John M. Stopford, 1991), Strange examines states&#39; transition towards the sidelines of global political economic relations. Though in the past authority might have been state based, now she argues it is more often based on non-state abilities to bring about (or structure) outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets, 2nd edition</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/states_and_markets_2nd_ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/states_and_markets_2nd_ed/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. States and Markets, 2nd edition. London: Printer Publisdhers, 1994.
There are no major differences between this and the first edition.
Keywords: Foundational Work; Political Economy; Structural Power, Power; Theory; Authority vs Markets
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rival States, Rival Firms: Competition for World Market Shares</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, John M. Stopford, with John S. Henley. Rival States, Rival Firms: Competition for World Market Shares. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1991.
A self-avowedly part international relations - part international business management work which in keeping with Strange&amp;rsquo;s views discusses the interdependence between politics and economics without fore-grounding one at the expense of the other. The book builds on Strange&amp;rsquo;s theory of power and links it through three national studies (Brazil, Malaysia, Kenya) to a consideration of the effect of structural change in the international political economy on the role of TNCs in international economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/states_and_markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/states_and_markets/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. States and Markets. London: Pinter Publishers, 1988.
Although subtitled &amp;lsquo;An Introduction&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; to IPE, this represents the only book length discussion of Strange&amp;rsquo;s theory of the four dimensions of power in IPE. It is at once an introduction to the subject and a forceful agenda setting exercise for further research. As such, though often appearing on undergraduate course reading lists, this is Strange&amp;rsquo;s defining book, one about which the rest of her work revolves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, &amp;ldquo;The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony.&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 41, no. 4 (1987): 551-574.
Strange&amp;rsquo;s classic attack of the &amp;lsquo;declinist school&amp;rsquo; in international relations. Once she has discussed the more &amp;lsquo;sociological&amp;rsquo; reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casino Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/casino_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/casino_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Casino Capitalism. Oxford: Blackwell Publishers, 1986.
Strange argues that uncertainty and risk in the financial sector/structure have provoked major economic disturbances in the last twenty or so years. This work represents a detailed sectoral history and analysis which argues against many of the proposed solutions to the international economic crisis she identifies. Strange argues that the United States must once again take up the leadership role (which it enjoys by virtue of economic preponderance) and more radically suggests that in the future financial regulation of credit creating agencies should not be a territorially based jurisdiction, but based on the currencies themselves wherever the credit transactions take place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis.&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1982): 479-496.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_economics_and_international_relations_a_case_of_mutual_neglect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_economics_and_international_relations_a_case_of_mutual_neglect/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 46, no. 2 (1970): 304-315.
Strange’s first call for the development of International Political Economy as a separate discipline. She identifies a major void between the academic study of international relations and the study of international economics. The failure to fill this void will result in a loss of relevance for the subjects and an inability to deal with the major problems that beset the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
