<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foundational Work on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/foundational-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foundational Work on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/foundational-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>In The persistent myth of lost hegemony International Organization 41,no.4(Autumn),551-574.197.
Strange’s classic attack of the ‘declinist school’ in international relations. Once she has discussed the more ‘sociological’ reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE. This exposition closely parallels (though in a brief form) the arguments that appear in States and Markets (1988).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis,&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36 no. 2, (1982): 337-354.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 46, no. 2 (1970): 304-315.
Strange’s first call for the development of International Political Economy as a separate discipline. She identifies a major void between the academic study of international relations and the study of international economics. The failure to fill this void will result in a loss of relevance for the subjects and an inability to deal with the major problems that beset the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
