<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corporations on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/corporations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Corporations on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/corporations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Business and the EEC</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</guid>
      <description>Stange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Business and the EEC.&amp;rdquo; In The Eruopean Economic Community, edited by James Barber, 82-95. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1974.
Strange discusses the relationship between international business and the EEC by briefly examining three partly overlapping assertions: that the main achievements of the EEC have resulted not from the community’s own work but from the impact of international business; that international business is a ‘Trojan horse’ for American influence and interest in Europe; and that the EEC is a necessary response to the problems brought by international business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of : R.J Barber The American Corporation: Its Power, Its Money, Its Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_rj_barber/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_rj_barber/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of : R.J Barber The American Corporation: Its Power, Its Money, Its Politics.&amp;rdquo; International Journal 27, no. 2 (1972): 308-309.
Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
