<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liberalism on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/liberalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Liberalism on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/liberalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/wake_up_krasner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/wake_up_krasner/</guid>
      <description>Strange offers a criticism of Krasner’s realist position, drawing on her recent work and an understanding of structural power. She also offers brief critiques of political and economic liberalism as being essentially internally inconsistent, before suggesting that it is they rather than the ‘societal’ approaches that are having theoretical problems with recent developments in the international political economy. Realism and liberalism lack the heuristic power of her own (and others) structuralist approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 197s style?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>In this article, which is a clear precursor to (Strange and Tooze 1981), Strange discusses the management of surplus capacity in three sectors of the international economy - steel, textiles and shipbuilding, and the recourse to protectionism. She then goes on to discuss the problems this implies for mainstream theories of international economics. She argues that Liberalism, theories of development, and organisational or functionalist theories do not offer satisfactory explanations for the resurgence of tariff barriers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
