<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Japan on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Japan on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>European Business in Japan. A Policy Cross-roads?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_business_in_japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/european_business_in_japan/</guid>
      <description>Contrasting European and American proposals for the perceived difficulty of setting up foreign owned subsidiaries in Japan, Strange argues that this is a central issue for any nascent European foreign policy initiative. She argues that it may now be beyond any nationally elected government (even in the US.) to re-impose its hegemonic intent on other states. But some co-ordinated pressure from Japanese and European policy bodies may support the reintroduction into global politics of a more interdependent (and less free-market) approach to commercial and financial diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance, Information and Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_information_and_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/finance_information_and_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange discusses the difference between American structural power and Japanese relational power in the financial structure. In addition she discusses the impact of communications technology changes on the operation of international financial markets, which represents an illuminating case study of how two structures interact with each other to bring about changes in the international political economy, in this case the financial and knowledge structures. In addition Strange notes that at least part of American structural power is derived from the privileged position of the ‘American-English’ language in the knowledge structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
