<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United States on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/united-states/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United States on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/united-states/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Criticizing US Method and Thought in International Relations: Why a Trans-Atlantic Divide Narrows IR&#39;s Research Subject</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/criticizing_us_method_and_thought_in_international_relations_why_a_trans-atlantic_divide_narrows_irs_research_subject/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/criticizing_us_method_and_thought_in_international_relations_why_a_trans-atlantic_divide_narrows_irs_research_subject/</guid>
      <description>Verbeek, Bertjan. &amp;ldquo;Criticizing US Method and Thought in International Relations: Why a Trans-Atlantic Divide Narrows IR&amp;rsquo;s Research Subject.&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 139-158. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Theory; United States; International Relations
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still an Extraordinary Power, but for How Much Longer? The United States in World Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_but_for_how_much_longer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_but_for_how_much_longer/</guid>
      <description>Helleiner, Eric. &amp;ldquo;Still an Extraordinary Power, but for How Much Longer? The United States In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 251-270. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: Structural Power, Power; Money and Finance; United States
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United States and World Trade: Hegemony by Proxy?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_united_states_and_world_trade_hegemony_by_proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_united_states_and_world_trade_hegemony_by_proxy/</guid>
      <description>Goldstein, Judith. &amp;ldquo;The United States and World Trade: Hegemony by Proxy?&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 349-272. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: United States; Structural Power, Power; Trade
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Fall&#39; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_fall_of_the_united_states/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;Fall&amp;rdquo; of the United States: Peace, Stability, and Legitimacy.&amp;rdquo; In The Fall of Great Powers: Peace, Stability and Legitimacy, edited by Geir Lundestad, 197-211. Oslo and Oxford: Scandinavian University Press and Oxford University Press, 1994.
Once again Strange argues at length that the notion of American decline in the global system is mistaken if examined through her structural perspective. She presents a brief history of the previous fifty years to explore how America&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;fall&amp;rsquo; can be proposed and why this misunderstands power in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_governs_networks_of_power_in_world_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_governs_networks_of_power_in_world_society/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Who Governs? Networks of Power in World Society.&amp;rdquo; Hitotsubashi Journal of Law and Politics Special Issue (1994): 5-17.
Starting from Strange&amp;rsquo;s response to Waltz&amp;rsquo;s (in)famous London School of Economic lecture (see Millennium: 22/2 - Summer 1993) in this article she first argues for a wider reading of politics – not just what states do. She then briefly summarises her arguments regarding structural power before discussing the roles states have historically played as producers of security, credit, market relations and environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?&amp;rdquo; In The External Relations of the European Community, in Particular EC-US Relations, edited by Jürgen Schwarze, 109-118. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1989.
Strange suggests that the two primary activities of any political organisation are the furtherance of security and the control of money, and it is these issues that remain at the centre of the problem of US-Europe relations. Here Strange again challenges the assumption of a loss of American hegemony (and therefore power) in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics, Trade and Money</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/politics_trade_and_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/politics_trade_and_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Politics, Trade and Money.&amp;rdquo; In Europe, America and the World Economy, edited by Loukas Tsoukalis, 243-255. Oxford: Basil Blackwell for the College of Europe, 1986.
Strange identifies two main obstructions to a constructive dialogue between the United States and Europe over international trade: America&amp;rsquo;s lack of interest in maintaining a steady provision of credit to the interdependent international system; and Europe&amp;rsquo;s inability to take responsibility for its own defence and security, and therefore reducing its dependence on America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuba and After</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/cuba_and_after/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/cuba_and_after/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cuba and After.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1963, edited by George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, 1-28. London: Stevens, 1963.
Resisting the prevailing &amp;lsquo;informed&amp;rsquo; analysis that the Cuban Missile Crisis was more an apparent danger than a real one, Strange sides with the &amp;lsquo;man in the street&amp;rsquo; to argue it was a very real moment of possible war and as such profoundly affected the US system of alliances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/british_foreign_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/british_foreign_policy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;British Foreign Policy.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1955, edited by George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, 35-53. London: Stevens, 1955.
Strange argues that a state whose power is waning is more liable to make fatal mistakes. British economic survival could only be made possible by conditions of expanding world trade, rising standards of living in export markets and a minimum of economic nationalism. Britain&amp;rsquo;s future thus largely depends on the US, as she is no longer as essential as a market and supplier of capital as she once was to the members of the Commonwealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economic Work of the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_economic_work_of_the_united_nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_economic_work_of_the_united_nations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Economic Work of the United Nations.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1956, edited by George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, 118-140. London: Stevens, 1954.
Strange argues that governments have increased power over domestic economic forces, and feel that this power is necessary and desirable. The UN has generated and publicised debates surrounding economic development, and led indirectly to &amp;lsquo;point four programme&amp;rsquo; financial aid. But the US has in practice been given a paternal right to define and prioritise the economic goals of the UN, and set the agenda of acceptable economic policies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
