<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ford and the Global Strategies of Multinationals: The North American Auto Industry</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ford_and_the_global_strategies_of_multinationals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ford_and_the_global_strategies_of_multinationals/</guid>
      <description>Studer-Noguez, Maria Isabel. Ford and the Global Strategies of Multinationals: The North American Auto Industry. London: Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, 2002.
Keywords: Corporations; States; Globalization; Authority; Markets
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mad Money</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/mad_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/mad_money/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Mad Money. Manchester: Manchester University Press, 1998.
In this sequel to Casino Capitalism (1986) Strange returns to a concentration on the financial structure. Her final book finds Strange once again emphasising the need to recognise the problems of instability in the global financial sector. Arguing that the system itself needed to be reformed, she once again refused to accept that the current upheavals were inevitable or unavoidable.
Keywords: Money and Finance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Retreat of the State: State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state_state_diffusion_of_power_in_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state_state_diffusion_of_power_in_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Retreat of the State: State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1996.
In what might effectively be regarded as the third part of a trilogy, together with States and Markets (1988) and Rival States, Rival Firms (with John M. Stopford, 1991), Strange examines states&#39; transition towards the sidelines of global political economic relations. Though in the past authority might have been state based, now she argues it is more often based on non-state abilities to bring about (or structure) outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets, 2nd edition</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/states_and_markets_2nd_ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/states_and_markets_2nd_ed/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. States and Markets, 2nd edition. London: Printer Publisdhers, 1994.
There are no major differences between this and the first edition.
Keywords: Foundational Work; Political Economy; Structural Power, Power; Theory; Authority vs Markets
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rival States, Rival Firms: Competition for World Market Shares</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/rival_states_rival_firms/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, John M. Stopford, with John S. Henley. Rival States, Rival Firms: Competition for World Market Shares. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1991.
A self-avowedly part international relations - part international business management work which in keeping with Strange&amp;rsquo;s views discusses the interdependence between politics and economics without fore-grounding one at the expense of the other. The book builds on Strange&amp;rsquo;s theory of power and links it through three national studies (Brazil, Malaysia, Kenya) to a consideration of the effect of structural change in the international political economy on the role of TNCs in international economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/states_and_markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/states_and_markets/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. States and Markets. London: Pinter Publishers, 1988.
Although subtitled &amp;lsquo;An Introduction&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; to IPE, this represents the only book length discussion of Strange&amp;rsquo;s theory of the four dimensions of power in IPE. It is at once an introduction to the subject and a forceful agenda setting exercise for further research. As such, though often appearing on undergraduate course reading lists, this is Strange&amp;rsquo;s defining book, one about which the rest of her work revolves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casino Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/casino_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/casino_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Casino Capitalism. Oxford: Blackwell Publishers, 1986.
Strange argues that uncertainty and risk in the financial sector/structure have provoked major economic disturbances in the last twenty or so years. This work represents a detailed sectoral history and analysis which argues against many of the proposed solutions to the international economic crisis she identifies. Strange argues that the United States must once again take up the leadership role (which it enjoys by virtue of economic preponderance) and more radically suggests that in the future financial regulation of credit creating agencies should not be a territorially based jurisdiction, but based on the currencies themselves wherever the credit transactions take place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sterling and British Policy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy_a_political_study_of_an_international_currency_in_decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy_a_political_study_of_an_international_currency_in_decline/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Sterling and British Policy: A Political Study of an International Currency in Decline. London: Oxford University Press, 1971.
Strange proposes a four element theoretical framework for international currencies in the international political economy: Neutral currencies; Top currencies; Master Currencies; and Negotiated currencies, where each category exhibits certain economic and political characteristics. A currency may display more than one set of characteristics but will belong predominantly to one category. She then goes on to discuss the development of the international political economy in light of the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Sterling Problem and the Six. London:Chatham House/PEP, 1967.
In this small pamphlet Strange analyses the twin roles of sterling in the international economy - that of reserve currency and of vehicle currency (in which transactions are carried out), in a precursor to her typology of currencies in Sterling and British Policy (1971). She argues that while the City has benefited from the expansion of the ‘Euro-currency’ markets, in its ‘middleman’ role, this has led to a number of problems for sterling both in the wider context of the international economy and, more specifically, the context of the emerging European Community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Soviet Trade Weapon</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Soviet Trade Weapon. London: Phoenix House, 1959.
This pamphlet appeared in Background Books series. Taking a rather optimistic (though at that time widespread view) of the Soviet Bloc&amp;rsquo;s economic situation vis-à-vis the West, Strange concludes that Soviet economic (and political) influence is reliant on economic &amp;lsquo;trouble-spots&amp;rsquo; and the aversion by many developing states to the West&amp;rsquo;s recent history of colonialism. This leads her to suggest that money then spent on military aid might be better spent helping developing countries deal with agricultural surplus capacity in the global a market, a theme she would return to in &amp;ldquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rdquo; (1979).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
