<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markets on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/markets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markets on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Structural-Power and International Regimes.</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strucutural-power_and_international_regimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strucutural-power_and_international_regimes/</guid>
      <description>Gwynn, Maria A. &amp;ldquo;Structural-Power and International Regimes&amp;rdquo;. Journal of Political Power 12, no. 2 (2019): 200-223.
This paper revisits the international relations approach to structural power. In particular, it stresses the influence of international regimes, institutions and international law, on current understandings of structural power. The new approach broadens conceptions that see structural power solely as constraints; structures not only reflect the capabilities of actors that created them, but also generate new capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 176-203.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power potentially is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This article offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the &#39;Knowledge Structure&#39;: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the ‘Knowledge Structure’: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 164-175.
Somewhat paradoxically, the implications of knowledge governance&amp;rsquo;s changing role for the exercise of power in the Information Age remains underappreciated outside those scholars and policymakers directly engaged with these specific areas. This special issue brings together political scientists and communication scholars to consider the issue of knowledge governance through the theoretical framework of Susan Strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money, Power, Authority</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/money_power_authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/money_power_authority/</guid>
      <description>Cohen, BenjamIn J. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 129-143. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter discusses the political economy of the global transformation. The share of American gross domestic product (GDP) in relation to global GDP had declined; the control of American corporations over key international markets remained high and was even growing. Strange argued that the global articulation of power was constituted by a complicated amalgam of public and the private authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaping the World Beyond the &#39;Core&#39;: States and Markets in Brazil&#39;s Global Assent</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/shaping_the_world_beyond_the_core_states_and_markest_in_brazils_global_assent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/shaping_the_world_beyond_the_core_states_and_markest_in_brazils_global_assent/</guid>
      <description>Tussie, Diana. &amp;ldquo;Shaping the World Beyond the &amp;lsquo;Core&amp;rsquo;: States and Markets In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 73-86. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter argues that the global financial crisis of 2008 presented a unique opportunity to re-visit them and to re-evaluate Strange&amp;rsquo;s core argument about the enduring structural power of the US in global finance. It explains how this power was particularly apparent in two international developments that took place at the height of the crisis: the US international lender-of-last-resort role and the absence of a dollar crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall, editor. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. London: Routledge, 2016.
This edited volume addresses the 2007/2009 financial crisis as the occasion to engage critically with the corpus of Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s work, in order to consider what changes (if any) this crisis portends for the structural organization of the global political economy. The contributors use Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on the broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Economy of Global Transformation: Susan Strange, E.H. Carr and the Dynamics of Structural Change</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_political_economy_of_global_transformation_susan_strange_eh_carr_and_the_dynamics_of_structural_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_political_economy_of_global_transformation_susan_strange_eh_carr_and_the_dynamics_of_structural_change/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;The Political Economy of Global Transformation: Susan Strange, E.H. Carr and the Dynamics of Structural Change.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 183-200. London: Routledge, 2016.
Do international relations precede or follow (logically) fundamental social relations? There can be no doubt that they follow. Any organic innovation in the social structure, through its technical–military expressions, modifies organically absolute and relative relations in the international field too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transnational Corporations and the Proliferation of Bilateral Investment Treaties: More Than a Bit Influential</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/transnational_corporations_and_the_proliferation_of_bilateral_investment_treaties_more_than_a_bit_influential/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/transnational_corporations_and_the_proliferation_of_bilateral_investment_treaties_more_than_a_bit_influential/</guid>
      <description>Jacobs, Michael. &amp;ldquo;Transnational Corporations and the Proliferation of Bilateral Investment Treaties: More Than a Bit Influential.&amp;rdquo; Transnational Corporations Review 8, no. 2 (2016): 93-111.
To date, over 2500 bilateral investment treaties (BITs) have been signed. The popularity of these treaties raises the question, what has driven the proliferation of BITs? Previous research argues that the proliferation of BITs is the product of competition for capital among developing states. This study hypothesises that the developed state transnational corporations (TNCs) are driving the spread of BITs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering the Ontological Foundations of International Energy Affairs: Realist Geopolitics, Market Liberalism and a Politico-Economic Alternative</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/reconsidering_the_ontological_foundations_of_international_energy_affairs_realist_geopolitics_market_liberalism_and_a_politico-economic_alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/reconsidering_the_ontological_foundations_of_international_energy_affairs_realist_geopolitics_market_liberalism_and_a_politico-economic_alternative/</guid>
      <description>Stoddard, Edward. &amp;ldquo;Reconsidering the Ontological Foundations of International Energy Affairs: Realist Geopolitics, Market Liberalism and a Politico-Economic Alternative.&amp;rdquo; European Security 22, no. 4 (2013): 437-463.
Accounts of international energy affairs often present a divergence between geopolitical/realist and liberal market-based approaches. This article suggests that this state of affairs reflects the (often implicit) legacies of realist and rationalist international thought in the study of energy affairs and the corresponding political and economic ontological hierarchies of analytical frameworks employed in different accounts of energy politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return of the State? The G20, the Financial Crisis and Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/return_of_the_state_the_g20_the_financial_crisis_and_power_in_the_world_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/return_of_the_state_the_g20_the_financial_crisis_and_power_in_the_world_economy/</guid>
      <description>Nordberg, Donald. &amp;ldquo;Return of the State? The G20, the Financial Crisis and Power in the World Economy.&amp;rdquo; Review of Political Economy 24, no. 2 (2012): 289-302.
The Group of Twenty and the new world order it is meant to signify have prompted a wave of triumphalism around the world from those who, like French President Nicolas Sarkozy, bemoan the influences of ‘Anglo-Saxon capitalism’ and from neo-Marxists, who view the economic crisis as a harbinger of the resurgence of states over markets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
