<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internaional Relations on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/internaional-relations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internaional Relations on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/internaional-relations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: Reuiniting Three Fields of Intellectual Endeavour</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ipe_reuiniting_three_fields_of_intellectual_endeavour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ipe_reuiniting_three_fields_of_intellectual_endeavour/</guid>
      <description>Strange uses the work she was co-ordinating with John Stopford, later published as (Strange and Stopford 1991) to launch a critique of the separation of International Relations, International Economics and the research carried out in business schools. She argues that her approach, foregrounding structural power, requires analysis from all three directions and therefore there needs to be much better contact and co-operation between the three fields. Here Strange is again expressing her frustration, which first surfaced in (1970a) and continued to produce recommendations for the breaking down of disciplinary boundaries throughout her subsequent career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sterling and British Policy: A Political View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy_a_political_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy_a_political_view/</guid>
      <description>Strange sets the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar in the context of international politics. She stresses the need to integrate economic studies with those of international relations. Both state behaviour and the behaviour of international society, hitherto interpreted in terms of power and politics should now be extended to take in the monetary factor especially in the light of economic interdependence - the monetary factor is bound to become increasingly important in understanding state behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</guid>
      <description>Strange’s first call for the development of International Political Economy as a separate discipline. She identifies a major void between the academic study of international relations and the study of international economics. The failure to fill this void will result in a loss of relevance for the subjects and an inability to deal with the major problems that beset the international economy. This will also lead to the inability to analyse the two main tendencies in the international economic system; growing international co-operation and organisation, and increased domestic defensiveness over national welfare issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Money Matters</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_money_matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_money_matters/</guid>
      <description>Strange uses a survey of a number of recent textbooks (and other writing) on international economics to criticise the economics profession as a whole for taking too little account of politics. Most economists are satisfied with international growth and rising ‘efficiency’ she argues without ever asking questions regarding the evident inequalities in the intentional economy or the political dimensions of the uneven growth between countries. These criticisms were instrumental in her call in other writing around this time for the establishment of a discipline of International Political Economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Default in the International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debt_and_default_in_the_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Acting as a rapporteur for the SSRC Advisory Group on International Organisation (chaired by Goodwin), Strange maps out current and future research as well as examining its organisation and administration. Though published two year prior to Strange’s first call for the establishment of International Political Economy (1970a), this report on the discussion of research into international organisation and international relations reveals many themes (from the impact of structure and technology to the importance of international economics) she would develop in her own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers. While encouraging industry in developing states, instead of commodity exports, this would reduce the ‘loading of the dice’ identified by G77.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debts, Defaulters, and Development</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</guid>
      <description>Strange suggests that problems of national debt default have not been solved, merely suppressed by the expansion of credit provision. Developing states dependence on ‘supplier credit’, and frequent rescheduling of other debts will lead to eventual wide-spread default unless action is taken. She suggests that: principles governing international loans should be established; these ‘rules’ should be applied through aid-agencies and other international bodies; technical assistance to finance ministries should be available from multilateral institutions (the World Bank, possibly) to ensure states understand their fiscal position and their options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dissident View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_dissident_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_dissident_view/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article: Strange comments on the UN deliberations concerning the future of Palestine and highlights the central factor that gave the Zionists an in-built advantage at the assembly. While the Arabs were negotiating in a state that was essentially antipathetic to their struggle, their opposite numbers were surrounded by sympathisers and supporters both within and outside the organisation. She also discusses some of the limitations and problems with such negotiations within the forum of the UN, and alludes to structural impediments to the ‘fair’ settlement of differences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
