<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal: Millennium Journal of International Studies on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/journal-millennium-journal-of-international-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal: Millennium Journal of International Studies on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/journal-millennium-journal-of-international-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Business and the State</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/big_business_and_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/big_business_and_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange argues in this short piece that TNCs should be placed at the centre of IPE analysis along with the state and should not be left on the periphery. She also argues for an outside-in understanding of TNCs, putting them into the context in which they operate to understand them. This context is being transformed by changes in the production and financial structures, while she implicitly also argues for the centrality of changes in the ‘knowledge’ structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back - But Mostly Forward</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</guid>
      <description>In this survey article, Strange looks back across the first ten years of Millennium to examine the development of International Relations, although as she makes plain she prefers the term International Studies. Having seen the field expand from a focus on the foreign polices of various states, she maps the increasing interest in the international system itself. However, she then argues that what is now needed is a further development of research into the structures of this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/british_foreign_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/british_foreign_policy/</guid>
      <description>This pamphlet appeared in Background Books series. Taking a rather optimistic (though at that time widespread view) of the Soviet Bloc’s economic situation vis-à-vis the West, Strange concludes that Soviet economic (and political) influence is reliant on economic ‘trouble-spots’ and the aversion by many developing states to the West’s recent history of colonialism. This leads her to suggest that money then spent on military aid might be better spent helping developing countries deal with agricultural surplus capacity in the global a market, a theme she would return to in (1979a).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
