<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Globalization on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/globalization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Globalization on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/globalization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, Krasner! The World has Changed</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globaloney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globaloney/</guid>
      <description>In this review of the influential Paul Hirst and Grahame Thompson Globalisation in Question (Oxford: Polity Press, 1996) alongside two other books arguing a similar position, Strange makes a major intervention in the debate over the ‘myth’ of globalisation. Arguing that the authors (like others) miss the deterritorialisation of commercial power in the global system, Strange allows that there needs to be a corrective to the extreme globalisation thesis of complete transformation, but that a failure to examine what is really happening in the global political economy, while relying on aggregated and out-of-date statistics has led too many political economists to fail to recognise the very real changes in the balance of power between multinational corporations and states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_limits_of_politics/</guid>
      <description>Originally delivered as a lecture at the LSE this article finds Strange explicitly engaging with the notion of globalisation. For Strange globalisation is: the development of products for explicitly global and transnational markets; the decline of barriers and distinctions between national economies; the emergence of at least partial labour mobility in addition to the more recognised capital mobility; and the speeding up of transport and communications. While these trends have changed the balance between authority and markets over outcomes in the international political economy, they have also led to an increasingly globalised but asymmetrical array of structural power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
