<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1980&#39;s on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/1980s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1980&#39;s on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/1980s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Never Meant to be an Academic</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/i_never_meant_to_be_an_academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/i_never_meant_to_be_an_academic/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;I Never Meant to be an Academic.&amp;rdquo; In Journeys Through World Politics: Autobiographical Reflections of Thirty-four Academic Travellers, edited by James Kruzel, James N. Roseneau, 429-436. Lexington: Lexington Books, 1989.
This brief autobiographical essay makes interesting reading and, if one so chooses, may give clues to the personal foundations for Strange&amp;rsquo;s approach. The essay is weighted towards her earlier life but is none the less informative for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: Reuniting Three Fields of Intellectual Endeavour</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_political_economy_reuniting_three_fields_of_intellectual_endeavour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/international_political_economy_reuniting_three_fields_of_intellectual_endeavour/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Political Economy: Reuniting Three Fields of Intellectual Endeavour.&amp;rdquo; Liberal Education 75, no. 3 (1989): 20-24.
Strange uses the work she was co-ordinating with John Stopford, later published as Rival States, Rival Firms (with John M. Stopford, 1991) to launch a critique of the separation of International Relations, International Economics and the research carried out in business schools. She argues that her approach, foregrounding structural power, requires analysis from all three directions and therefore there needs to be much better contact and co-operation between the three fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistence_of_problems_in_ec-us_relations_conflicts_of_perception/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Persistence of Problems in EC-US Relations: Conflicts of Perception?&amp;rdquo; In The External Relations of the European Community, in Particular EC-US Relations, edited by Jürgen Schwarze, 109-118. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1989.
Strange suggests that the two primary activities of any political organisation are the furtherance of security and the control of money, and it is these issues that remain at the centre of the problem of US-Europe relations. Here Strange again challenges the assumption of a loss of American hegemony (and therefore power) in the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Theory of Transnational Empire</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/towards_a_theory_of_transnational_empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/towards_a_theory_of_transnational_empire/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Towards a Theory of Transnational Empire.&amp;rdquo; In Global Changes and Theoretical Challenges: Approaches to World Politics for the 1990s, Edited by Ernst-Otto Czempiel and James N. Roseneau, 161-176. Lexington: Lexington Books, 1989.
In this article Strange offers only her second explicit excursion into the epistemology of international theories, the first being a similar section in States and Markets (1988). She argues that theories must be more than description, taxonomy, importation of models from other disciplines or quantitative and that theories must explain some aspect of the international system not obvious to &amp;lsquo;commonsense&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dissident View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/a_dissident_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/a_dissident_view/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;A Dissident View.&amp;rdquo; In One European Market? A Critical Analysis of the Commission&amp;rsquo;s Internal Market Strategy, edited byRoland Bieber, John Pinder, Joseph H.H. Weiler, 73-76. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1988.
A brief article in which Strange argues that in the national competition for market shares within the global economy, there are two important strategies, neither of which at that time could the European Community realistically follow. Firstly, state procurement can be used as a stimulus to research and development and secondly the control of market access can be used as a bargaining lever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending Benign Mercantilism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Defending Benign Mercantilism.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Peace Research 25, no. 3 (1988): 273-277.
In this review of Robert Gilpin&amp;rsquo;s Political Economy of International Relations, Strange again argues against &amp;lsquo;Hegemonic Stability Theory&amp;rsquo;, see &amp;lsquo;The persistent myth of lost hegemony&amp;rsquo; (1987), but has started to develop a theory of transnational empire to explain the structural power of the United States. Part of this argument is the increasing non-territoriality of structural power, which is developed in a number of works below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States and Markets</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/states_and_markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/states_and_markets/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. States and Markets. London: Pinter Publishers, 1988.
Although subtitled &amp;lsquo;An Introduction&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; to IPE, this represents the only book length discussion of Strange&amp;rsquo;s theory of the four dimensions of power in IPE. It is at once an introduction to the subject and a forceful agenda setting exercise for further research. As such, though often appearing on undergraduate course reading lists, this is Strange&amp;rsquo;s defining book, one about which the rest of her work revolves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of the American Empire</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_future_of_the_american_empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_future_of_the_american_empire/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Future of the American Empire.&amp;rdquo; Journal of International Affairs 42, no. 1 (1988): 1-17.
Strange argues that increasingly power in the international political economy is not territorially defined, and what has emerged is an empire that is not territorially based, and secondly is controlled by information-rich US corporations. However while she call this the &amp;lsquo;American Empire&amp;rsquo; her argument is (self-avowedly) close to an international Gramscian &amp;lsquo;historical bloc&amp;rsquo; analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony: Reply to Milner and Snyder &#39;Lost Hegemony?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony_reply/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony_reply/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan &amp;ldquo;The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony: Reply to Milner and Snyder [&amp;lsquo;Lost Hegemony?&#39;].&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 42, no. 4 (1988): 751-752.
In reference to &amp;lsquo;The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony&amp;rsquo; (1987) there was a brief methodological exchange in the pages of International Organisation which while essentially inconclusive, offered a brief clue to Strange&amp;rsquo;s attitude to empirical evidence. Though she originally cited empirical data, in response to the criticism from Milner and Snyder that this evidence left her arguments unproved, Strange answered that the real evidence to prove her argument empirically would be too difficult to collect, though in theory it could be possible to compile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, &amp;ldquo;The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony.&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 41, no. 4 (1987): 551-574.
Strange&amp;rsquo;s classic attack of the &amp;lsquo;declinist school&amp;rsquo; in international relations. Once she has discussed the more &amp;lsquo;sociological&amp;rsquo; reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
