<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiley on </title>
    <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/wiley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wiley on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/categories/wiley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</guid>
      <description>Building on the argument of Robert Reich that the location of economic activity (in a state) was more important for its competitiveness than the ownership of companies (whose production was carried out abroad), Strange suggests that unless European policy recognises the importance of society based competitiveness rather than firm-based competitiveness, Europe’s economic problems cannot be overcome. Strange then discusses European trade policy (which needs to be more predictable), investment policy (which should be more open), European Monetary Union (which while stabilising may have little effect on inward investment from non-European investors), and welfare issues (which need to continue to cushion technological-unemployment).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Business in Japan. A Policy Cross-roads?</title>
      <link>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/european_business_in_japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks-child-theme.netlify.app/archive/european_business_in_japan/</guid>
      <description>Contrasting European and American proposals for the perceived difficulty of setting up foreign owned subsidiaries in Japan, Strange argues that this is a central issue for any nascent European foreign policy initiative. She argues that it may now be beyond any nationally elected government (even in the US.) to re-impose its hegemonic intent on other states. But some co-ordinated pressure from Japanese and European policy bodies may support the reintroduction into global politics of a more interdependent (and less free-market) approach to commercial and financial diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
