<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1960&#39;s on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/1960s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1960&#39;s on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/1960s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Multilateral Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_meaning_of_multilateral_surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Meaning of Multilateral Surveillance.&amp;rdquo; In International Organisation: World Politics: Studies in Economic and Social Agencies, edited by Robert W. Cox, 231-247. London: Macmillan, 1969.
Taking the relationship between debtor and creditor countries as her starting point Strange argues that multilateral surveillance is not as draconian as it is presented. She notes that military expenditure is seldom included in the requests for debtor country adjustments. Despite the international economic organisations’ role, states were still able to manipulate their creditors through political pressures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on International Organisation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, Geoffrey Goodwin. Research on International Organisation (Social Science Research Council Review of Current Research: 2). London: Heinemann Educational, for the Social Sciences Research Council, 1968.
Acting as a rapporteur for the SSRC Advisory Group on International Organisation (chaired by Goodwin), Strange maps out current and future research as well as examining its organisation and administration. Though published two year prior to Strange’s first call for the establishment of International Political Economy, in &amp;lsquo;International economics and international relations: a case of mutual neglect&amp;rsquo; (1970), this report on the discussion of research into international organisation and international relations reveals many themes (from the impact of structure and technology to the importance of international economics) she would develop in her own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debts, Defaulters, and Development</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/debts_defaulters_and_development/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Debts, Defaulters, and Development.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 43, no. 3 (1967): 516-529.
Strange suggests that problems of national debt default have not been solved, merely suppressed by the expansion of credit provision. Developing states dependence on &amp;lsquo;supplier credit&amp;rsquo;, and frequent rescheduling of other debts will lead to eventual wide-spread default unless action is taken. She suggests that: principles governing international loans should be established; these &amp;lsquo;rules&amp;rsquo; should be applied through aid-agencies and other international bodies; technical assistance to finance ministries should be available from multilateral institutions (the World Bank, possibly) to ensure states understand their fiscal position and their options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Problem and the Six</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_sterling_problem_and_the_six/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Sterling Problem and the Six. London: Chatham House/PEP, 1967.
In this small pamphlet Strange analyses the twin roles of sterling in the international economy - that of reserve currency and of vehicle currency (in which transactions are carried out), in a precursor to her typology of currencies in Sterling and British Policy (1971). She argues that while the City has benefited from the expansion of the ‘Euro-currency’ markets, in its ‘middleman’ role, this has led to a number of problems for sterling both in the wider context of the international economy and, more specifically, the context of the emerging European Community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sterling Question</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_sterling_question/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_sterling_question/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Sterling Question.&amp;rdquo; In Britain and the Common Market, edited by Anthony Moncrieff, 43-50. London: BBC, 1967.
In this text of a radio talk first broadcast on 19th February 1967, Strange summarises the arguments she made in The Sterling Problem and the Six (1967). Discussing the links between Britain and the European Community, she examines the international position of sterling in a time of monetary crisis. Noting both the lack of reserves held by the British government and Britain’s extra-European financial commitments, Strange argues that de Gaulle may be correct in thinking it is impossible for Britain to act ‘like good Europeans’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;A New Look at Trade and Aid.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 42, no. 1 (1966): 61-73.
In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuba and After</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/cuba_and_after/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/cuba_and_after/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cuba and After.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1963, edited by George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, 1-28. London: Stevens, 1963.
Resisting the prevailing &amp;lsquo;informed&amp;rsquo; analysis that the Cuban Missile Crisis was more an apparent danger than a real one, Strange sides with the &amp;lsquo;man in the street&amp;rsquo; to argue it was a very real moment of possible war and as such profoundly affected the US system of alliances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Trends in World Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/changing_trends_in_world_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/changing_trends_in_world_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Changing Trends in World Trade.&amp;rdquo; In Year Book of World Affairs 1962, edited by George W. Keeton, Georg Schwarzenberger, 139-158. London: Stevens, 1962.
Here Strange notes that since 1945 although manufacturing growth has accelerated expanding the trade between developed states there has been less growth in the demand for raw materials and agricultural goods. This distorted or uneven growth in trade had not only had an unsettling effect of world trade, but has also required developing states to take out loans to support their development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of: J.L Allen Soviet Economic Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/review_of_jl_allen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/review_of_jl_allen/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of: J.L Allen Soviet Economic Power.&amp;rdquo; Economica 28, no. 109 (1961): 98-99.
Strange challenges the implicit assertion by the author that the interpretation of Soviet interest, or its choice of the means to an end, is static. She also doubts the ascription by the author of Finnish subservience to the Soviet Union as being solely one of economic dependence rather than strategic vulnerability. As one would expect Strange dismisses mono-causality, as she continues to do in all her work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
