<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political Economy on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/political-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political Economy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/political-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Study of Transnational Relations.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 333-345.
Using the ‘Dollar Crisis’ as a way of examining the problems which beset academic approaches to international relations Strange suggests that: foreign policy analysis seems unable to recognise the centrality of economic problems for states; (Neo)functionalism is far too optimistic concerning the possibility of international integration; much ‘abstract theorising’, such as game theory, seems to have no connection with what is happening in the international system; and international economics has diverted attention away from international political problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Poicy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, and Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?&amp;rdquo; International Journal 30, no. 2 (1975): 207-224.
Here Strange commits to print an early version of the structure of power theory which she would develop over the next thirteen years. In this manifestation, there are three dimensions of power in the international political economy - security, ‘ideology’ and economic. There is more concern, though, with a location of four level or stages at which economic power is apparent - the world market structure; international co-operative relations; national/governmental control of markets; and the operational level of the economic transactions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMF: Monetary Managers</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;IMF: Monetary Managers.&amp;rdquo; In The Anatomy of Influence: Decision Making in International Organisation, edited by Robert W. Cox and Harold K. Jacobson, 263-297. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1974.
This is a detailed case study of the IMF, which Strange uses to back up her warning that there can be no justification for an analytical division between the economic and the political. She argues that the IMF can only be understood within its international political context, and suggests that any institutional changes will reflect the continuing development of the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dollar Crisis 1971</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Dollar Crisis 1971.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 48, no. 2 (1972): 191-216.
Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_multinational_corporation/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Multinational Corporation and the National Interest.&amp;rdquo; In Decision Making in Britain, edited by James Barber, 165-178. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1972.
In one of her earliest pieces to deal directly with multinational companies or corporations Strange argues that an analysis of the companies not only leads to both domestic and foreign policy making but also into the realm of international (regulatory) policy making. Much of the text is taken up with a discussion of the likely conflicts in interest between governments and corporations with multinational operations (as she prefers to term them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sterling and British Policy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Sterling and British Policy: A Political View.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 47, no. 2 (1971): 302-315.
Strange proposes a four element theoretical framework for international currencies in the international political economy: Neutral currencies; Top currencies; Master Currencies; and Negotiated currencies, where each category exhibits certain economic and political characteristics. A currency may display more than one set of characteristics but will belong predominantly to one category. She then goes on to discuss the development of the international political economy in light of the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 46, no. 2 (1970): 304-315.
Strange’s first call for the development of International Political Economy as a separate discipline. She identifies a major void between the academic study of international relations and the study of international economics. The failure to fill this void will result in a loss of relevance for the subjects and an inability to deal with the major problems that beset the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Money Matters</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_money_matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_money_matters/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Money Matters.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 46, no. 4 (1970): 737-743.
Strange uses a survey of a number of recent textbooks (and other writing) on international economics to criticise the economics profession as a whole for taking too little account of politics. Most economists are satisfied with international growth and rising ‘efficiency’ she argues without ever asking questions regarding the evident inequalities in the intentional economy or the political dimensions of the uneven growth between countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of International Currencies</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_international_currencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_politics_of_international_currencies/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Politics of International Currencies.&amp;rdquo; World Politics 23, no. 2 (1970): 215-231.
Here Strange argues that because of interdependence states are not so much defenders of national territories or peoples but of national currencies and monetary systems. Conflict can be caused by one monetary system damaging another. The expansion of the international economy requires more and more sophisticated and complex monetary and financial arrangements and the forms of association among them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
