<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political Economy on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/political-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political Economy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/political-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: The Story so Far and the Way Ahead</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_political_economy_the_story_so_far_and_the_way_ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_political_economy_the_story_so_far_and_the_way_ahead/</guid>
      <description>In An International Political Economy (International Political Economy Yearbook No.1), edited by W. Ladd Hollist and F. LaMond Tullis, 13-25.Boulder:Westview Press, 1985.
After noting again the essential role of economic historians in the study and understanding of the international political economy, Strange builds on an appreciation of the value of development economists, a plea for the re-inclusion of values into the study of IPE. This in the main is because they are already tacitly included, but there is little engagement with the economist’s prioritising of efficiency or the International Relations scholar’s of peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionsim and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>In Protectionism and World Politics International Organization39, no.2(Spring).233-259.1985.
In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade ‘inefficiencies’ as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a ‘secondary structure’ which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures. The disruption in the international system and trade relations is in fact a symptom of disruptions within the primary structures, and especially the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis,&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36 no. 2, (1982): 337-354.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back - But Mostly Forward</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Looking Back - But Mostly Forward,&amp;rdquo; Millennium Journal of International Relations 11, no. 1 (1982):38-49.
In this survey article, Strange looks back across the first ten years of Millennium to examine the development of International Relations, although as she makes plain she prefers the term International Studies. Having seen the field expand from a focus on the foreign polices of various states, she maps the increasing interest in the international system itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Robert O. Keohane and Joeseph S. Nye (1977) Power and Interdependence: World Politics in Transition and Edward L. Morse (1976) Modernization and Transformation of International Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review-of-o.-keohane-and-joeseph-s-1977-power-and-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review-of-o.-keohane-and-joeseph-s-1977-power-and-independence/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Review of Robert O. Keohane and Joeseph S. Nye (1977) Power and Interdependence: World Politics in Transition and Edward L. Morse (1976) Modernization and Transformation of International Relations&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 53, no. 2 (1977): 270-273.
In this short review of two important books in the development of International Political Economy, Strange briefly suggests the position which she would adopt more forthrightly later in her career: that IPE was not a sub-discipline of International Relations, but rather sought to completely redefine what it is to study the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Study of Transnational Relations.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 333-345.
Using the ‘Dollar Crisis’ as a way of examining the problems which beset academic approaches to international relations Strange suggests that: foreign policy analysis seems unable to recognise the centrality of economic problems for states; (Neo)functionalism is far too optimistic concerning the possibility of international integration; much ‘abstract theorising’, such as game theory, seems to have no connection with what is happening in the international system; and international economics has diverted attention away from international political problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, and Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?&amp;rdquo; International Journal 30, no. 2 (1975): 207-224.
Here Strange commits to print an early version of the structure of power theory which she would develop over the next thirteen years. In this manifestation, there are three dimensions of power in the international political economy - security, ‘ideology’ and economic. There is more concern, though, with a location of four level or stages at which economic power is apparent - the world market structure; international co-operative relations; national/governmental control of markets; and the operational level of the economic transactions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMF: Monetary Managers</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/imf_monetary_managers/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;IMF: Monetary Managers.&amp;rdquo; In The Anatomy of Influence: Decision Making in International Organisation, edited by Robert W. Cox and Harold K. Jacobson, 263-297. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1974.
This is a detailed case study of the IMF, which Strange uses to back up her warning that there can be no justification for an analytical division between the economic and the political. She argues that the IMF can only be understood within its international political context, and suggests that any institutional changes will reflect the continuing development of the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dollar Crisis 1971</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_dollar_crisis_1971/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Dollar Crisis 1971.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 48, no. 2 (1972): 191-216.
Strange feels that the author overstates the political power and influence of multinational in themselves. She identifies a close connection between the US government and larger corporations. Interestingly this is a position that she gradually moves away from in subsequent work, identifying transnational firms as actors in their own right by 67), arguing for their major importance as actors in the international political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
