<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Susan Strange on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/susan-strange/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Susan Strange on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/susan-strange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An International Political Economy Perspective</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/an_international_political_economy_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/an_international_political_economy_perspective/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;An International Political Economy Perspective.&amp;rdquo; In Governments, Globalization, and International Business, edited by John H. Dunning, 132-145. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1997.
In this chapter Strange lays out her idea of what International Political Economy is, including a wide-ranging view of politics (not just the activities of politicians and governments) and a focus on structural power. This then leads her to discuss the problems that globalisation presents for governments, business and people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Eclectic Approach</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/an_eclectic_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/an_eclectic_approach/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;An Eclectic Approach.&amp;rdquo; In The New International Political Economy (International Political Economy Year Book No.6), edited by Craig N. Murphy , Roger Tooze, 33-49. Boulder: Lynne Rienner Publishers, 1991.
Strange reiterates the structural dimensions of power from States and Markets (1988) and then goes on to develop this further by adding three conditioning factors that influence the structural elements of power - these are states, markets and technology. Essentially the new element here is the dynamic of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Business and the State</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/big_business_and_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/big_business_and_the_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Big Business and the State.&amp;rdquo; Millennium Journal of International Studies 20, no. 2 (1991): 245-250.
Strange argues in this short piece that TNCs should be placed at the centre of IPE analysis along with the state and should not be left on the periphery. She also argues for an outside-in understanding of TNCs, putting them into the context in which they operate to understand them. This context is being transformed by changes in the production and financial structures, while she implicitly also argues for the centrality of changes in the &amp;lsquo;knowledge&amp;rsquo; structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casino Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/casino_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/casino_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. Casino Capitalism. Oxford: Blackwell Publishers, 1986.
Strange argues that uncertainty and risk in the financial sector/structure have provoked major economic disturbances in the last twenty or so years. This work represents a detailed sectoral history and analysis which argues against many of the proposed solutions to the international economic crisis she identifies. Strange argues that the United States must once again take up the leadership role (which it enjoys by virtue of economic preponderance) and more radically suggests that in the future financial regulation of credit creating agencies should not be a territorially based jurisdiction, but based on the currencies themselves wherever the credit transactions take place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the-global-political-economy-1959-1984/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984,&amp;rdquo; International Journal 39, no. 2 (1984): 267-283.
After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/cave_hic_dragones_a_critique_of_regime_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Cave! Hic Dragones: A Critique of Regime Analysis.&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1982): 337-354.
Strange’s classic critique of regime theory, often used as a touchstone for those regime-theorists wanting to make the point they recognise that there have been criticisms of their approach. As such it has at least a totemic importance. Strange argues for five shortcoming of regime theory: that it is a passing fad, is imprecise, has a value bias, is too static and is too state-centred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_financial_factor_and_the_balance_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Financial Factor and the Balance of Power.&amp;rdquo; In Foreign Policy: Policy Making and Implementation, edited by James Barber, Josephine Negro, Micheal Smith, 35-46. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1975.
Strange presents the Soviet-American balance of power alongside the balance of power in the international monetary system to make links between supposedly different sectors of the international system. While these balances function in different ways, Strange prefaces her remarks with a short argument for an International Political Economy approach to problems rather than a predominantly political or predominantly economic account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arab Oil and International Finance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/arab_oil_and_international_finance/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Arab Oil and International Finance.&amp;rdquo; The Ditchley Journal 1 (1974).
Essentially a conference report, Strange discusses the meeting held at Ditchley in December 1973 to discuss the financial prospects and problems for industry and government in the world economy, and the inescapable problem of the oil crisis. Discussing the various aspects of monetary order, from balance of payments problems and trade barriers, to financial flows, she argues that at this point too little work had been done to understand the effects and causes of shifts in monetary flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Business and the EEC</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_business_and_the_eec/</guid>
      <description>Stange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Business and the EEC.&amp;rdquo; In The Eruopean Economic Community, edited by James Barber, 82-95. Milton Keynes: Open University, 1974.
Strange discusses the relationship between international business and the EEC by briefly examining three partly overlapping assertions: that the main achievements of the EEC have resulted not from the community’s own work but from the impact of international business; that international business is a ‘Trojan horse’ for American influence and interest in Europe; and that the EEC is a necessary response to the problems brought by international business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;A New Look at Trade and Aid.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 42, no. 1 (1966): 61-73.
In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
