<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Persistent Myth of Lost Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_persistent_myth_of_lost_hegemony/</guid>
      <description>Strange’s classic attack of the ‘declinist school’ in international relations. Once she has discussed the more ‘sociological’ reasons for American academics holding this view (of which the most powerful/cynical is that it is essentially a convenient denial of responsibility by Americans for their effect on the international system), Strange goes on to elaborate the four structures of power in IPE. This exposition closely parallels (though in a brief form) the arguments that appear in (1988e).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionism and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade ‘inefficiencies’ as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a ‘secondary structure’ which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures. The disruption in the international system and trade relations is in fact a symptom of disruptions within the primary structures, and especially the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_global_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_global_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration. Strange also stresses that while the four structures are not hierarchical, she believes it is disruptions in the financial structure that has caused most upheavals over the period examined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
