<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The poverty of multilateral economic diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_poverty_of_multilateral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_poverty_of_multilateral/</guid>
      <description>In Diplomacy at the United Nations, edited by Geoff Berridge and Anthony Jennings, 109-129. London: Macmillan Press, 1985.
After reviewing the four values authority might pursue - wealth, security, justice and freedom (an argument developed at more length in States and Markets (1988), she uses these value choices to interrogate the three main paradigms used to think about the international political economy, liberalism, structuralism and nationalism. She then examines UN economic multilateralism utilising an eclectic combination of all three perspectives and concludes that as each approach continues to look to international organisation to sustain the values it emphasises, despite its failings economic multilateralism is likely to continue to be regarded as a worthwhile enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan.&amp;ldquo;Who Runs World Shipping?&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 346-367.
In the first article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane ‘transnational politics’ approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/what_is_economic_power/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;What is Economic Power, and Who Has it?&amp;rdquo; International Journal 30, no. 2 (1975): 207-224.
Here Strange commits to print an early version of the structure of power theory which she would develop over the next thirteen years. In this manifestation, there are three dimensions of power in the international political economy - security, ‘ideology’ and economic. There is more concern, though, with a location of four level or stages at which economic power is apparent - the world market structure; international co-operative relations; national/governmental control of markets; and the operational level of the economic transactions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economic_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economic_relations/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economic Relations I: The Need for an Interdisciplinary Approach.&amp;rdquo; In The Study of International Affairs: Essays in Honour of Kenneth Younger, edited by Roger Morgan, 63-84. London: RIIA/Oxford University Press, 1972.
Strange’s second major attack on the discipline of international economics as it then stood, see also &amp;lsquo;International economics and international relations: a case of mutual neglect&amp;rsquo; (1970). She derides the academic ‘apartheid’ that separates off political considerations from the economic and argues that what is required is a single international studies discipline that encompasses both the politics and economics of international relations (what would eventually become International Political Economy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sterling and British Policy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/sterling_and_british_policy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Sterling and British Policy: A Political View.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 47, no. 2 (1971): 302-315.
Strange proposes a four element theoretical framework for international currencies in the international political economy: Neutral currencies; Top currencies; Master Currencies; and Negotiated currencies, where each category exhibits certain economic and political characteristics. A currency may display more than one set of characteristics but will belong predominantly to one category. She then goes on to discuss the development of the international political economy in light of the decline of sterling and the rise of the dollar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_economics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Economics and International Relations: a Case of Mutual Neglect.&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 46, no. 2 (1970): 304-315.
Strange’s first call for the development of International Political Economy as a separate discipline. She identifies a major void between the academic study of international relations and the study of international economics. The failure to fill this void will result in a loss of relevance for the subjects and an inability to deal with the major problems that beset the international economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on International Organisation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/research_on_international_organisation/</guid>
      <description>Goodwin, Geoffry, and Susan Strange. &amp;ldquo;Research on International Organisation.&amp;rdquo; Social Science Research Council Review of Current Research 2. (1968).
Acting as a rapporteur for the SSRC Advisory Group on International Organisation (chaired by Goodwin), Strange maps out current and future research as well as examining its organisation and administration. Though published two year prior to Strange’s first call for the establishment of International Political Economy, in &amp;lsquo;International economics and international relations: a case of mutual neglect&amp;rsquo; (1970), this report on the discussion of research into international organisation and international relations reveals many themes (from the impact of structure and technology to the importance of international economics) she would develop in her own work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
