<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/information_technology_and_control_in_a_changing_world_understanding_power_structures_in_the_21st_century/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/information_technology_and_control_in_a_changing_world_understanding_power_structures_in_the_21st_century/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Kate Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
Draws on Susan Strange’s conception of the knowledge structure to offer guiding theoretical insights for analyzing how the control of knowledge in its many forms is affecting global politics, society and economics.
Keywords: Theory; Knowledge; Structural Power, Power; Security
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov. &amp;ldquo;Introduction.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century, edited by Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 1-20. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
While the control of knowledge is becoming the dominant means by which economic, political, and social control is exerted globally, the mechanisms through which this is happening—including intellectual property rights, state and commercial surveillance, digitisation and datafication, and a nearly ubiquitous internet mediating human interactions—are often examined separately instead of as part of a larger phenomenon of knowledge governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Knowledge Seriously: Towards an International Political Economy Theory of Knowledge Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/taking_knowledge_seriously_towards_an_international_political_economy_theory_of_knowledge_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/taking_knowledge_seriously_towards_an_international_political_economy_theory_of_knowledge_governance/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Taking Knowledge Seriously: Towards an International Political Economy Theory of Knowledge Governance.&amp;rdquo; In Information, Technology and Control in a Changing World: Understanding Power Structures in the 21st Century. Blayne Haggart, Kathryn Henne, Natasha Tusikov, editors. 25-52. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2019.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This chapter offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/incorporating_the_study_of_knowledge_into_the_ipe_mainstream_or_when_does_a_trade_agreement_stop_being_a_trade_agreement/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Incorporating the Study of Knowledge into the IPE Mainstream, or, When Does a Trade Agreement Stop Being a Trade Agreement?&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 176-203.
The treatment of knowledge—most notably commodified knowledge—as a source and vector of power potentially is a key blind spot in our understanding of the global political economy. This article offers a theoretical framework, based on the work of Susan Strange, for considering the relationship between what she called the “knowledge structure” and the other key sources of political and economic power—security, production, and finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/internet_freedom_and_copyright_maximalism_contradictory_hypocrisy_or_complementary_policies/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne, Michael Jablonski. &amp;ldquo;Internet Freedom and Copyright Maximalism: Contradictory Hypocrisy or Complementary Policies?.&amp;rdquo; The Information Society 33, no. 3 (2017): 103-118.
U.S. advocacy for increased international intellectual property protection and a free and open Internet has been criticized as being inconsistent at best and hypocritical at worst. Placing U.S. copyright and Internet policy in a historical context and using Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s concepts of structural power and knowledge structures, we argue that copyright and Internet policies cannot be analyzed in isolation, but are intimately and inextricably linked forms of knowledge regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the &#39;Knowledge Structure&#39;: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/introduction_to_the_special_issue_rise/</guid>
      <description>Haggart, Blayne. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the Special Issue: Rise of the ‘Knowledge Structure’: Implications for the Exercise of Power in the Global Political Economy.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Information Policy 7 (2017): 164-175.
Somewhat paradoxically, the implications of knowledge governance&amp;rsquo;s changing role for the exercise of power in the Information Age remains underappreciated outside those scholars and policymakers directly engaged with these specific areas. This special issue brings together political scientists and communication scholars to consider the issue of knowledge governance through the theoretical framework of Susan Strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing the Human Condition in a Dynamic Global System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/diagnosing_the_human_condition_in_a_dynamic_global_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/diagnosing_the_human_condition_in_a_dynamic_global_system/</guid>
      <description>Pauly, Louis W. &amp;ldquo;Diagnosing the Human Condition in a Dynamic Global System.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 183-192. London: Routledge, 2016.
Virgil&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;rerum cognoscere causas,&amp;rsquo; adorns the crest of the London School of Economics and Political Science. &amp;lsquo;To know the cause of things&amp;rsquo; expressed an abiding aspiration for Susan Strange, even if she doubted all absolute truth-claims. In the mid-1970s, after she had rejoined her alma mater as a lecturer in the International Relations Department, I attended her course on &amp;lsquo;The Politics of International Business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of IPE</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;Susan Strange and the Future of IPE.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 19-36. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explains how contributors use Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of international political economy (IPE). Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s life and times spanned the most tumultuous decades of the twentieth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering the Ontological Foundations of International Energy Affairs: Realist Geopolitics, Market Liberalism and a Politico-Economic Alternative</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/reconsidering_the_ontological_foundations_of_international_energy_affairs_realist_geopolitics_market_liberalism_and_a_politico-economic_alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/reconsidering_the_ontological_foundations_of_international_energy_affairs_realist_geopolitics_market_liberalism_and_a_politico-economic_alternative/</guid>
      <description>Stoddard, Edward. &amp;ldquo;Reconsidering the Ontological Foundations of International Energy Affairs: Realist Geopolitics, Market Liberalism and a Politico-Economic Alternative.&amp;rdquo; European Security 22, no. 4 (2013): 437-463.
Accounts of international energy affairs often present a divergence between geopolitical/realist and liberal market-based approaches. This article suggests that this state of affairs reflects the (often implicit) legacies of realist and rationalist international thought in the study of energy affairs and the corresponding political and economic ontological hierarchies of analytical frameworks employed in different accounts of energy politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a New Understanding of Structural-Power: &#39;Structure is What States Make of It.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/towards_a_new_understanding_of_structural-power_structure_is_what_states_make_of_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/towards_a_new_understanding_of_structural-power_structure_is_what_states_make_of_it/</guid>
      <description>Pustovitovskij, Andrej, Jan-Frederik Kremer. &amp;ldquo;Towards a New Understanding of Structural-Power: &amp;lsquo;Structure is What States Make of It.&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; In Power in the 21st Century. Enrico Fels, Jan-Frederik Kremer, Katharina Kronenberg, editors. 59-78. Berlin: Polity Press, 2012.
The study of power in International Relations (IR) can be seen as the search for the cornerstone of our discipline. Hardly any theory or approach of IR can claim evidence and explanatory power without at least implicitly addressing the question of the ontology of power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
