<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Susan Strange on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-susan-strange/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Susan Strange on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-susan-strange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Experiences on the Asian Mainland</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/globalisation_and_capitalist_diversity_expieriences/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, editor. Globalisation and Capitalist Diversity: Experiences on the Asian Mainland. Florence: European University Institute/Robert Schulman Centre, 1997.
This volume collects together papers presented at a conference organised by Strange at the EUI on 2-4th May 1996. Strange herself only contributed an introduction outlining the papers in the volume and discussing the organisational background to the conference. Strange argues that comparative politics scholars and international business academics need to &amp;lsquo;build bridges&amp;rsquo; between the two disciplines to better understand the interaction between states and firms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/conclusion_paths_to_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/conclusion_paths_to_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Conclusion.&amp;rdquo; In Paths to International Political Economy, Susan Strange, editor. London: Allen and Unwin, 1984.
Strange then poses the question &amp;lsquo;What about International Relations?&amp;rsquo; in her conclusion to Paths to International Political Economy (1984). After discussing the importance of the grounding in politics for economists and vice versa, Strange notes that radical theorists have concentrated too much on the production structure, and notes that the other three (finance, security and &amp;lsquo;knowledge&amp;rsquo;) are as important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Money and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/on_money_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/on_money_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, D.P. Calleo. &amp;ldquo;On Money and World Politics.&amp;rdquo; In Paths to International Political Economy, Susan Strange, editor. London: Allen and Unwin, 1984.
Strange discusses &amp;lsquo;Money and World Politics&amp;rsquo; criticising economists for supposing questions of values and power are questions of market &amp;lsquo;imperfections&amp;rsquo; and not of central importance. The article then goes on to consider the balance of payments problem and how suggestions for addressing this &amp;lsquo;problem&amp;rsquo; reveal theoretical standpoints. They also note the disruptive influence/effect of American policies on the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths to International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_international_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/paths_to_international_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, editor. Paths to International Political Economy. London: Allan and Unwin, 1984.
This is a collection of nine essays looking at various sectoral aspects to the study of IPE, together with a brief preface by Strange. In her preface Strange again singles out development economists, applied economists and economic historians and praises their openness to insights and evidence from other disciplines and sub-disciplines. Implicitly there is an epistemological argument here, against theoretical closure, though as in the majority of her writings this remains implicit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Politics of Surplus Capacity: Competition for Market Shares in the World</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_international_politics_of_surplus_capacity_competition_for_market_shares_in_the_world_/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_international_politics_of_surplus_capacity_competition_for_market_shares_in_the_world_/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan, Roger Tooze, editors. The International Politics of Surplus Capacity: Competition for Market Shares in the World. London: Allen and Unwin, 1981.
This is a collection of 17 essays resulting from a conference held by the International Political Economy Group of the BISA, together with an editorial overview of theoretical approaches to IPE and a conclusion concerning the agreements and differences among the contributors. Writing with Tooze, Strange notes that it is not intended to dispense with the ‘insights’ of the realists, but it is necessary to widen their approach considerably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/international_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;International Trade.&amp;rdquo; In Money and Trade (A Background Special), Bertrand Jouvenel, Susan Strange, editors. 53-77. London: Batchworth Press, 1955.
Foregrounding the role of technology in the development of international trade, Strange discusses the difference between the theory of free trade and the actual patterns (and barriers) to international trade in the 1950s. This leads her to emphasise balance of payments problems linked to international monetary flows and political barriers to freer trade.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
