<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trade on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/trade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trade on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/trade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan.&amp;ldquo;Who Runs World Shipping?&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 346-367.
In the first article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane ‘transnational politics’ approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, &amp;ldquo;A New Look at Trade and Aid,&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 42 no. 1 (January, 1966): 61 - 73.
In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Soviet Trade Weapon</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Soviet Trade Weapon. London: Phoenix House, 1959.
This pamphlet appeared in Background Books series. Taking a rather optimistic (though at that time widespread view) of the Soviet Bloc’s economic situation vis-à-vis the West, Strange concludes that Soviet economic (and political) influence is reliant on economic ‘trouble-spots’ and the aversion by many developing states to the West’s recent history of colonialism. This leads her to suggest that money then spent on military aid might be better spent helping developing countries deal with agricultural surplus capacity in the global a market, a theme she would return to in &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rsquo; (1979).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
