<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trade on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.org/tags/trade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trade on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:25 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.org/tags/trade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Rival States: Beyond the Triangle?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/revisting_rival_states_beyond_the_triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/revisting_rival_states_beyond_the_triangle/</guid>
      <description>Stopford, John. &amp;ldquo;Revisiting Rival States: Beyond the Triangle?&amp;rdquo; In International Business and Government Relations in the 21st Century, edited by Robert E. Grosse, 103-116. Cambridge: Emerald Group Publishing Ltd., 2005.
When Susan Strange and I looked into the relationships between firms and States during the late 1980s, we were primarily concerned to signal that the rivalry among States for control over the means of wealth creation had grown to the point where it had overtaken such traditional concerns as control over territory, to become the predominant driver of diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Today-Finance, Firms, Mafias and the State: A Review of Susan Strange&#39;s Work from a Developing Country Perspective</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/dependency_today-finance_firms_mafias_and_the_state_a_review_of_susan_stranges_work_from_a_developing_country_perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/dependency_today-finance_firms_mafias_and_the_state_a_review_of_susan_stranges_work_from_a_developing_country_perspective/</guid>
      <description>Leander, Anna. &amp;ldquo;Dependency Today-Finance, Firms, Mafias and the State: A Review of Susan Strange’s Work from a Developing Country Perspective.&amp;rdquo; Third World Quarterly 22, no. 1 (2001): 115-128.
This is an analysis of how the global strategies of Multi-national Enterprises (MNE&amp;rsquo;s) affect the power relationship between MNE&amp;rsquo;s and states in the context of increasing trans-national economic integration.
Keywords: Money and Finance; Trade; Structural Power, Power; Economic Development
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United States and World Trade: Hegemony by Proxy?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_united_states_and_world_trade_hegemony_by_proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_united_states_and_world_trade_hegemony_by_proxy/</guid>
      <description>Goldstein, Judith. &amp;ldquo;The United States and World Trade: Hegemony by Proxy?&amp;rdquo; In Strange Power: Shaping the Parameters of International Relations and International Political Economy, edited by Thomas Lawton, James Rosenau, Amy C. Verdun, 349-272. London: Routledge, 2000.
Keywords: United States; Structural Power, Power; Trade
Text access (external link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/who_are_eu_ambiguities/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Who are EU? Ambiguities in the Concept of Competitiveness.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Common Market Studies 36, no. 1 (1998): 101-114.
Building on the argument of Robert Reich that the location of economic activity (in a state) was more important for its competitiveness than the ownership of companies (whose production was carried out abroad), Strange suggests that unless European policy recognises the importance of society based competitiveness rather than firm-based competitiveness, Europe&amp;rsquo;s economic problems cannot be overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dissident View</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/a_dissident_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/a_dissident_view/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;A Dissident View.&amp;rdquo; In One European Market? A Critical Analysis of the Commission&amp;rsquo;s Internal Market Strategy, edited byRoland Bieber, John Pinder, Joseph H.H. Weiler, 73-76. Baden-Baden: Nomos Verlasgesellschaft, 1988.
A brief article in which Strange argues that in the national competition for market shares within the global economy, there are two important strategies, neither of which at that time could the European Community realistically follow. Firstly, state procurement can be used as a stimulus to research and development and secondly the control of market access can be used as a bargaining lever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defending Benign Mercantilism</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/defending_benign_mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Defending Benign Mercantilism.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Peace Research 25, no. 3 (1988): 273-277.
In this review of Robert Gilpin&amp;rsquo;s Political Economy of International Relations, Strange again argues against &amp;lsquo;Hegemonic Stability Theory&amp;rsquo;, see &amp;lsquo;The persistent myth of lost hegemony&amp;rsquo; (1987), but has started to develop a theory of transnational empire to explain the structural power of the United States. Part of this argument is the increasing non-territoriality of structural power, which is developed in a number of works below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bondage of Liberal Economics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_bondage_of_liberal_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/the_bondage_of_liberal_economics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Bondage of Liberal Economics.&amp;rdquo; SAIS Review 6, no. 1 (1986): 25-38.
Here Strange returns again to the inadequacy of economics in its analysis of international trade, made in &amp;lsquo;International Trade&amp;rsquo; (1955) and &amp;lsquo;International money matters&amp;rsquo; (1970), and elsewhere. Noting the contradictions between economic models of international trade and what was actually happening in the international economy, Strange argues economists have failed to appreciate that trade is only a secondary international structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionism - Why Not?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/protectionism_why_not/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/protectionism_why_not/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Protectionism - Why Not?&amp;rdquo; The World Today 41, nos. 8 and 9 (1985): 148-150.
In this short polemic piece Strange argues that states should adopt a pragmatic approach to protectionism (mimicking the practices, if not the ideology of America). With the growth of international production and bi-lateralism it is little wonder that, despite the GATT&amp;rsquo;s claims to the contrary, the actual figures on international trade suggest the overall protectionism has little effect on growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protectionism and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;Protectionism and World Politics.&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 39, no. 2 (1985): 233-259.
In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade &amp;lsquo;inefficiencies&amp;rsquo; as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a &amp;lsquo;secondary structure&amp;rsquo; which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.org/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.org/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade.&amp;rdquo; Austrailian Outlook 38, no. 2 (1984): 106-110.
Strange identifies three ‘shaky assumptions’ underlying the call to revive the GATT negotiations, that protectionism was the main cause of the 1930s depression, that the GATT was a necessary condition of post-war recovery, and free trade was ever a widely followed ‘norm’. However, though the alternatives are presented as a hegemonic system run by the US or a multilateral system managed through the GATT, Strange argues that the reality is a cob-web of bi-lateral agreements which accords with many people’s desire to have their own state manage their affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
