<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trade on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/trade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trade on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/trade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Protectionsim and World Politics</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/protectionism_and_world_politics/</guid>
      <description>In Protectionism and World Politics International Organization39, no.2(Spring).233-259.1985.
In discussing the question of protectionism Strange contends that her structural understanding of the international political economy - with four structures; security, production, finance, knowledge - shows that concerns about trade ‘inefficiencies’ as a disruptive element within the international system miss the real problem. She argues that trade is only a ‘secondary structure’ which is influenced and shaped by the primary structures. The disruption in the international system and trade relations is in fact a symptom of disruptions within the primary structures, and especially the financial structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/gatt_and_the_politics_of_north-south_trade/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;GATT and the Politics of North-South Trade,&amp;rdquo; Austrailian Outlook 38, no. 2 (1984): 106-110.
Strange identifies three ‘shaky assumptions’ underlying the call to revive the GATT negotiations, that protectionism was the main cause of the 1930s depression, that the GATT was a necessary condition of post-war recovery, and free trade was ever a widely followed ‘norm’. However, though the alternatives are presented as a hegemonic system run by the US or a multilateral system managed through the GATT, Strange argues that the reality is a cob-web of bi-lateral agreements which accords with many people’s desire to have their own state manage their affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity_or_how_does_theory_stand_up_to_protectionism_1970s_style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity_or_how_does_theory_stand_up_to_protectionism_1970s_style/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Mamagement of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 1970s style?&amp;rdquo; International Organisation 36, no. 2 (1979): 303-335.
In this article, which is a clear precursor to (Strange and Tooze 1981), Strange discusses the management of surplus capacity in three sectors of the international economy - steel, textiles and shipbuilding, and the recourse to protectionism. She then goes on to discuss the problems this implies for mainstream theories of international economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. &amp;ldquo;The Management of Surplus Productive Capacity,&amp;rdquo; In Economic Issues of the Eighties edited by Nake M. Kamrany and Richard H. Day, 226-246. Baltimore, Johns Hopkins University Press, 1979.
This chapter is a lightly edited version of &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity: Or how does theory stand up to protectionism 1970s style?&amp;rsquo; (1979).
Keywords: Production, Structural Power, Power, Theory, Trade
Text Access (External Link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Runs World Shipping?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/who_runs_world_shipping/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan.&amp;ldquo;Who Runs World Shipping?&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 52, no. 3 (1976): 346-367.
In the first article Strange sets out an outline method for sectoral analysis in the international economy. This is prefaced by a critical engagement with the Nye and Keohane ‘transnational politics’ approach. After stressing the inseparability of politics and economics, and the crucial authority/market trade-off, she suggests three analytical questions that must be asked in any sectoral analysis; questions about the loci and distribution of power over economic processes, the who, why, and how of economic intervention, and the question of the consequences, and benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Look at Trade and Aid</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/a_new_look_at_trade_and_aid/</guid>
      <description>Susan Strange, &amp;ldquo;A New Look at Trade and Aid,&amp;rdquo; International Affairs 42 no. 1 (January, 1966): 61 - 73.
In the light of UNCTAD’s problems, declining optimism over foreign aid and the unfavourable terms of trade for developing states, Strange suggests that ‘Prebisch’s thesis’, allowing subsidised exporting by developing states, and the dropping of tariff barriers, while unpopular would be a useful way forward. She suggests an ‘import bounty’ system, to diffuse opposition, paid for through a tax on developed states domestic and exporting manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Soviet Trade Weapon</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_soviet_trade_weapon/</guid>
      <description>Strange, Susan. The Soviet Trade Weapon. London: Phoenix House, 1959.
This pamphlet appeared in Background Books series. Taking a rather optimistic (though at that time widespread view) of the Soviet Bloc’s economic situation vis-à-vis the West, Strange concludes that Soviet economic (and political) influence is reliant on economic ‘trouble-spots’ and the aversion by many developing states to the West’s recent history of colonialism. This leads her to suggest that money then spent on military aid might be better spent helping developing countries deal with agricultural surplus capacity in the global a market, a theme she would return to in &amp;lsquo;The Management of Surplus Capacity&amp;rsquo; (1979).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
