<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Relations on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/international-relations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Relations on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/tags/international-relations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Westfailure System </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_westfailure_system/</guid>
      <description>In this posthumously published essay, Strange briefly outlines the parallel histories of the territorial system of states and the economic system of markets and suggests that until the last quarter of the twentieth century each benefited the other. However, as she often argued in the 1990s, the political system is now failing in three areas: the states system is increasingly unable to manage instability in the global financial system; the sovereign system is unable to deal effectively with globalised environmental problems; and lastly the political system’s interaction with the global market is producing widening socio-economic inequality across the global system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy: Beyond Economies and International Relations</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ipe_beyond_economies_and_international_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ipe_beyond_economies_and_international_relations/</guid>
      <description>This is slightly revised version of (1995e).
Economies et Sociétés. Volume: 34 Issue: 4. Pages 3-24</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Retreat of the State. State Diffusion of Power in the World Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_retreat_of_the_state/</guid>
      <description>In what might effectively be regarded as the third part of a trilogy, together with (1988e) and (Strange and Stopford 1991), Strange examines states’ transition towards the sidelines of global political economic relations. Though in the past authority might have been state based, now she argues it is more often based on non-state abilities to bring about (or structure) outcomes. This has to some extent been obscured by the increasing intervention by states in the lives of their citizens, giving an impression of the retention of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Defective State</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_defective_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_defective_state/</guid>
      <description>Strange argues that while states remain superficially important as major actors within the global system, the underlying power relations have hollowed out their authority. This authority has in some cases flowed ‘upwards’ to international institutions, and in other cases flowed down to markets (and also more localised organisations). These movements have led to an asymmetry of structural authority in the global system. Strange also makes some comments regarding the state-centric nature of the discipline of International Relations and suggests a new research agenda based around her conception of structural power and the importance of non-state actors in the functioning of authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Political Economy, 1959-1984</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_global_political_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_global_political_economy/</guid>
      <description>After discussing some terms she would like to see the back of (‘actors’, ‘issue-areas’), reviewing years of the Global Political Economy, Strange proposes four structures that condition change. These are Security, Production, Knowledge and Finance, and though at this point this is only used as a taxonomy for looking at changes in the GPE, it represents the first time the structures of her theory appear in their final configuration. Strange also stresses that while the four structures are not hierarchical, she believes it is disruptions in the financial structure that has caused most upheavals over the period examined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of: C.F Bergsten The World Economic in the 1980s - Selected Papers (Toronto: D.C Heath, 1981)</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/review_of_cf_bergsten/</guid>
      <description>Strange criticises Bergsten’s exaggeration of US decline in hegemonic power and absolution of the USA of bearing prime responsibility for the deteriorating economic situation. Indeed much of her work in the 1980s revolved round the dual need to recognise US responsibility for global economic crises, and the problem of such a responsibility being denied by the US (both policy makers and academics).
International Journal. Volume: 38 Issue: 2. Pages 355-356</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back - But Mostly Forward</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/looking_back-but_mostly_forward/</guid>
      <description>In this survey article, Strange looks back across the first ten years of Millennium to examine the development of International Relations, although as she makes plain she prefers the term International Studies. Having seen the field expand from a focus on the foreign polices of various states, she maps the increasing interest in the international system itself. However, she then argues that what is now needed is a further development of research into the structures of this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Money: Expanding the Agenda for Research</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_worlds_money/</guid>
      <description>After a survey of current modes of thought, both academic and practitioner, Strange concludes that while much analysis can usefully illuminate the mechanisms of the global monetary system, there is little attempt ally this to a consideration how the system links up with and effects the values of and outcomes in a globalised society. She wants work on the international monetary system to go beyond a mere mechanical explanation and to move towards a more political analysis (which would also include an assessment of the impact of technology on global finance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of Surplus Capacity: Or How Does Theory Stand up to Protectionism 197s style?</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_management_of_surplus_capacity/</guid>
      <description>In this article, which is a clear precursor to (Strange and Tooze 1981), Strange discusses the management of surplus capacity in three sectors of the international economy - steel, textiles and shipbuilding, and the recourse to protectionism. She then goes on to discuss the problems this implies for mainstream theories of international economics. She argues that Liberalism, theories of development, and organisational or functionalist theories do not offer satisfactory explanations for the resurgence of tariff barriers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Transnational Relations </title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:32:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/the_study_of_transnational_relations/</guid>
      <description>Using the ‘Dollar Crisis’ as a way of examining the problems which beset academic approaches to international relations Strange suggests that: foreign policy analysis seems unable to recognise the centrality of economic problems for states; (Neo)functionalism is far too optimistic concerning the possibility of international integration; much ‘abstract theorising’, such as game theory, seems to have no connection with what is happening in the international system; and international economics has diverted attention away from international political problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
