<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor: Randall Germain on </title>
    <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-randall-germain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor: Randall Germain on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanstrange.github.io/contributors/editor-randall-germain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/ahead_of_her_time_susan_strange_and_global_governance/</guid>
      <description>Sell, Susan K. &amp;ldquo;Ahead of her Time? Susan Strange and Global Governance.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 39-50. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter argues that Strange&amp;rsquo;s work is of enduring significance because it helps us forge a practical understanding of critical global problems. Global environmental problems, global financial crises, and global inequalities are three of the small set of global problems regularly pointed to by promoters of the new global public policy degree programs established over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Power in a Global Economy</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/corporate_power_in_a_global_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/corporate_power_in_a_global_economy/</guid>
      <description>Palan, Ronen. &amp;ldquo;Corporate Power in a Global Economy.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 170-182. London: Routledge, 2016.
What is the nature of the powers of corporations in a globalized economy? Has there been a shift of power from states to corporations? From states to markets? And if yes, how and why? These are the sort of questions that were at heart of Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing the Human Condition in a Dynamic Global System</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/diagnosing_the_human_condition_in_a_dynamic_global_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/diagnosing_the_human_condition_in_a_dynamic_global_system/</guid>
      <description>Pauly, Louis W. &amp;ldquo;Diagnosing the Human Condition in a Dynamic Global System.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 183-192. London: Routledge, 2016.
Virgil&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;rerum cognoscere causas,&amp;rsquo; adorns the crest of the London School of Economics and Political Science. &amp;lsquo;To know the cause of things&amp;rsquo; expressed an abiding aspiration for Susan Strange, even if she doubted all absolute truth-claims. In the mid-1970s, after she had rejoined her alma mater as a lecturer in the International Relations Department, I attended her course on &amp;lsquo;The Politics of International Business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money, Power, Authority</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/money_power_authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/money_power_authority/</guid>
      <description>Cohen, BenjamIn J. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 129-143. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter discusses the political economy of the global transformation. The share of American gross domestic product (GDP) in relation to global GDP had declined; the control of American corporations over key international markets remained high and was even growing. Strange argued that the global articulation of power was constituted by a complicated amalgam of public and the private authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaping the World Beyond the &#39;Core&#39;: States and Markets in Brazil&#39;s Global Assent</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/shaping_the_world_beyond_the_core_states_and_markest_in_brazils_global_assent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/shaping_the_world_beyond_the_core_states_and_markest_in_brazils_global_assent/</guid>
      <description>Tussie, Diana. &amp;ldquo;Shaping the World Beyond the &amp;lsquo;Core&amp;rsquo;: States and Markets In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 73-86. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter argues that the global financial crisis of 2008 presented a unique opportunity to re-visit them and to re-evaluate Strange&amp;rsquo;s core argument about the enduring structural power of the US in global finance. It explains how this power was particularly apparent in two international developments that took place at the height of the crisis: the US international lender-of-last-resort role and the absence of a dollar crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/still_an_extraordinary_power_after_all_these_years/</guid>
      <description>Helleiner, Eric. &amp;ldquo;Still an Extraordinary Power After All These Years: The US and the Global Financial Crisis of 2008.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 111-126. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explores Strange&amp;rsquo;s analysis of the centrality of dominant knowledge and financial structures in the constitution of the contours of the global political economy and of financial capitalism. It draws upon critical political economy, focusing on the how of power and its mobilization through dominant knowledge and financial structures to establish central bank independence and financial liberalization as grundnorms of the global financial system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Bedfellows? Bankers, Business(men) and Bureaucrats in Global Financial Governance</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_bedfellows_bankers_businessmen_and_bureaucrats_in_global_financial_governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_bedfellows_bankers_businessmen_and_bureaucrats_in_global_financial_governance/</guid>
      <description>Cutler, A. Claire. &amp;ldquo;Strange Bedfellows? Bankers, Business(men) and Bureaucrats In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 144-169. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explains how to diagnose the human condition in a dynamic global system. Strange was the one who insisted that the things to be explained were not always what they seemed, and that theory, especially the grand theory, could obscure the fundamental realities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Power Over Credit; or the Enduring Strength of US Structural-Power</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_power_over_credit_or_the_enduring_strength_of_us_structural-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/strange_power_over_credit_or_the_enduring_strength_of_us_structural-power/</guid>
      <description>Schwartz, Herman Mark. &amp;ldquo;Strange Power Over Credit; or the Enduring Strength of US Structural-Power.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 87-110. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter provides some retrospective comments on what Strange says on the nexus of money and power; and second, in the light of what she had to say, to assess her vision of where the monetary system is heading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_global_political_economy_power_control_and_transformation/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall, editor. Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation. London: Routledge, 2016.
This edited volume addresses the 2007/2009 financial crisis as the occasion to engage critically with the corpus of Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s work, in order to consider what changes (if any) this crisis portends for the structural organization of the global political economy. The contributors use Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on the broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Strange and the Future of IPE</title>
      <link>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanstrange.github.io/archive/susan_strange_and_the_future_of_ipe/</guid>
      <description>Germain, Randall. &amp;ldquo;Susan Strange and the Future of IPE.&amp;rdquo; In Susan Strange and the Future of Global Political Economy: Power, Control and Transformation, edited by Randall Germain, 19-36. London: Routledge, 2016.
This chapter explains how contributors use Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s rich conceptual framework to explore the financial crisis and its aftermath, and reflect critically on broader contributions which her work has made to the discipline of international political economy (IPE). Susan Strange&amp;rsquo;s life and times spanned the most tumultuous decades of the twentieth century.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
